Vanessa: Hi.
I'm Vanessa from SpeakEnglishWithVanessa.com.
Let's talk about describing people.
Today, I'm going to help you learn 82 expressions
for describing people.
There are three different ways to describe
people.
One of them is to describe their appearance.
I have brown hair.
The second way is to describe their personality
or character.
I'm optimistic.
The third way is to describe their actions
or hobbies.
I'm a teacher.
I like cats.
Today, we're going to specifically focus on
how to describe someone's or maybe your personality
and character.
Have you ever taken a personality test?
These kind of tests try to tell you something
new about your character or maybe put you
into a category.
You are a comforter.
You are enthusiastic.
You are a pessimist.
Personally, I hate almost every personality
test.
Why do I need a test to tell me about my personality?
I already know my personality.
You probably learned a lot about me just from
that statement.
I don't need a test.
I don't need someone else to tell me about
my personality.
Having said that, sometimes personality tests
can be really helpful for expanding your vocabulary
so that you can accurately describe people.
Maybe you just got a new job and you want
to tell your husband about your boss.
You want to explain your boss' character or
maybe how your boss looks or some things that
your boss does or maybe you're on a first
date with someone and you want to tell them
the wonderful things about your personality.
You need to describe yourself.
In this lesson, I'm going to give you the
vocabulary to accurately describe other people
and also yourself.
Today, I want to ask you six questions to
learn more about your personality.
The goal is to choose some of these nouns
and adjectives and create a sentence or maybe
a couple of sentences describing yourself.
If you feel like this is too personal, you
can kind of create a list for someone else
in your life.
At the end of this lesson, I have some extra
special material.
You're going to see a conversation with five
native English speakers where we try to describe
each other.
Hopefully, this will help to also expand your
vocabulary, but you'll have to wait until
the end of this lesson.
All right.
Let's get started with the first question
on this personality test.
Personality test question number one.
Are your travel plans generally organized?
What about your home and office?
Are they pretty tidy?
Tidy means clean.
Things are orderly.
Think about this for a moment.
Organized.
Tidy.
Does this describe you?
Think about this for three seconds.
Choose yes or no.
Three, two, one.
Let's say you decided to say yes.
My travel plans are generally organized.
My home and office are pretty tidy.
Some great adjectives we can use to describe
you.
I'm organized.
I'm put together.
I have it together.
Here, we're talking about you're life.
You have your life together.
It is organized.
I'm organized.
I'm put together.
I have it together.
Or you might say I'm A Type.
A Type is compared to B Type, which we'll
talk about in just a moment.
A Type means that you are quite orderly.
There is a place for everything in your life.
You might also a qualifier to some of these
expressions.
I'm so somewhat A Type.
I'm kind of A Type.
I'm pretty A Type.
Here, we're lessening it a little bit.
You're not 100% A Type.
You're not 100% organized.
I'm somewhat organized.
Okay.
That's fine.
Most of us are kind of in the middle of a
lot of these categories, so it's good to use
these qualifiers.
I'm somewhat organized.
You might also say if you said yes to this
that your travel plans are generally organized,
you might say I'm a doer.
Doer.
Here the root word is do.
You do things.
You don't just think about them and wait for
something to happen.
You do things.
You take action.
I'm a doer.
Or you might say simply I'm clean.
Things in my life are clean.
I'm a clean person.
If you said no to this, no, my travel plans
are not orderly.
My home and office, they are a wreck.
Well, what are some adjectives we can use
to describe you?
You might be spontaneous or creative.
What if you are not A Type, you are B Type?
B Type means that you don't always have things
orderly.
Maybe you tend to be slower at doing things.
You think about things a lot.
Usually, B Type people might be a little more
of the creative, spontaneous type.
That's why you're in this list.
Then, we have some negative words that we
can use to describe these people as well.
You might be scatterbrained.
Here, we can imagine in your head things are
not orderly.
They are scattered.
Scattered means unorganized.
If you say to someone you are scatterbrained,
it is not nice.
You could say it about yourself.
That's fine.
I'm scatterbrained.
But, you don't want to say that about someone
else.
During today's lesson for these words that
are definitely rude to say to someone else,
I put a little star beside it so that you
know I should probably be careful saying this
to other people because these are always negative.
The final thing you might say if you said
no to this question is I'm not clean.
I'm messy.
My life is messy.
My house is messy.
Just things are not organized.
I'm messy.
Did you write down some words that relate
to your personality?
All right.
Let's go on to the personality test question
number two.
Question number two.
Is it easy to stay relaxed even when you have
pressure?
Do small events not change how you feel about
the rest of the day?
Maybe a small negative thing happens and how
cares.
It doesn't bother you.
You can just easily forget about it.
Think about these questions.
Is it true for you?
Yes, I can easily stay relaxed even when there's
pressure.
Yes, I can easily forget about little annoyances
during the day.
Or no, it's hard for me to feel relaxed even
when there's pressure.
Think about this for you and let's talk about
some words in three, two, one.
What if you said yes to this?
It's easy for me to feel relaxed even when
there's pressure.
Yeah.
If there's small annoying things that happen
during the day, it doesn't bother me.
What are some words we can use to describe
you?
You could say I'm easygoing.
Nothing phases me.
I'm optimistic.
I'm even-keeled.
We talked about this word in a previous lesson
where Dan and I talked about our relationship,
our marriage together.
He said that I'm even-keeled.
This is a great word.
You might say I'm confident.
I'm calm.
I'm rational.
These are all things that you might use to
describe you if you said yeah, I can easily
stay relaxed even when there's pressure.
What about if you said no to this question?
What if you said no, I don't easily feel relaxed.
I'm often not relaxed.
I'm often stressed.
What are some words we can use to describe
you?
We might say I'm sensitive.
This means that things affect you easily.
It's not always a negative thing.
Of course, it depends no the situation.
If you're applying for a high stress job,
you don't want to say I'm sensitive.
It probably means you're not a good fit for
the position, but this could be just to describe
you personally.
I'm sensitive.
Or maybe you might say I'm emotional.
Your emotions play a big part in your life.
Another way to say emotional is moody.
Moody is always a negative thing.
This means you're in a good mood.
You're in a bad mood and you're swinging between
those moods and there's no rhyme or reason.
That means there's no predictability.
One day or one moment you feel like this and
the next day or the next moment you feel like
this.
You're moody.
This is stronger than emotional.
This is much more negative than emotional,
so don't tell someone you're moody.
Especially if they are moody, it won't go
well.
Do you know what the opposite of optimistic
is?
You might be pessimistic.
Pessimistic means that the glass is half empty.
The glass is not half full.
The glass is half empty.
This is an expression that means you always
see maybe the negative side or what if this
happens.
You're always asking what if in kind of that
negative way.
Of course, it's good to balance being optimistic
and pessimistic, but these are the two extremes.
The next five words mean something very similar
and they're all negative.
I don't recommend telling someone else that
they are these things.
Of course, you can say them about yourself
if you would like.
You might say I'm uptight.
Tight, we can kind of imagine something inside
of you is maybe twisted or tight and inside
of you, you don't feel relaxed.
You're uptight or maybe you're anxious.
You can say I'm anxious and that describes
your personality, but you might just be anxious
about one thing.
I'm anxious about my exam tomorrow.
Okay.
Maybe in general, you're not an anxious person,
but you're anxious about that specific activity.
That's fine.
That's not really describing your personality.
Every day I'm often anxious.
No, it's just one specific thing or you might
be high strung.
High strung has that same feeling of uptight,
anxious, high strung.
Or you might be a worrier.
A worrier.
She is a worrier.
That means that she worries a lot.
This defines her personality.
She's a worrier.
Or we might say neurotic.
He's neurotic.
She's neurotic.
I'm neurotic.
This is quite strong.
You are uptight and a lot of things bother
you.
Let's go on to personality test question number
three.
There's actually three questions in one here.
They are is it difficult to introduce yourself
to new people?
Do you feel tired after you spend time with
a group of people?
Is a good book or a good movie more interesting
than a social event?
Think about those questions for a moment.
Is it difficult to introduce yourself to new
people?
How do you feel when you get together with
a group of people?
Do you feel tired?
Think about that for a moment.
If the answer is yes or no.
Three, two, one.
Let's imagine that you said yeah, it's difficult
to introduce myself to people.
I think that when I get together with a group
of people, I feel so tired.
I would rather read a good book or watch a
movie than go to a social event.
If you said yes to this, let's talk about
some adjectives that can describe you.
You could say I'm reserved.
I'm shy.
I'm timid.
I'm introverted.
Or just simply I prefer small groups.
I know some people are like this.
They don't like big groups.
They would rather get together with just one
other person or maybe two or three other people,
not a group of 20 people.
I prefer small groups.
I'm introverted.
I'm reserved.
I'm shy.
I'm timid.
These are all great words.
What about if you said no, I feel energetic
when I get together with a group of people.
I would rather go to a social outing.
It's no problem to introduce myself to new
people.
What are some words we can use to describe
you?
You could say I'm outgoing.
I'm the life of the party.
Now for this expression, it's probably better
that someone else says this about you just
because it's maybe not so humble if you say
I'm the life of the party.
It means that everybody loves me.
People love talking with me.
It's probably better if your friend said "Yeah,
Vanessa, she's the life of the party," instead
of me saying it about myself.
But, this might be an expression you can use
to talk about someone like this.
Or you might be the opposite of introverted,
extroverted.
You are at ease in social situations.
You take initiative.
You are social.
This word initiative is a beautiful word.
We can imagine that when there are are two
people maybe in a gathering and they both
are kind of looking at each other, but they
don't really want to start a conversation,
the person who starts the conversation, that
person takes initiative.
They took that opportunity.
If you have no problem introducing yourself
to other people or maybe asking questions
at a store, you take initiative.
Let's go on to question number four of this
personality test.
Do you often get lost in thought and kind
of forget your surroundings?
Do you often think about the meaning of life?
Do you get lost in thought?
Things are going on in your head and you're
thinking about those things not the things
about you.
Do you often think about the meaning of life?
What is life?
Think about this question.
Is it true for you?
Is it not true for you?
Three, two, one.
Let's imagine that you said yeah, I do often
kind of get lost in thought.
Yeah, I do think about the meaning of life
often.
What are some words we use to describe you?
You might say I'm deep.
Now, this is an expression kind of like I'm
the life of the party that it's not so humble.
If someone is deep, this is a compliment.
It means that they have a lot of wisdom.
It's probably better for you to say it about
someone else.
I really like talking to my cousin.
He's so deep.
He has such interesting thoughts.
Instead of saying it about yourself.
You may also say I care about finding truth.
This another way deep.
I care about finding truth.
Or you might be the kind of person who is
critical.
I'm critical of things.
If someone tells me something, I often question
it.
Is it true?
Is that real?
On the negative side, you might say cynical.
Cynical is always a negative word and that
just means that yes that person asks questions,
but they always doubt.
They're not just asking questions, but they're
always doubting.
Is that true?
There's no way that that's true.
They're cynical.
They're always doubting.
If you often get lost in thought, you might
say I'm a dreamer.
I often like to daydream.
I'm lost in my own world.
I live in my head.
They're not things that you want to say in
a job interview, but they're not necessarily
bad, so you can say them to your friends or
say them about yourself.
If you want to say this in a negative way,
you could say I'm a million miles away or
she's a million miles away.
She's not paying attention.
She is a million miles away.
That's pretty negative.
Then if you want to be really negative, you
could say I'm an airhead.
We can imagine your head is filled with nothing
but air.
I'm often lost in thought and I forget the
things around me.
I am an airhead.
This is a similar category as someone who
often thinks about things, but it's quite
different from being deep.
If you're deep, your head is filled with a
lot of thoughts.
But then on the negative side, you might say
airhead for having no thoughts.
Your often lost in your own world.
You're often in your head, but you're not
thinking about anything.
Just an airhead.
What if you said no, I'm not often lost in
thought.
I don't really think about the meaning of
life that often.
Life is life.
No, why would I care what the meaning of life
is?
What would you say on the other side?
You could say I'm alert.
You don't often get lost in your thoughts
because you're looking around.
You are alert to the things going on around
you.
You notice little details.
Maybe people who are lost in thought, they're
not thinking about the physical details around
them.
They don't realize there's a cup over there,
my friend just walked by.
If you are alert, you're noticing those things.
You might also I'm detail-oriented.
You notice lots of little details or you might
say I'm astute.
These are great things for a job interview.
I'm detail-oriented.
I'm alert and astute.
This means that you will not forget little
things because you are organized.
You are able to keep track of physical details.
Similar to alert, you might say aware.
I'm aware of my surroundings.
You're not lost in your head.
You are aware.
Or you might be a realist.
A realist.
This is quite the opposite of somebody who's
thinking about the meaning of life.
Well, if I think about the meaning of life,
I'm never going to really find out, so why
would I waste my time?
A realist would say that.
If you think, you might be a realist or you
might just be practical.
Practical and a realist are both quite similar.
You are practical.
You're not going to waste your time if you
know that something won't be profitable or
won't be helpful.
I don't think it's really helpful to contemplate
the meaning of life.
I'm just practical.
This might be something you can use to describe
you.
Let's go on to the next question.
Personality test question number five.
When you want something, do you often not
change your mind?
Think about this.
Is that true for you?
You don't change your mind or I'll say I change
my mind.
Well, it's not so serious for me.
Think about this.
Three, two, one.
Let's imagine that you said yes, it is true
for me.
When I want something, I don't often change
my mind.
What are some words we can use to describe
you?
We could say you are diligent.
You're motivated.
I want to study English.
I'm going to become fluid in English.
I'm going to feel more confident in English
and I will be diligent.
I will study every day.
I'm motivated.
You want something and you are not going to
be distracted.
These are positive expressions.
They're great for job interviews.
They're great general personality traits.
There are some negative ways to describe this
as well though.
You might be stubborn.
We have a lovely idiom, stubborn as a mule.
Or we might say you are headstrong.
Headstrong, this means stubborn.
When you want something, you often refuse
to think about other options.
I want this.
I'm not going to think about other things.
I'm stubborn.
Or you might be adamant.
Adamant, this means that you stick with your
opinion.
Let's imagine that you're a teenager and your
mom says "I heard that you were drinking beer
with some friends behind the school."
You say "No, Mom, I wasn't doing that.
I don't know who you were talking with, but
it wasn't me behind the school doing that."
She says "Well, I heard from this person that
you were doing it."
You stick with your opinion.
"No, it wasn't me.
It wasn't me.
There's no way that was me."
You are adamant that that person was not you.
You are adamant about something.
This means that you refuse to change your
story about something.
You are adamant.
You also might be opinionated.
You have opinions and you're not really afraid
to share them.
This isn't necessarily a negative thing to
be opinionated.
Of course if you are opinionated, if you have
strong opinions, especially if these are opinions
that are not shared with a lot of other people,
it's great to be careful about how you present
them, about how you share them with other
people so that they don't think that you are
pushy.
Pushy is always a negative thing.
If you are opinionated, you need to talk about
it in a specific way so that you don't become
pushy, pushing your opinions on people.
You might be persistent.
This is similar to adamant, but it's in a
negative way.
You are persistent.
"I wasn't drinking behind the school.
That wasn't me."
You are persistently keeping with the same
opinion.
Persistent.
Or maybe you have a three-year-old and that
three-year-old is asking for candy.
"I want candy.
Mom, I want candy.
I want candy."
That three-year-old is persistent.
They are wanting it and they're telling you
again and again and again.
You might hear the word bossy.
I'm bossy.
She's so bossy.
He's bossy.
This is similar to persistent.
Adamant, you're telling someone "You should
do this.
You should do this.
You do this.
You do this."
Like a boss, but usually if you're a good
boss, you don't act like that.
You're much kinder.
But, we use the term bossy for people who
have an opinion and they're not really to
change it in this negative way.
What if you said the opposite thing to this
question?
What if you said actually sometimes I do change
my mind.
I don't always stick with exactly what I say
I want every single time.
What are some other words we can use?
You could say I'm flexible.
I'm compliant.
I'm reasonable.
I'm open minded.
I'm agreeable.
These are all positive things, but what if
we take this to an extreme?
You might say I'm submissive.
This means that you never stand up for yourself.
To stand up for yourself means that you have
something you want and you never tell other
people.
You are submissive, maybe too submissive.
Or we can use a great expression I often get
walked on.
Get walked on.
If you have an opinion and you always change
it depending on what other people want, we
can imagine that you are like a doormat.
This is the thing that you walk on to enter
a house.
This is you.
People are always walking on you.
I often get walked on.
Your desires, your needs often get forgotten
because you don't stand up for yourself.
I often get walked on.
You could say that about someone else.
Yeah, he often gets walked on because he doesn't
feel comfortable standing up for what he wants.
He doesn't feel comfortable pushing what he
wants, so he just gets walked on.
Let's go to the next question.
Question number six.
This is our final personality test question.
When people come over to your house, when
guest come to your house, do they feel comfortable?
Do you go above and beyond what is necessary
to take care of them?
This is a great expression.
Go above and beyond.
Maybe it's necessary to give them a glass
of water.
When a guest comes to your house, you say
"Sit on the couch.
Here's a glass of water."
But maybe you go above and beyond.
You do more than that so that your guests
feel comfortable.
Is that true for you?
Do your guests feel comfortable?
Do you do more than is necessary?
Think about that for a moment.
Is it true or not true for you?
Three, two, one.
Let's say that this is true for you, that
you make your guests feel comfortable and
you do more than is necessary.
Let's talk about a lot of adjectives that
we could use to describe you.
You are hospitable, nice, friendly.
But here is a big warning.
If you come from France, Italy, Spain, Brazil,
Portugal, these romantic language countries
do not ... Warning, warning, warning.
Do not say sympathetic.
You do not say he is sympathetic.
She is sympathetic.
This does not mean nice in English.
This a false friend and I hear a lot of people
say this.
Instead, in English, we do have the word sympathetic.
This means that maybe your brother lost his
job and when you go over to his house, you
bring him some flowers and you bring him a
meal and you sit down and talk with him.
You talk about that difficult hard time in
his life because you are sympathetic to his
difficulty.
We usually have a difficult situation happening
and you didn't personally experience that
difficult thing, but you feel his difficulty.
You feel his pain.
You are sympathetic.
Here, we're using it in a completely difference
sense than friendly.
Friendly just means you're nice.
But if someone has a difficult situation,
you are sympathetic to their problem.
You understand I think my brother is really
sad right now.
He's probably worried about the future.
You are understanding his difficult times.
I hope I explained this word sympathetic so
that you do not use it and say "Vanessa, you're
so sympathetic."
No, no, no, no, no, don't use that.
What are some other words we can use?
You could say I'm compassionate.
I'm considerate.
I'm generous.
This means you give maybe your time or your
money to other people.
You could say I'm warm.
I'm warmhearted.
This means that people feel this warm feeling
when they're with you.
They feel like you're such a friendly person.
You could say I'm helpful.
I'm down to earth.
Down to earth is an expression that we used
to mean you are relatable.
People feel like your life is not so different
from theirs.
You often hear this word described with celebrities.
Celebrities, movie stars, they have lives
that are much different than our own, so they
seem kind of untouchable, so different, but
maybe there is one celebrity who relates to
the problems of normal people.
Someone might say yeah, she's really down
to earth.
She's down to earth.
Her feet are on the earth.
Or you might say she's sincere.
She's genuine.
She's really herself.
She's not faking it.
She's dependable or I'm dependable.
Your friends know that they can depend on
you.
What if you said no to this?
I imagine that you probably didn't say no
to this about yourself, but you probably know
somebody like this.
Let's talk about the opposite.
Someone who is maybe not so generous, not
so considerate or so friendly.
Let's talk about the opposite.
Maybe you know someone who is unpleasant.
This is a little bit of a nicer way to say
they're so annoying.
They're such a terrible person.
You could just say yeah, he's kind of unpleasant.
I don't really like working with him.
Unpleasant.
Or someone might because selfish.
They're not generous.
They don't like to go above and beyond.
They're kind of selfish.
Or maybe you know someone who is self centered.
The world revolves around their life.
They are self centered.
Their self is the center of the universe.
They're self centered.
How did you do?
How did you answer all of these six personality
test questions?
I hope you wrote down some adjectives that
you can use to describe yourself.
Write that sentence down in the comments.
But before we go, I'd like to share some extra
material with today.
You're going to see five native speakers.
They are three friends, plus my husband, plus
me.
We are attempting to describe each other.
I sat down with each of my friends individually
and asked "How would you describe this person?
How would you describe that person?"
I didn't tell them specifically to describe
their personality or their character, but
you'll see that a lot of these people, they
did describe their physical appearance a little
bit.
But, most of these descriptions had to do
with their personality or character.
You're going to hear some of the words that
we just talked about and maybe you'll hear
some new words as well.
Let's start with my friend Liz.
You're going to meet Liz, Heather, Lauren,
and Dan.
They're going to be describing each other.
Let's see what everyone has to say about Liz.
How do they describe Liz?
Let's watch.
Liz: Hi.
I'm Liz.
Heather: Gosh, Liz is witty and sarcastic
to a fault.
Vanessa: I'd say so.
Heather: She's super inquisitive and very
literate.
I’d say that’s very good description of
her.
Vanessa: For sure.
That's something that I first recognized about
Liz is she's really inquisitive.
She asks great questions.
Heather: She's curious about life.
Yeah.
I'd say she's adventurous for some things,
like travel or things like that.
Not so much food.
She's very loyal.
Very loyal friend.
Lauren: Liz is very sarcastic and smart, quick
witted.
She's funny and she has nice pretty long brown
hair.
Vanessa: That's true.
Dan: I would describe Liz as very curious.
Out of many people I know, not many people
will ask you questions a lot.
When Liz asks you a question, she'll ask more
and more questions, which I'm not hating on.
I think it's great.
She's also very assertive.
Whenever she has an opinion, she usually makes
it very clear.
It's not hidden in any way.
She's also very friendly though, so the assertiveness
doesn't get in the way of her friendliness.
Her friendliness shines through.
Vanessa: You just heard some amazing adjectives
to describe the wonderful person of Liz.
Let's go on to the second person.
You're going to meet Heather and let's see
how everyone describes Heather.
Heather: Hi.
I'm Heather.
Liz: Heather is a short little person and
she has brown hair and amazing freckles and
she's very creative.
She's an introvert.
She's a good painter.
She's very smart.
She's well traveled.
Vanessa: Those are all true things.
Lauren: Heather is short like me and she's
kind of got some ... She's dry humored, so
very subtle, also very smart, and well traveled.
She's live in lots of different places.
Dan: Heather.
Heather is very reserved.
Yet when you get to know her, she's very fun
loving.
She's also very curious.
She's kind of geeky.
She likes Harry Potter and Star Wars and stuff
like that.
Yeah, she's very fun and if you get together
with her at a party, you're going to have
a good time.
Vanessa: I hope you enjoyed those adjectives
to describe Heather.
Let's go on to Lauren.
How does everyone describe Lauren?
Lauren: Hi.
I'm Lauren.
Liz: Lauren is also a short little person.
She's got sort of blondish brown hair, sort
of a darker shade of blond.
She has glasses.
She to me is very businesslike and she likes
to tell stories with a lot of detail, which
are always interesting.
Heather: Lauren is short, with short hair,
glasses, and I think she's a geek.
Vanessa: Could you explain what you mean by
geek?
Is that her interests?
Heather: Yes.
A little bit about her interests.
She's, like Liz, curious about different knowledge
and stuff.
She loves Star Wars, Harry Potter.
Vanessa: Exactly.
That kind of stuff.
Heather: Harry Potter.
Movies.
She's definitely a movie buff.
She can remember almost everything.
All these weird random details.
Vanessa: Her mind is like steel trap.
Heather: Yes.
Vanessa: She knows everything.
Heather: Yeah.
I think she's also a very loyal friend and
very caring.
Vanessa: Yeah.
I've been friends with her for 10 years and
I feel like she is that kind of person.
Heather: She makes an effort.
Vanessa: Yeah.
Heather: She makes an effort in her relationships,
I think.
Vanessa: Yeah.
That's a great quality.
Heather: Yeah.
Very much.
Dan: Lauren.
Lauren.
Lauren is very loyal, I would say.
When she's your friend, she's your friend
for life.
She'll remember you and she's very detail-oriented.
She'll remember all the details of your relationship.
I don't mean this in a bad way.
I just mean there's always somebody in your
life who gives all those details about your
life.
She also knows a lot about from my perspective,
a lot about pop culture.
She's always filing me in on the details and
maybe I understand something that she also
understands and we can have a funny conversation
about that.
Usually, Vanessa doesn't understand.
Vanessa: Yeah.
I don't much about pop culture, so Lauren
is my window into this world.
She allows me to learn that stuff.
I hope you learn some great words with those
explanations.
Let's go on to my husband, Dan, and see what
everyone else has to say about Dan.
Dan: Hi.
I'm Dan.
Liz: Dan.
Dan is so fun.
Dan is this tall, skinny ginger.
He's got very great amazing red hair.
He always has a lot of energy.
I think he's always like "I'm Dan."
Vanessa: He does have a lot of energy.
Liz: He, I feel like, has a lot of strong
opinions about things, which I really like.
He's married to you and has a baby.
Vanessa: That is true.
Those are all true facts.
Liz: I think he's very relaxed in some ways,
but also cares about details in other ways.
Which is kind of hard to describe, but it's
true.
Vanessa: That is true.
Heather: Dan is a tall, skinny redhead.
Vanessa: That is the first thing Liz said,
too.
Heather: I think he is very creative.
I would probably describe him as adventurous,
not afraid to take risks, inquisitive, opinionated.
I think he has opinions and he's set in his
way, but I think he's also open for discussion.
Vanessa: Okay.
Heather: Yeah.
Lauren: Dan.
Oh, Dan.
Vanessa: Other people said that too.
Dan.
Oh, Dan.
Lauren: Dan is thin and he has red hair, very
red hair.
He can be kind of loud and enthusiastic.
That's a good word for Dan.
Vanessa: Enthusiastic.
Lauren: He's very intelligent too and adventurous.
He's into lots of different things and learning.
He likes to learn.
Vanessa: Those were some great adjectives
to describe Dan.
Oops, I forgot to say that my friends are
also going to describe me.
Here we go.
Liz: You.
You're just so delightful.
That was my first word for you.
Not just because you're in the room, but because
you are just delightful.
Vanessa: That's so nice.
Liz: You have effervescent personality.
I feel like you're very uplifting for other
people.
You bring a lot of joy to people.
I feel like you always seem like you have
it together.
That's definitely my most overarching impression
of you is you have it together.
You're also a very good host.
You're excellent with hospitality.
Vanessa: Thank you.
Liz: Obviously we share a love of reading,
so I know that you're very well read.
I like that you get very interested in specific
topics.
Vanessa: Whenever the topic ...
Liz: Whenever we read a book, she's like,
I went and did research and I found this out
and this and this.
It was just very interesting.
Vanessa: I think that's quite true that when
I'm interested in something, I'm really interested.
Liz: You go all the way.
Vanessa: Just go into it.
Yeah.
Well, thank you for your kind words.
Liz: Yes.
Heather: Vanessa.
Vanessa: Tell me what you think.
Heather: I think you're probably one of the
kindest people I've ever met.
I think you're just very genuinely nice.
Vanessa: Thanks.
That's really sweet.
Heather: I could be wrong.
Vanessa: You know when you're not around,
Heather, I'm evil.
Heather: I think you're also very inquisitive
and very literate.
Vanessa: I like to read.
Heather: I think you are very curious about
the world and people like this.
Heather: I think where you and Dan fit well
together he seems super creative, comes up
with ideas, but you're very good at implementing
ideas.
I think you're good at keeping people on task.
Vanessa: Okay.
Focusing on the point.
Heather: Yes.
Vanessa: Yeah.
Heather: I think you need that.
You run your own business, so I think that
is a good quality.
Vanessa: Yeah.
Got to be able to focus.
Heather: Yes.
Exactly.
Vanessa: That's great.
Heather: I think you are very good at having
fun, but also getting the work done.
Vanessa: Being serious when I need to be serious.
Heather: Exactly.
Lauren: Vanessa is kind and warm and likes
to learn as well, well traveled also, and
you have pretty brown hair too.
Vanessa: Thank you.
Dan: Vanessa.
Vanessa: No pressure.
I'm your wife.
I'm sitting right here.
Dan: Number on adjective is wonderful.
Vanessa: Thank you.
Dan: Vanessa is probably the nicest person
on Earth.
By nicest, I mean almost just like sincere.
She's always very sincere, very caring, very
curious, always sincerely interested in most
people's topics, like I'll hear even a boring
person say something and she'll be like "Oh
well, very interesting."
I don't think she's making it up either.
I think she's seriously very interested.
Vanessa: Yeah.
Life is interesting.
Everyone has something interesting if you
listen close enough.
Dan: Yes.
She's also very fun, very fun loving.
You can do a lot with her.
Obviously, I like Vanessa a lot because I
decided to marry her.
Vanessa: I'm glad you like me a lot.
Dan: We get along very well and I like yeah
about 99% of Vanessa.
Vanessa: Thank you.
I won't ask about the 1% yet.
I hope you've enjoyed today's long, intense,
English vocabulary lesson.
Now, I have a challenge for you.
In the comments below this video, I want you
to try to write a sentence or two or three
describing yourself or maybe describing someone
else in your life.
Try to fill it with these wonderful adjectives,
some of these are nouns as well, to describe
yourself.
It's a great way to remember them.
Try to ingrain them in your memory.
Thanks so much for learning English with me
and I'll see you again next Friday for a new
lesson here on my YouTube channel.
Bye.
The next step is to download my free e-book
Five Steps to Becoming a Confident English
Speaker.
You'll learn what you need to do to speak
confidently and fluently.
Don't forget to subscribe to my YouTube channel
for more free lessons.
Thanks so much.
Bye.