Dan: Hello.
Vanessa: Hello, hello.
Welcome to today's live English lesson here
on the wonderful Speak English with Vanessa
YouTube channel page.
Thank you for joining me.
I'm Vanessa and this is my husband, Dan.
Dan: I'm Dan.
You might know me well.
Vanessa: Yes.
Dan is going to help today to explain three
valuable English expressions.
One of them is a phrasal verb.
One of them is an idiom and what's the last
one?
Dan: We got slang as well.
We like slang around here.
Vanessa: Yes, so we're hopefully help you
to expand your vocabulary and also just see
some specific examples when you can use this
in your daily conversations or in your writing
or in your job or in your travels, anytime
that you use English.
If you're joining us live, thanks so much.
Let us know where you're from and let us know
in the chat box.
We're going to be asking a lot of questions
today so make sure that you interact and participate.
You can write out the questions.
You can write out your answers even if you're
not watching live, if you're watching the
replay, you can do the same thing.
Write out the questions.
Write out your own answers.
Try to use these because that's the best way
to remember what you're learning.
Dan: Yes, and a happy, early, Merry Christmas,
if anybody has noticed our Christmas tree
back here.
Vanessa: Yes.
Dan: I love Christmas.
It's my favorite time of year.
Vanessa: Yeah so we decided to open the door
so that you could get a little sneak preview
of our Christmas tree.
That was Dan's idea.
Thanks.
Dan: Yes.
You need the sneak preview.
Vanessa: Yes.
Yes.
Thank you, everyone who's joining us from
Mexico, India, Brazil.
Dan: Japan.
Vanessa: Yemen, Columbia.
Dan: Egypt.
Vanessa: Hungary.
Thank you so much for joining us.
Peru, Turkey, Morocco.
Wow.
Dan: Kurdistan, never been there.
Vanessa: From everywhere.
Everywhere around the world.
Thanks so much.
I'd like to start by asking you the first
question.
Dan: Okay.
Vanessa: My first question is, what has to
do with something that happened this week.
We had a friend who invited us to an escape
room for her birthday but I had never heard
of that so could you explain it to me?
What's in an escape room, because if my friend's
inviting me there for her birthday, I want
to know what I'm going to do.
Dan: Yeah.
An escape room, I don't know if they do this
in other countries yet, but it's started to
get kind of popular in America so you actually
pay to get locked up in a room.
Vanessa: Yes.
Dan: It's filled with puzzles so you have
to, one might say figure out some puzzles.
I've done one before and I remember they started
me off in the room in handcuffs with all the
lights off.
Vanessa: You were with other people or were
you alone?
Dan: I was with other people.
Vanessa: Okay.
Dan: It'd be a little scary alone I think.
Vanessa: Yeah, I guess you could do it alone
but it's fun as maybe a group activity.
That's why we got invited to a friend's house.
Dan: Right, and they call it an escape room
because you're supposed to escape the room,
that's the point of the game so I don't know.
Do they have that in your countries?
Vanessa: Yeah, are escape rooms becoming popular
in your country?
The kind of principle of this type of activity
is that you have to figure out how to get
out of the room.
What is this lovely phrasal verb here?
Figure out.
Dan: Figure out, that means to learn how to
do something.
Vanessa: Yes.
Dan: It usually means it's a little difficult.
You're working on something.
Maybe you have a really hard math problem.
This happened to me all the time when I was
in school.
Math was not my strong suit so I had to figure
out how to solve the problem.
Vanessa: Yes, you had to figure out so this
kind of implies a process.
It's difficult, maybe you have to look from
one resource to the next resource and ask
someone.
You have to do some problem solving, kind
of like you can imagine if Dan's in a dark
room with his friends, handcuffed, and they
have to figure out how to get out of the room,
that involves a process.
You have to problem solve and figure out other
things so I want to know for you, my question
for you is when was a time you had to figure
out how to solve a problem.
Dan: You can also say, figure it out.
Vanessa: Figure it out, so when would we use
figure it out?
Dan: Yeah.
If you're already in the process of working
on something, you might just say to yourself,
oh, man, I really need to figure it out.
Vanessa: Yeah, so the other day.
Dan: I need to figure this out.
Vanessa: I was in the office, in this room
and I think I made some kind of sound like,
some kind of frustrated sound and you said
from the other room.
Hey, Vanessa, are you okay?
I said, I was fine.
I'll figure it out.
I didn't tell him any specifics.
I didn't say I'm working on this problem on
the website and technical things are sometimes
frustrating to me.
I didn't give him any details.
I just said, oh, I'll figure it out.
Dan: She knew I wouldn't be able to figure
it out so.
Vanessa: I didn't want to explain those details.
Dan: She figured it out on her own.
Vanessa: Yes, so do you think that this is
an expression and a phrasal verb that you
could use in a workplace situation?
Dan: Yeah.
Vanessa: If you have some kind of problem?
Dan: Absolutely.
Yeah.
Vanessa: It's useful for those kind of professional
situations, certainly so maybe if you have
a problem on some kind of report that you're
working on and you want to ask a coworker
about it.
Dan: Can you help me figure this out?
Vanessa: Figure this out.
Dan: That would be polite and it's acceptable.
It's not slang.
Vanessa: Yeah, it's not slang.
It can be polite and you can split this phrasal
verb like Dan just did, figure it out or figure
this out or figure this problem out, figure
this thing out so you can split it or you
can keep it together, no problem.
We've got two different choices.
A lot of you are writing wonderful expressions
here.
I see, Zahira says, I will figure out how
to get confident in English.
Dan: That's a good one.
Vanessa: That is a great one.
Dan: Yeah.
Vanessa: Here, we can kind of imagine that
you're solving the problem.
You're working through this issue and you're
going to figure it out.
I will figure it out.
I know I'll do it.
Dan: I couldn't figure out what my boss was
talking about as I don't speak Mongolian.
That's a good one too.
I couldn't figure it out, in the negative.
Vanessa: Yes, so when you're using this in
the negative version, just like we saw here
in the sample sentence from those of you who
are here live with us, saying I couldn't figure
out what my boss was saying or maybe if you
had an English teacher who just talked way
too fast and talked about too many complex
things, then maybe you would say, oh, I can't
figure out what Vanessa is saying.
She's just talking too fast.
Dan: We have a question.
Is find out, similar?
Vanessa: Oh, this is a great question.
Dan: Find out.
Vanessa: I want to give you a little tip,
maybe a year ago, over a year ago or maybe
less than a year ago, I'm not sure.
I made a video comparing figure out and find
out.
After this has finished, I'll link this video
up here and then also in the description but
I want you to get some more details about
that.
If I said, I'm going to find out who is at
the door.
Dan: That means you're going to discover,
you're going to see, find out.
You don't know right now and then you're going
to find out, you're going to discover.
Vanessa: It kind of doesn't imply that process.
You're searching a difficult thing.
Instead, it's an instant thing like, a-ha.
I opened the door, and I can see who's there.
I'm going to find out who's there.
Dan: Yeah, maybe if you said, I'm going to
figure out who's at the door, maybe you hear
a knock on the door and you look through the
hole and you don't see anybody or maybe somebody
is wearing a mask and then they give you a
puzzle.
Vanessa: Yes, so it is kind of implies a process.
Dan: It needs to be more involved.
Vanessa: Yes, so if you would like some more
details about figure out versus find out,
feel free to check out that video but in general,
figure out means there's some process, you're
searching, you're figuring out how to do something.
We often add how at the end, figure out how
to escape from the room, figure out how to
become a confident English speaker and find
out is just the solution.
Find out what is happening.
Find out who is at the door.
Dan: I want to find out what presents are
under my Christmas tree.
Vanessa: Are there any presents under our
Christmas tree?
Dan: There are no presents.
Vanessa: maybe someday there will be presents
under the Christmas tree.
Dan: Christmas is ruined.
Vanessa: Oh, well when you have a toddler.
Dan: It's still early.
Vanessa: You can't put Christmas presents
under the tree early.
It's a recipe for getting them opened.
Dan: Yes.
Vanessa: All right.
I'd like to go to the second expression, which
is an idiom.
This past week, our car was doing some kind
of funny things, making some funny sounds
and I noticed that you didn't fix the car
yourself.
Dan: No.
Vanessa: You took it to the mechanic.
Why did you take the car to the mechanic?
Dan: Well, I'm not a mechanic.
I'm not very handy.
Handy means you can fix a lot of things.
I'm kind of handy but not with cars so I am
in over my head when it comes to fixing cars.
I would be in over my head if I tried to fix
my car.
In over my head.
Vanessa: A lovely idiom.
We need four words here.
Dan: In what?
Vanessa: Well, we can kind of imagine the
feeling of being overwhelmed.
You're completely surrounded or covered in
the problem so here we can imagine Dan opening
the car, trying to fix the problem.
He's trying to figure out what's making that
strange sound.
He's trying to look around.
Dan: I'm ripping pieces out of the car.
Vanessa: Oh, and he thinks, oh, it's going
to be a disaster.
I should just go to the mechanic because I
am in over my head.
It's a problem that's too big.
Dan: You can think of swimming in the ocean.
If you're drowning, the waters over your head.
You're in trouble.
Vanessa: Yes.
Dan: You're you're struggling.
Vanessa: I think that's a great image.
Dan: I think this is where this comes from.
Vanessa: Yeah, when I think of this expression,
I do think of water that you're in the swimming
pool or in the ocean and the water's getting
higher and higher and when the water is over
your head, bad news.
Dan: Yeah, I mean really, that probably means
you're going to die.
Vanessa: Yeah.
Dan: This is a little bit of an expression
that's not literal, obvious.
That's why it's idiom right?
You're just in trouble.
You're in big trouble.
Vanessa: Yes.
In over your head.
I want to know for you, when was a situation
that was just too much for you and you felt
like you were in over your head.
What was a time?
Maybe you decided to volunteer at your job
to be the person who helps the American director
who's coming to your office and you said,
sure, I'll talk to the American director.
I'll take him out to dinner, I'll guide him
around the office.
I can speak English.
This is fine, and then you meet him and you
realize he has a strong Southern accent.
Dan: Howdy, folks.
Vanessa: Maybe at the end of that day, you
feel like I was in over my head.
This situation was too much for me.
I can understand English, but I didn't realize
that his accent would be so strong.
I was in over my head.
Dan: Yeah, I have a personal example.
Vanessa: Yes.
What was your personal example?
Dan: We used to teach English in South Korea,
you probably know this.
I had never taught children before so the
first time I had to teach a class of children,
I was in over my head.
In over my head because the children, they
didn't necessarily respect me yet.
I'm different looking in South Korea, my red
hair and my freckles.
They thought it was weird.
They didn't take me seriously, they started
yelling and screaming.
I was in over my head because I didn't know
what to do about it so.
Vanessa: Yes, and over time, you learned more
and more what to do but that's a perfect situation
and perfect expression to use especially for
your first day at school, your first day as
a teacher, your first day at your job, maybe
your first day living in the U.S. or if you
move to Australia.
Dan: This happens a lot.
Vanessa: I was in over my head that first
day, but eventually it got better so I want
to know for you, when was a situation when
you were in over your head?
Dan: Tell us about it.
Vanessa: Yes, yes.
Let us know in the comments.
Make sure that you use this expression as
much as you can.
I'd like to read a sentence that one of you
wrote, I was in over my head.
I was stressed.
I couldn't do it.
Oh, stress is usually associated with being
in over your head.
You're stressed.
You're overwhelmed.
Yes, it's just too much.
I'm in over my head.
Khaled says, I'm in over my head.
The American director speaks too fast.
Dan: That's a good example.
Vanessa: I hope that that didn't happen to
you but if this happened, you're going to
use a beautiful idiom to describe it, oh,
I'm in over my head.
Dan: Are you in over your head when you watch
Vanessa's videos?
I hope not.
Vanessa: Oh, yes.
I hope that you can easily understand and
you're not too cool for my videos.
Dan: She's a little advanced.
Vanessa: Sure, if you're here.
That means you can already understand two
native English speakers.
Congratulations, but hopefully it means that
you're learning something new while also understanding
most of our explanations.
I just used our third expression.
Dan: You did?
Vanessa: The slang expression.
I hope you're not too cool for these videos.
Dan: Too cool for.
Vanessa: Yes.
I want to know when you were a teenager, what
was something that you decided that you didn't
want to do anymore?
Dan: Yeah, I can actually go back to when
I was younger.
Vanessa: Okay.
Dan: Even when I was a kid, when I was eight
years old, I was too cool for Barney.
You know Barney is?
Vanessa: Barney is a kids TV show.
It's probably popular around the world.
It's a big purple dinosaur.
Dan: He's a big purple dinosaur in a big costume
and he's, I'm happy, you know and I remember
being as a kid, I was too cool for Barney
and this means that I thought it was dumb.
I wouldn't watch it myself.
If somebody was watching this show, I would
maybe look down on them.
Vanessa: They're too like, they're children.
Children, watch this.
I'm too old and too cool for this.
Dan: I don't watch Barney.
I'm too cool for Barney.
Vanessa: Yes.
I feel like this slang expression, too cool.
Dan: Barney, B-A-R-N-Y.
Vanessa: N-E-Y?
Dan: Y?
E-Y?
Vanessa: E-Y?
Something like that.
I'm sure you'll find the big purple dinosaur
online.
Dan: That's it.
Vanessa: Well, when you say too cool for something,
it's pretty self explanatory.
You feel like, this is for children.
This is for someone who is less than me so
it's a slang expression where you feel like
you're above some kind of item or activity
or concept.
Oftentimes, teenagers feel like this.
Maybe when you were a teenager, you felt like
you were too cool to hold hands with your
mom when you cross to the street.
You said, I'm a teenager.
I can handle this.
I'm too cool for that and you kind of feel
like that's for children.
Dan: Yes, and this slang term definitely implies
attitude.
You're not just saying, oh no, I don't like
that.
You're saying, that's stupid.
Vanessa: Yeah, I'm too cool for that.
Dan: That's dumb.
I wouldn't listen to that music anymore, loser.
Vanessa: Yeah, so you might hear this often
used by kids, like in Dan's example about
the children's TV show or by teenagers but
we can use this as adults in a joking way
because we often take expressions that are
strong and then use them in lighter situations
where it's not as serious.
For example, maybe if I want to watch, I don't
know if you've seen the, I think it's a Pixar
movie, Coco.
It's really cute and I enjoyed it a lot.
If I asked Dan, hey, do you want to watch
Coco tonight?
He might say.
Dan: I would say.
Vanessa: He would say yes.
Let's imagine that he might say no and let's
say-
Dan: Let's say I'm too cool.
Vanessa: Yeah, I might say, what?
Dan: Coco.
Vanessa: Are you too cool to watch Coco?
Dan: I don't watch cartoons.
Vanessa: That's not true but in this situation.
Dan: I actually love cartoons.
Vanessa: We might say, I might say to Dan,
are you too cool for Coco?
Dan: Too cool for Coco.
Vanessa: Are you too cool for Pixar movies?
Are you to cool for more animated movies?
Here, we're using this not in a, like a teenager
or childish way, but just in a joke kind of
way.
Dan: It's kind of a joke.
Vanessa: Yeah, to say oh, you think you're
better than this movie?
It's great for everybody.
I enjoy it.
I think a lot of people have enjoyed it so
you can use too cool for something in a lot
of situations.
Dan: By the way, the original expression I
think from too cool is too cool for school.
We actually say that still.
Sometimes people even say that like as a good
thing, like, wow, that's too cool for school.
Vanessa: When would you use that?
This is taking slang to the next level, extra
slang.
Dan: If you saw maybe like an outfit that
was really cool.
You'd say, that's too cool, or that's too
cool for school.
I wouldn't say this is extremely common but
it's, people would understand you're not being
rude.
Vanessa: Yeah, so I imagine if you heard this
in a TV show or a movie, now you'll feel a
little more comfortable with too cool and
also too cool for school, which is just the
rhyming original expression.
Dan: Yeah, the original expression was, you
would say somebody is too cool for school.
He's too cool for school.
He doesn't like to go to school.
He is unhappy at school.
Vanessa: He has an attitude.
Dan: He doesn't like reading, that kind of
thing.
That's the original source.
Vanessa: Yeah.
Well, we have a lot of great sentences here
from those of you who are joining us live,
talking about-
Dan: Your grandma's too cool to watch Coco.
Vanessa: Oh, no.
Well, Sylvester says I will never be too cool
to watch cartoons.
Dan: I agree.
Vanessa: I'll never be too cool for cartoons.
Dan: Maybe it's because I was a child with
cartoons.
I still like cartoons especially Miyazaki,
does anybody watching Miyazaki, Japanese animation.
Vanessa: Very cool.
Dan: I like that.
Vanessa: Very cool or another great comment
we've got here is, I'm too cool for dancing.
Oh, so maybe if your friend asked you to go
to a concert to dance or a club or somewhere
to dance on, I'm too cool for dancing.
Dan: I'm not too cool for dancing but I'm
bad at dancing so.
Vanessa: There are lots of excuses you can
give, various excuses.
Dan: Too cool for Brad Pitt?
Vanessa: Oh, maybe there's a lot of different
ways that you can use too cool for something.
Well, I'd like to thank you so much for joining
us to learn about phrasal verbs, idioms and
the slang expression today.
Figure out, in over my head and too cool for
something.
If you enjoyed Dan and I's explanation and
our little stories about this, we do this
every month in The Fearless Fluency Club.
We make a vocabulary lesson that's about,
how long would you say?
Dan: That's like 30, 40 minutes.
Vanessa: Oh, I'd say it's about an hour.
Usually there's two parts.
There's two 30 minute parts that we have for
the vocabulary lessons.
Dan: Okay, that's true.
We cut it in half.
Vanessa: Yeah, we cut it in half and make
two different parts so you'll get an hour
of about 15 to 20 vocabulary expressions every
month.
For the month of December, you got a sneak
preview about these expressions.
In December, three of the 17 or 18 expressions
are figure out something, in over my head
and too cool for something.
Dan: Too cool.
Vanessa: These are three expressions that
we talk about in the December lesson set for
The Fearless Fluency Club so I'd like to show
you really quick and give you a quick sneak
preview.
Dan: Yes, so Let's take a look.
Vanessa: Yes, of this wonderful monthly lesson
set so that you can see here.
We have the December 2018 lesson set that's
going to come out tomorrow.
If you join in December, you'll get access
to the December lesson set and you can use
the coupon code NEW, N-E-W to get it for only
$5 and I'd like to show you here, we have
the vocabulary that we just mentioned.
The vocabulary part one, you can see, oh we're
going to put this on.
Dan: I had a haircut.
Vanessa: On mute, just so that you can see
it.
We talk about a lot of different expressions
and then you can see the clips from the original
conversation when it was used so here, you're
getting great explanations from Dan and I.
Two different parts and then we go on to the
grammar lesson and in December, you're going
to get one of the longest grammar lessons
that I've ever made.
It's 34 minutes but you're going to get access
to this grammar lesson where we're going to
discuss some excellent expressions with would
have.
Would have, oh, this is a complex verb.
It seems simple but it's quite complex so
we break it down, go through it step by step
and I try to help you use it naturally.
Then in the next section in December, we talk
about pronunciation.
This pronunciation lesson is extra special
because we're going to be focusing on a lot
of sentences.
Oh, here we have a sentence with figure out,
they can figure things out.
We go through this step by step and you can
figure out how to pronounce this sentence
as accurately as possible and then you get
to watch the conversation with my friend,
Faith.
You get to hear her naturally say this originally
in the conversation because the last video
is the conversation where we have a 30 minute
chat together about her interesting job, working
for AmeriCorps, which is a nonprofit in the
U.S.
She volunteers at different schools, at different
organizations and has interesting perspective
about education.
We're going to talk about some wonderful ideas
there.
We also focus on a story that includes all
of the vocabulary and grammar.
All of the would have expressions.
Some new expressions as well that are in the
story.
This is a fun Christmas story because it's
the December lesson set and you can study
this all together.
I hope that this lesson set overall will help
you to feel comfortable using English and
really trying to incorporate it into your
daily life so if you enjoyed today's lesson,
feel free to join us every month in The Fearless
Fluency Club.
There is a link in the description.
You can continue learning with Dan and I.
Dan: You can figure out English with us.
Vanessa: Yes, you can figure out how to use
it.
Dan: If you're not too cool for school.
Vanessa: Yeah, don't be too cool for school.
Before we go today, I'd like to practice pronouncing
a final sentence that uses two of the expressions
we talked about today.
I wrote it down here so that we can practice
it together.
It is, I would like to say it slowly, and
then we're going to speed it up and I want
you to say it out loud so that you can use
your speaking muscles.
I'd like you to join me too, Dan.
Dan: Okay.
Vanessa: Okay.
Dan: I'm nervous.
Vanessa: All right, we got this.
The sentence is, I was in over my head before.
Dan: In over my head.
Vanessa: Now I figured out how to learn English.
I was in over my head before, but now I figured
out how to learn English.
What does the sentence mean?
I was in over my head before, but now I figured
out how to learn English.
Dan: Well, this means that before today maybe,
you didn't know how to speak English at all.
You didn't understand me.
You didn't understand Vanessa, but now you
have figured it out.
Vanessa: Yes, you have figured out the best
path and the best method is with Vanessa and
Dan.
Dan: This is true.
Vanessa: Let's speed this sentence up and
I want you to pronounce it clearly and then
use it yourself.
Are you ready?
I was in over my head before, but now I figured
out how to learn English.
Let's say it faster.
I was in over my head before, but now I've
figured out how to learn English.
I wasn't over my head before, but now I figured
out how to learn English.
Can you say it?
Dan: I was in over my head before, but now
I have figured out how to learn English.
Vanessa: I was in over my head before, but
now I have figured out how to learn English,
with Vanessa and Dan.
Thanks so much for learning English with us.
I hope that you enjoyed this lesson.
This live lesson you can join me for a new
lesson every Friday and you just can subscribe
to my YouTube channel and click the bell to
get a notification every time there's a live
lesson.
I hope that you'll continue to enjoy these
and we'll see you again next Friday for a
new lesson here on this YouTube channel.
Thanks so much.
We'll see you again later.
Dan: Thanks, everybody.
Vanessa: Bye.
Dan: Bye.