Hi.
I'm Vanessa from SpeakEnglishWithVanessa.com.
I get this question a lot, "Vanessa, why can
I understand you but I can't understand other
English speakers?"
Today I wanna give you three reasons why.
Let's talk about it.
The first reason why you can understand me
but not other english speakers in TV shows
and movies, is because the topic that we're
talking about is a pretty comfortable topic
for you.
We're not talking about economics, politics
or sociology.
We're talking about learning English.
So this is something that you feel pretty
comfortable with already, you've probably
been studying English for a while.
So the kind of vocabulary that you need to
use in these videos is pretty basic.
So I think this is a great reason why you
probably understand me in these videos more
than TV shows, but let's talk about the second
reason why.
To be honest, when I first started making
YouTube videos, I was kinda surprised that
so many people could understand me, because
when my husband Dan watched my videos, he
told me, "Vanessa, you're talking too fast.
People aren't gonna be able to understand.
You're teaching English, you need to speak
slower and in a better way so that people
can understand you."
But I kept getting comments from people who
said, "Vanessa, I can understand you.
This is great!"
So I've continued in that way and forgot his
advice.
So this was a little surprising to me, but
after thinking about it, I realized that even
though I speak pretty quickly, this is pretty
natural speed.
I do speak clearly and I think this is just
something about my style of speech, where
I speak clearly but I do speak fast.
So I think that's something that hopefully
will test your ears and help you start to
get ready.
I don't wanna speak like this, "Welcome to
this English channel.
I'm so glad that you are here."
That's boring and it's not your level.
This is for intermediate learners.
So I wanna speak quickly and at a difficult
pace, but clearly.
So I hope that that's useful for you.
I wanna test your ears, but also speak clearly.
The third reason why you can understand me
but you can't understand other English speakers
as much is because simply, it's just me.
It's not a conversation.
You're just listening to me talk and you're
focusing on my voice.
So because these videos are one person.
You're not needing to focus on multiple people
at the same time and in TV shows and in movies,
you're often gonna hear two or three or five
people talking together, and that's real life.
So I wanna be able to present that to you
to share real conversations with you, and
that's what a lot of my premium course, 'The
Fearless Fluency Club' is about.
I present two conversations per month to you
with me and another English speaker and with
me and Dan, my husband talking about vocabulary,
talking about a natural topic because I wanna
test your ears.
I wanna help train you to be able to understand
everyone and anyone, and that's really important,
to hear multiple people talking at the same
time.
I hope that today's video and these three
ideas were useful for you.
I wanna help you start to understand other
native speakers now.
So I wanna give you a special sample lesson
set that you can start watching and testing
your ears.
If you click on the 'I' at the top up here
or in the description below, you can watch
a full sample lesson set for 'The Fearless
Fluency Club'.
You're gonna see a conversation between my
sister and I, you're gonna see a conversation
between Dan, my husband and I, and you're
gonna be able to really learn what is going
on.
And this is gonna test your ears and train
you to understand other speakers.
So go ahead, click on the link.
When you go to that link, you can download
the course ... the sample course for free.
This is something that you can watch whenever
you want and I really wanna help you completely
understand it and use it yourself of course.
So I hope that you'll join me and watch this
sample lesson set and I hope it's useful for
you.
So far, hundreds of English learners have
really enjoyed it.
So you can be there too.
Thanks so much every one.
Have a beautiful day.
See you the next time, bye.