C[ustome]r
Customer satisfaction, CS
P[atro]n
p[atronag]e
client
c[lientel]e
trade
risk trade
trader
transact
transaction
credit transaction
deal
dealer
deal in used cars
close a deal
broker
stock broker
bargain
make a good bargain
bargain about the price
prosper
flourish
thrive
prosperous thriving business
lucrative
profitable
money-making business
this is the best offer we can make
auction
offer
bid
offer $2,000 for the car
out bid
the highest bidder
retailer
retail
wholesale
sell out by retail
wholesaler
outlet
distributor
automobile distributor
parlor
pizza parlor
pizzeria
margin
have a good, fair margin of profit
commission
used
second hand
used car
second hand bookstore
trade in
an old machine
as is
buy a used car as is
over-the-counter
over-the-counter share
over-the-counter drug
on approval
buy goods on approval