Get ready to laugh!
Let's learn English with this hilarious
and famous scene from Friends -
The Test!
So this is a really great scene
where they play a game
to see which of the friends
knows each other best.
So we get to learn a lot of very funny
facts about each of the characters.
And if you're new here, every single week
we help learners like you
understand natives without getting lost,
without missing the jokes,
and without subtitles,
So if you want to be able to do that too
then I highly recommend
you hit that Subscribe button and
the bell down belowt to not miss
a single one of our new lessons.
Now, let's watch the clip!
Hey! Do you love learning
English with Friends?
Well, we've helped thousands of learners just like you
understand natives and
improve their English fluency
with our premium course
Fluent with Friends!
You can get a free taste of this right now
by signing up for
our 3-part mini-course.
Just click up here or
down in the description below
and become the next learner that
we help to get Fluent with Friends!
Hey! If this lesson is making you laugh,
then I highly recommend that you check
out this other lesson,
where we get to learn
all sorts of different secrets
about the gang from Friends!
Alright! Great job today!
Now it's time to test everything that you learned.
You can do that that by watching
the full scene without subtitles,
and you'll find that down
in the description below.
Also, please support our channel
by hitting that Like button
and subscribing so you don't miss a single one
of our new lessons.
Check out that mini-course that I told you about,
so that you can take your fluency to the next level.
Also, I have two videos here that I think
you'll really enjoy.
Now it's time to go beyond the classroom,
and LIVE your English!
Aww yeah!