Aww Yeah! In today's lesson,
we're learning English with Jennifer Aniston's
hit new series, The Morning Show.
So, over the holidays, I watched the first season
of this Apple TV+ Original,
and I have to say I was seriously
impressed.
It has superb performances, from both
Jennifer Aniston and Reese Witherspoon,
as well as an intriguing story.
And it's no surprise that it was
nominated  for several Golden Globes
which is a prestigious award in the United States.
So, I thought it would be perfect for you to learn with, and don't worry because the scene we chose today
has no spoilers. So, whether or not you've
seen the show you, will be able to enjoy it
and learn with it, as it is completely
full of advanced English vocabulary.
But, before we get into the lesson, I wanted
to let you know that if you're new here,
every single week, we make
fun lessons just like this one
so that you can understand fast speaking natives
without getting lost,
without missing the jokes,
and without subtitles.
Fran says that we helped in
to making learning English fun and easy
and you will too — all you have to do
is hit the Subscribe button,
and the bell down below, so you don't miss
any of our new lessons.
Hey! Do you want to use correct
pronunciation when you speak English?
Well, our Fluent with Friends course
can help you a lot.
Over this 48-week course, you will learn alongside
the first two seasons of the TV series Friends,
starring Jennifer Aniston.
Plus, you get 20+ page PDF Power Lessons,
vocabulary memorization software,
access to our Fluency Circle global community,
and so much more.
And the best part is, you can try it
for FREE right now
with our 3-part Masterclass.
All you have to do is click up here
or down in the description below
to learn more and sign up.
Want more Jennifer Aniston
Well, check out this funny lesson that
we have teaching with her on The Ellen Show,
after you finish this video.
I hope you had a lot of fun today!
If you did, then I highly recommend you
check out The Morning Show.
It really is a phenomenal series that can
help you to improve your English a lot.
And be sure to give us a like if you would like us
to make more lessons with The Morning Show.
Finally, if you're a fan of Jennifer Aniston,
then you definitely are gonna want to check out
some of our lessons that we have
with her on Friends.
Now, it's time to go beyond the classroom and...
LIVE your English!
Aww Yeah!