Awww yeah ladies and gentlemen today we
have an English lesson with a classic
animated film Shrek so even though it's
been 18 years since the first Shrek was
screened for the first time we can
honestly say and that this amazing movie
and all of its beloved characters never
get old The Adventures of Shrek and his
friend donkey are very humorous because
it's actually parody of many other fairy
tale stories that have been adapted to
film
- Wake up
-What?
so, that said, you'll get to
learn a lot of vocabulary that is
related to these classical stories and
fairy tales that take place in medieval
times. Plus, definitely pay attention
closely to all the pronunciation because
not only will you learn formal and
informal English but you'll also get
some exposure to English and Scottish
accents and if you're new here well
every single week we make fun lessons
like this one to help you understand
fast speaking natives without getting
lost
without missing the jokes and without
subtitles just like Hassan who said that
he has improved every aspect of his
English in the year that he's been
studying along with our lessons and you
can too
all you have to do is hit that subscribe
button and the bell down below so you
don't miss any of our new lessons. So, are
you ready to laugh and learn with this
awesome movie let's do it!
Awwww yeah!
If you like Shrek and then I bet you will also
really enjoy all the different lessons
that we've done with Disney movies you
can check out those in this playlist
after you finish this lesson.
so in this forty eight week course you
will learn alongside the first two
seasons of the friend series. Plus, every
week you get twenty plus page PDF power
lessons vocabulary memorization software,
access to our fluency circle global
community and so much more what are you
waiting for
you can try it for free right now all
you have to do is click up here or down
the description below to learn more and
sign up.
Isn't learning just so much better when you have fun
like you did today?
well don't stop the  learning now. Be sure to hit that
subscribe button so that you don't miss
any of our new lessons and check out one
of these other lessons that I know
you're gonna love now it's time to go
beyond the classroom
and live your English, awww yeah!