Get ready for a funny English lesson with friends
that will help you to understand some
American English insults and more and if
you're new here every single week we
make fun lessons just like this one so
that you can understand fast speaking
natives without getting lost without
missing the jokes and without subtitles
Alexa said she's getting everything she
needs as a non-native speaker of English
from our Channel
and you will too all I have to do is hit
the subscribe button and the button
below so you don't miss any of our new
lessons
Hey if you would to master how Americans
really speak then there's no better way
than with our fluent with friends course
in this forty eight week course you will
master American vocabulary pronunciation
cultural context and so much more
alongside the first two seasons of the
TV series friends and you get 20 plus
page PDF power lessons vocabulary
memorization software access to our
fluency circle global community and so
much more you can try it for freed right
now with our three-part master class so
what are you waiting for just click up
here or down the subscription below to
learn more and sign up now
Rachel really make the perfect pair and
you can continue learning with them in
this playlist after you finish this
lesson just give a click up here to find that.
Hey wasn't that fun? Well don't stop now
you can continue your English learning
adventure with one of the lessons over
here and now it's time to go beyond the classroom
And live your English!
Aww yeah!