So based on the popularity of our first lesson with Harry Potter and so many of you asking us for another one
We thought we would bring you a new lesson with a famous scene from this delightful movie in this scene
We see the kids learning one of their first spells as we explained in the other lesson
We made on Harry Potter a spell is a group of words used as a magical charm or incantation
In the Wizarding World, they use wands to cast spells that is to cause them to take effect
All right. Let's watch the first part of the scene where Professor Flitwick explains the spell
One of the Wizards most rudimentary skills is an imitation
The ability to make objects fly
You will have your feathers good
Now what?
Don't forget the nice wrist
Movement, we've been practicing the swish ad flick
everyone
Enunciate Wingardium Leviosa off you go then
One of the Wizards most rudimentary skills is an imitation or the ability to make objects
fly
Levitation is the action of rising and floating in the air without any physical support
This word is typically associated with supposed magical or super powers
so when Superman or a Dragonball Z character flies
We could also say they are levitating the verb to levitate can refer to causing something to levitate or levitating yourself
Example some people actually believe that if you meditate enough you can achieve the ability to levitate
one of the Wizards most rudimentary skills is an invitation now the adjective rudimentary it means the same as
basic, so if something such as a skill as considered rudimentary
It relates to the beginning or initial phase of learning. That is it is a basic skill not an advanced one
Example she only had a rudimentary formal education that you will have your feathers
Professor Flitwick will now try and teach the students how to levitate an object by magic for practice
They're going to try the spell on feathers
now well
Don't forget the nice wrist
Movement we've been practicing the wrist is the part of the body between the hand and the arm where you'd normally wear a watch
Movement, we've been practicing the swish
Everyone
In the Wizarding World to cast a spell with your wand also requires you to make a specific
movement of the wrist while holding the wand he describes this movement as the swish and flick if
Something swishes or you swish it?
It moves through the air making a soft sound this refers to the first part of the movement
Which is about making a long soft swishing movement with the wand
The second part is about flicking the wand if something flicks or you flick it it
moves and hit something or simply stops with a short sudden movement if
You flicked someone or something. It could be painful as we see when Monica and Rachel fight here
Did you just flick me? Okay, well you wouldn't let me finish and I was
Hey, if you're enjoying having fun learning with videos like this one on our Channel
But you feel like you need some more help
Taking your English comprehension and fluency to the next level
Then I highly recommend you check out our fluent with friends course, you will master native vocabulary pronunciation
Cultural context and so much more with the first two seasons of the popular TV series friends
You can get a free trial at right now with our three-part mini course
Just click up here or down the description below to learn more and sign up. Don't forget the nice wrist
Movement, we've been practicing by the way. Did you notice how Flitwick pronounces the word wrist here? Don't forget the nice wrist
Movement, how about the word rudimentary?
one of the Wizards most rudimentary skills
You probably noticed this sounds very
Different from the are sounds heard in the American accent and even different from the more common standard British accent
Let's hear it again. Don't forget the nice wrist
Movement, you just heard the distinctive rolling R
That is common to the Scottish accent interestingly enough
It sounds very similar to the rolling are found in Spanish Portuguese and Italian languages
Something you'd like to say there are several things. I would like to say
We never use
Transfiguration as a punishment surely Dumbledore told you that
Might have mentioned it, but you will do well to remember it. I
Thought if you find it now, I could can't only a parent or a guardian consign since I am neither it would be inappropriate
What do you think of all the different accents that can be heard in the Harry Potter movies do you find any particular character?
Who you think is harder to understand join the discussion in the comments below
the swish ad pick everyone
Good
Enunciate Wingardium, Leviosa
To enunciate it's a say or pronounce words fully and clearly for example
I really try to enunciate much more when I teach English than when I speak with American friends in
This case Professor Flitwick is referring to making a clear sound and correctly pronouncing the spell
Don't yet Wingardium Leviosa?
Off you go then off you go
Is a British English idiomatic expression with two slightly different?
applications in this case
it was used as to tell somebody that they can now start doing something such as a
Presentation or an activity in class as seen in the scene Flitwick is allowing his students to start practicing
However, this expression is more commonly used to let somebody know that they can now leave
Is there something you wish to tell me?
No, sir
Very well then off you go
Highly recommend reacquaint yourself with the chapter on antidotes
I'll tell you more about bazaars in our next class right off you go. Please forget your rat tail
Wingardium Leviosa
Stop stop stop
You're going to take someone's eye out
Besides you're saying it wrong. It's
Leviosa, not Leviosa, you do it then if you're so clever
Wingardium Leviosa
Oh well done. See here everyone. Miss Granger has done it. Splendid
Guardian Leviosa
Stop stop stop
You're going to take someone's eye out.
Even though Hermione is probably jokingly exaggerating here when she says that Ron is going to take someone's eye out
she means that he's been too careless or
irresponsible with this movement because it seems to be so
Uncontrolled and aggressive that he will end up causing an accident and hurting somebody's eye
Example, I don't want you kids playing with fireworks. You could lose a finger or take somebody's eye out
Hey, so every week. We hope learners like you understand fast speaking natives without getting lost without reason the jokes and without subtitles
Just like Huma who said that she's improving her English fluency every day by watching our videos
So if you want to improve your fluency just like Huma then I highly recommend you hit that subscribe button and the bell down below
To not miss a single one of our new lessons
You're going to take someone's on it besides you're saying it wrong
It's Navy Oh saw not Navy Oh song
Besides means the same as also or in addition
It is used to add new information like an argument to what has already been said
Beyond your reach
Sorry, no way you had matter you upside besides you don't even know how to fly
I'll be forever grateful for this
To both of you. I want to go with you one day perhaps
Sometime my life will be too unpredictable
and besides
He'll meant to be here in this case Hermione
First said that he was doing the wrong movement by being too aggressive with it. Then she added that he was also saying it wrong
You're going to take someone's Island besides you're saying it wrong
by the way
be careful not to confuse it with the word beside which is a
Preposition that is used to indicate being by the side of or next to something
Okay
Now you marry but never known your family
You see them
Standing beside you
Who sang wrong? It's never OSA not live you saw
You do it then if you're so clever to be clever is to have the ability to quickly understand
Elaborate or apply ideas more simply put to be clever is to be intelligent
Ron is saying to Hermione that if she thinks she is so smart telling him that he is doing it all wrong
She should try doing the spell herself
The one does it truely answer to me
Hi honey, I'm clever but not clever enough besides. We've got a
Hoax me we know
We'll show you a quicker way you do it then if you're so clever
As an informal idiomatic expression go on is used to encourage somebody to say or do something
Talk about tongues right go on
Phones, right Harry, you're gonna need your strength today. I'm not hungry
Come on now, you'll be late
trees leaving gone
Come on, we're saying wrong. It's never OSA not Liv you saw
Wingardium Leviosa
Although Wingardium Leviosa are made-up words
We can still analyze this humorous explanation that Hermione gave Ron from a phonetic point of view and learn a lot from it
She explained that when saying when Guardian Leviosa, you should not pronounce Leviosa with an open a sound at the end
But rather with a schwa sound
So instead of saying Leviosa, you should say
Musa
This is really useful to practice because the schwa sound is the most common sound in English
So in order to have clear correct pronunciation, it is important that you master it. So, let's practice it with Hermione
in Guardium Musa
Wingardium Leviosa
Oh
well
See here, everyone this great just done it
splendid splendid means excellent fantastic or very impressive example
We had a splendid holiday together. It can be used by itself. Just as Flitwick did to express great admiration for something or somebody
In the old days. I used to throw together the occasion or supper party
next door to
Our considers an honor sir
You'd be welcome to Granger
I'd be the lightest that blended
All right
So now it is time for you to test everything that you learned today by watching the full scene
without subtitles and to further challenge you we will be actually
Pausing at the scene at different moments to ask you some different quiz questions, and hey
We definitely want to make more lessons like this one with Harry Potter
So if you enjoyed it
Let us know by hitting that like button below and if there's a particular
Scene you would like us to do just write it down in the comments below and maybe we'll do it
Alright, so now it's time to roll the test
One of the Wizards most rudimentary skills is
limitation
The ability to make objects fly
You will have your feathers good
now well
Don't forget the nice wrist
Movement, we've been practicing the swish add flick
everyone
Enunciate Wingardium, Leviosa
Off you go there
Wingardium Leviosa
Stop stop stop. You're going to take someone's eye out besides you're saying it wrong
It's Leviosa not live you saw you do it then if you're so clever
Don't bore Olivia Wingardium Leviosa
Oh
Well dub see here everyone this gray just done it
splendid
Thank god Livio swell time. Oh
I
Think we're going to need another feather over here professor
Alright well if you're a Harry Potter fan, we're definitely going to be making up more lessons with the movies
I highly recommend that you hit that subscribe button
So you don't miss any of those and if you're learning British English, well we have a ton of more British English lessons
Which you will find in this playlist. I recommend you watch that after you finish this video
So now it's time to go beyond the classroom and live your English. Hi-yah