In this video you're going to learn English with one of the best and most popular rappers of all time, Eminem.
We're covering portions of three of
his hit songs in this lesson.
Lose Yourself
The Real Slim Shady
and The Monster featuring Rihanna.
Just a word of caution, these rap songs contain some profane language so listen at your own risk.
If you're looking for a family-friendly lesson, be sure to check out our playlist.
This is how it will work.
First, you will watch each video clip
with subtitles in English,
then we will explain the meaning
of the most important words, expressions,
cultural context and pronunciation in the lyrics.
Finally, you will test everything you've learned
by watching the clip without subtitles
and answering some quiz questions.
Are you ready?
Let's get our groove on with Eminem.
So every single week we make fun lessons with some of your favorite movies, TV series, music and more.
So that you can understand fast speaking natives without getting lost,
without missing the jokes,
and without subtitles.
In fact, Daniel said that we make learning English
as easy as the ABCs,
and you can make learning English
a lot more fun and easy too.
All you have to do is hit that subscribe button
and the bell down below,
so you don't miss any of our new lessons.
So, if you want to master connected speech then one of the best ways is with our Fluent with Friends course.
Every week for 48 weeks you will learn following the first two seasons of the friends series,
including 20-plus page PDF power lessons that break down all of the pronunciation for you,
vocabulary memorization software,
access to our Fluent Circle Global Community and so much more.
Do you want to try it?
Well, you can try it for free right now with our three-part master class.
You just have to click up here or down in the description below to sign up for that.
And we're looking forward to meeting you there.
Hey do you want to be able to learn with
songs all on your own?
Well then definitely check out this video where we show you how.
Alright, I hope that you learned a lot today, and you feel like you've opened up your ears and your mouth...
...to native pronunciation.
If you love music, then be sure to check out some of our other lessons featuring different artists and
songs in this playlist and now it's time
to go beyond the classroom and live your English!
Aww yeah!