Aw yeah! Get ready to laugh and learn
English with Priyanka Chopra Jonas
on the Ellen Show.
So, every single week we help
learners like you to understand
fast-speaking natives without getting
lost
without missing the jokes and
without subtitles!
If you want to be able to do that too,
then I highly recommend you hit that
Subscribe button and the bell down below
so you don't miss a single one of our
new lessons.
So Priyanka sure has terrific English, right?
Wouldn't you love to have better fluency and know more about American culture
just like she does?
Well, a great place to start is
our premium course Fluent with Friends,
which will help you to learn tons of
real-life vocabulary, native pronunciation,
and American culture so
that you can understand natives,
and speak confidently.
You can get a free trial
now with our mini course.
Just click up here or down in the description below.
So, as you know, interviews like this one are a fantastic
way to learn English, and we have a whole
playlist full of English lessons
teaching you with interviews just like this one.
You can find that by clicking up here or down in the description below.
Alright! Great job today!
I hope you learned a ton!
Be sure to test everything that you learned
by watching the original interview which
you can find down in the description below.
Also support our channel by
hitting the like button and I recommend
that you subscribe too,
so you don't miss a single one of our new lessons.
Take your English to the next level
with that mini course I told you about!
Also, check out all of our lessons with Ellen,
and this other lesson that I think you will really enjoy.
Now it's time to go beyond the classroom and
LIVE your English!
Aww yeah!