Aww Yeah! Are you ready to learn with
one of the most popular cartoons of all time?
In today's lesson, we go under the sea with
SpongeBob SquarePants and his friends,
Patrick Star and Squidward.
We will be learning with three clips
from three different episodes
which you might remember if
you've ever watched this classic series.
So, let's dive in!
Hey! Just before we jump into learning with this clip,
I wanted to let you know that if you're new here,
every single week we make fun lessons
just like this one so that you can learn
to understand fast-speaking natives
without getting lost,
without missing the jokes,
and without subtitles.
Just like Paula, who says that she's
learning how English is really spoken,
not how she learned at the academies.
And you will too — all you have to do is hit
that subscribe button and the bell down below
so you don't miss any of our new lessons.
So, would you like to master how natives really speak, just like you did here
with the morphing of the D + Y sound?
Well, the most fun way to do it is with
our Fluent with Friends course.
In this 48-week course,
you'll learn alongside the first two seasons
of the TV series Friends.
You get 20+ page PDF Power Lessons,
vocabulary memorization software,
access to our Fluency Circle global community.
and so much more.
And you can try that for FREE
right now with our 3-part Masterclass.
All you have to do is click up here
or down in the description below
and you can learn more
and sign for that right now.
Hey, if you enjoy SpongeBob, then I bet you will also
really love this lesson that we made
with the anime classic, Dragon Ball Z.
You can watch that after you finish
this lesson by clicking up here.
So, if you enjoyed today's lesson with SpongeBob, remember to give us a like down below
to let us know that you would
like more lessons like this.
And you're doing a fantastic job, so continue your
English learning journey with one of the videos here.
And now, it's time to go beyond the classroom,
and LIVE your English!
Aww Yeah!