Aww yeah today we are learning with the one the only King of Pop Michael Jackson
So the song that we're learning with today Billie Jean has frequently been mentioned
by different magazine polls as one of the best songs ever made
and it's really no wonder why Michael Jackson was a genius songwriter and we can see this
particularly in the creativity of the lyrics of this song Billie Jean
Because he uses the same word to mean different things throughout the song
and we're going to explain all that to you
So now let's roll the first clip
Alright, so I hope you're already having a lot of fun singing along,
but before I get into explaining all the vocabulary and pronunciation
I wanted to let you know that if you're new here every single week we make lessons with your favorite songs
TV series and movies so that you can understand fast speaking natives
without getting lost
without missing the jokes
and without subtitles
Just like Faridah who told us that in just the first two weeks of watching our lessons
They can already see improvements in their speaking and your English comprehension
and fluency is going to improve a lot too
All you have to do is hit that subscribe button and the belle down below to don't miss any of our new lessons
Hey, do you want to learn a correct native stress and pronunciation like this?
Well, then I highly recommend you check out our fluent with friends course every week for 40 weeks
You will get a lesson following along with the first two seasons of the TV series friends
Plus you get 20 plus page PDF power lessons
vocabulary memorization software
access to our fluency circle global community and so much more and
You can try for you right now with our three-part master class
All you have to do is click up here or down the description below and you can learn more and sign up for that
right now
Hey, are you loving this lesson so far well we've made two other
fantastic music lessons with Queen
And Eminem
You can check those both out in this playlist along with all of our other lessons with songs also
Comment down below and let us know which of these is your favorite song by Michael Jackson
Alright, I hope you've had a lot of fun getting groovy with this song by Michael Jackson.
And if you want to continue having fun with more music then be sure to check out all of our lesson with songs in this
Playlist and now it's time to go beyond the classroom and live your English. Aww yeah