In today's lesson, we will learn with a
scene from the British TV series, Peaky Blinders.
Now, this series is set in the
early 1920s in England,
and tells the story of the Shelby family,
and their urban street gang, the Peaky Blinders.
Now, if you are a fan of mafia and family crime
stories, you should definitely stick around
because you are going to love
learning all of the expressions
and advanced vocabulary in this scene.
But, I wanted to let you know first that it does contain
some explicit language and offensive words,
so, if you're looking for something lighter, then
you might want to check out this playlist instead,
which you can find by clicking up here.
Finally, these characters come from Birmingham
in the center of England,
and it can be even difficult for me
as a native speaker from the United States
to understand them sometimes.
So, if the first watch you feel like
you didn't understand anything,
don't worry, relax, because we are going
to help you to understand all of it,
and you will understand much better the second go.
So, are you ready? Let's get into it!
All right. So, now, we are going to learn all of the most
difficult vocabulary, pronunciation, and cultural context
from that clip.
But, first, I wanted to let you know that
if you're new here, every single week
we make fun lessons just like this one,
so that you can understand fast-speaking natives
without getting lost,
without missing the jokes,
and without subtitles.
Like Pachu, who says that our lessons are helping him
to increase his English listening and speaking.
And, you will too — all you have to do
is hit that subscribe button and the bell down below,
so you don't miss any of our new lessons.
So, I know you're watching this lesson
because you get frustrated
when you can't understand natives,
whether it's in music, TV series, movies,
or even in real-life conversations.
And this hurts your confidence.
You're scared of actually using your
English in real-life.
You want to be able to confidently
understand natives in any situation,
just like your mother tongue, right?
Well, this is exactly why we created
our Fluent with Friends course.
Our goal for you with this course is to be able to
learn the principles of real native speech,
so that you can understand natives
no matter how fast we speak,
and have a lot of fun doing it.
Now, in this 40-week course, you will learn alongside
the first two seasons of the TV series Friends,
with innovative tools like Power Lessons,
vocabulary memorization software, and more.
And, you even get access to our global community
of English learners, the Fluency Circle.
So, do you want to try it?
Well, you can do that for FREE
with our 3-part Masterclass.
All you have to do is click up here
or down in the description below,
and you can learn more
and sign up for that right now.
Are you learning British English?
Well, then after you finish this lesson,
you're definitely gonna want to check out
some of the videos in this playlist.
All you have to do is click up here
or down in the description below to find that.
Awesome work today!
That was a really difficult one,
but if you enjoyed it, then it's definitely worth
checking out the full series.
In fact, I just finished the most recent season
and I really can't wait for the next one to come out.
And, don't stop — you can continue
on your English learning journey
with one of these fun lessons over here.
And, now, it's time to go beyond the classroom
and LIVE your English!
Aww Yeah!