Today, we're going to learn advanced
English vocabulary with The Simpsons.
So, do you want to understand natives
even when we speak fast, without getting lost?
without missing the jokes?
how about, without subtitles?
Well, you're in the right place.
You better hit that subscribe button
and the bell down below
so that you don't miss a single one of our new lessons,
and you can take your English to
the next level just like Alexey,
who says that he took his English from the A2
to the B1 level in just one month with our lessons.
Hey guys! Just a quick interruption.
So, here at Learn English with TV series, we are celebrating two million subscribers
Thanks to your support, we've been able to help more
and more people to look at learning English
as fun and meaningful.
So, to thank you you can get a 49% discount
on our Fluent with Friends course.
for the next few days until April 24th.
Just imagine this time next year,
you could understand your favorite series
and laugh along with all the jokes,
have a confident conversation,
get a promotion at work
or even move to another country.
Really, the possibilities are endless
when you set your mind to it
and the Fluent with Friends course can
help you a lot in reaching your goals.
Just like Edyta, who told us that our course helped her
stop looking at English as a boring school subject,
and helped her become passionat
about learning the language.
So, what are you waiting for?
You can learn more and sign up by
clicking up here or down in the description below.
And remember to get your 49% discount,
just use the code 2million at checkout.
Now, let's get back to laughing
and learning with The Simpsons.
Awesome work today! Now if you are ready
to take your English to the next level,
and understand your favorite movies and
series even without the subtitles,
then, I highly recommend that you take advantage
to check out our Fluent with Friends course
and get a huge discount by using
that code 2million at checkout to get 49% off.
Just click down in description below
to find a link for that.
But, remember, you only have a few more
days to take advantage of this offer.
Now, it's time to go beyond the classroom
and LIVE your English.
Aww Yeah!