Get ready to laugh and learn with Taylor Swift and Ellen!
So, I'm Ethan, and every week here on learning English with TV series
we help you to understand fast English
without getting lost, without missing the
jokes, and without subtitles.
So, if that sounds like something that you would like to be able to do,
be sure to hit that Subscribe button and the bell down below
so you don't miss a single lesson.
Do you love laughing with Ellen?
Well, then be sure to hit that like
button down below because this lets YouTube know
that you want to be notified
when we make new lessons like this one.
If you're enjoying this, then highly recommend you check out this playlist
teaching you real-life English with the Ellen show.
Alright, it's almost time for your test!
But before we do that, I wanted to let you know that if you get frustrated
when you can't understand fast-speaking natives,
then we have a really fantastic FREE 3-part mini-course for you.
It's going to help you to learn all of the pronunciation, the vocabulary,
and the cultural secrets that you need to understand natives at any speed.
You can check that out by clicking up here!
Now, let's jump into your test!
Aw yeah! I hope you had an awesome time
learning with us today.
Be sure to check out that free 3-part mini course
I told you about. Also, Subscribe, so you can get
all of our newest lessons!
Check out this playlist of lessons
Learning with Music, and
check out this other video that I think you'll really like.
Now, it's time to go outside the classroom,
and LIVE your English!
Aww yeah!