Milly sat under the apple tree and watched the rain clouds sweep over the hills. --
What a wet day! --
She ate an apple and waited for the rain to stop. --
Soon it did. --
The sky turned blue again, and the Sun shone, warm and golden. --
Then she saw the rainbow.  --
It began as an explosion of light, high in the clouds. --
The sky filled with dazzling colours: blue, orange, green and purple. --
Then both ends of the rainbow began to fall to Earth... --
The rainbow landed in the garden. --
‘Wow!’ Milly went closer and touched the rainbow.  --
She felt nothing, just air. --
But the colours moved beneath her fingers. --
When she looked up, the rainbow seemed to be stretching on and on into space. --
'What would happen if I stepped inside it?' she wondered. --
There was only one way to find out... --
She stepped inside. --
It was beautiful!  --
And very quiet.  --
Milly couldn’t hear anything. --
She looked up.  --
The rainbow seemed to go on forever... --
WHOOSH! Milly was sucked up by the rainbow.  --
It was a tunnel of light.  --
She whizzed along like a button up a vacuum cleaner.  --
Wind whistled past her ears.  --
She tumbled over and over but didn’t hurt herself: she was carried on a soft cushion of air.  --
Up and up and up she went, so fast. --
But rainbows go up... --
and rainbows come down.  --
Soon she was falling down the far side of the rainbow.  --
She could see green below. --
Green grass, rushing up to meet her, faster and faster... --
BUMP! She landed hard, but nothing was broken. --
Milly stood up.  --
She was on the other side of the valley, standing on a steep green hill. --
She could see her house, far away. --
It was like a tiny white box with a rainbow in the garden. --
Everything was calm and peaceful and very lovely... --
WHOOSH! Suddenly she was shooting back through the rainbow, faster than a firework. --
Red, blue, yellow ... stripes of light, flashing by. --
Up, up, up she went and down, down, down...  --
BUMP. She landed back in her own garden. --
'Oww...!’ Milly groaned.  --
‘I am going to be so bruised tomorrow.' --
Then she had a thought... --
'GOLD! There is always gold at the end of a rainbow!' --
She dropped to her knees and started to dig.  --
The earth flew out behind her, covering the grass with stones and soil. --
'Come on, come on! It must be here somewhere...' --
She went deeper and deeper.  --
Then she saw something shiny, under her fingertips. --
She pulled it out. --
'Gold...' --
Milly stared at it, breathless with excitement. --
It was a golden coin, bigger than usual money and much heavier.  --
She rubbed it clean.  --
There were words written on it: Make a wish before the rainbow fades. --
'Oh wow!' she said. 'This is amazing! A wish!' --
Her head began to fill with ideas, everything she could wish for. --
But then she saw something.  --
The rainbow was starting to fade. --
It was going thin at the edges. --
'No! I haven't made up my mind! Please - wait!' --
But the rainbow didn't wait. --
It was fading. Going away, and taking her wish with it. --
'No! I’ll make my wish soon. Just a moment, please!' --
But still the rainbow was fading.  --
The golden coin was getting hot in her hand. --
'Ohh....! Choose... choose... Yes. YES! I have it!' --
Milly closed her eyes and made her wish and VOOMF! --
The rainbow disappeared, and so did the golden coin. --
Milly hardly dared to move. --
Had her wish come true? --
Maybe. --
She looked up.  --
The sky was peacock blue. --
The Sun was golden, warm on her face. --
Such a beautiful day. --
Such a beautiful world. --
'Even if the wish doesn't come true, I am a very lucky girl,' she said.
--
And she smiled. --