Making my way down town
Walking fast
Faces pass
And I'm home bound
Staring blankly ahead
Just making my way
Making a way
Through the crowd
And I need you
And I miss you
And now I wonder
If I could fall
Into the sky
Do you think time
Would pass me by
'Cause you know I'd walk a
thousand miles
If I could just see you, tonight
It's always times like these
When I think of you
And I wonder If you ever think of me
'Cause everything's so wrong
And I don't belong
Living in
Your precious memory
'Cause I need you
And I miss you and now I wonder
If I could fall
Into the sky
Do you think time
Would pass me by, oh
'Cause you know I'd walk a
thousand miles
If I could just see you tonight
And I, I don't want to let you know I,
I drown in your memory I,
I don't want to let this go
I,I don't.
Making my way down town walking fast
Faces pass
And I'm home bound
Staring blankly ahead
Making my way
Making a way
Through the crowd
And I still need you
And I still miss you
And now I wonder
If I could fall into the sky
Do you think time, would pass us by
'Cause you know I'd walk a
thousand miles
If I could just see you, now
If I could fall into the sky
Do you think time would pass me by
'Cause you know I'd walk a
thousand miles
If I could just see you
If I could just hold you, tonight.
www.RentAnAdviser.com