Making my way down town -- 我要去市區
Walking fast -- 我走得很快
Faces pass -- 陌生臉孔飛逝而過
And I'm home bound -- 我在尋找回家的路
Staring blankly ahead -- 但我只能望著前方發呆
Just making my way -- 我知道我該向前走
Making a way -- 一直向前走
Through the crowd -- 穿過這群人
And I need you -- 我需要你
And I miss you -- 我想你
And now I wonder -- 我想知道…
If I could fall -- 如果我能掉進
Into the sky -- 到天空
Do you think time -- 你覺得時間…
Would pass me by -- 會讓我回到你的身邊嗎
'Cause you know I'd walk a thousand miles -- 你知道的，我已經走了幾千哩
If I could just see you, tonight -- 我只希望今晚讓我見到你吧！
It's always times like these -- 我經常有這個困擾…
When I think of you -- 每次，當我想到你的時候…
And I wonder If you ever think of me -- 我想知道，你是不是也想到了我？
'Cause everything's so wrong -- 因為每件事都錯的離譜
And I don't belong -- 我也不屬於
Living in Your precious memory -- 你那珍貴回憶裡的一部份.....
'Cause I need you -- 因為我需要你
And I miss you and now I wonder -- 我想你, 我想知道…
If I could fall -- 如果我能墜落到
Into the sky -- 掉進天空
Do you think time -- 你覺得時間…
Would pass me by, oh -- 會讓我回到你的身邊嗎
'Cause you know I'd walk a thousand miles  -- 你知道的，我已經走了幾千哩
If I could just see you tonight -- 我只希望今晚讓我見到你吧！
And I, I don't want to let you know I, -- 而且我不希望讓你知道
I drown in your memory I, -- 我沉醉在你的回憶
I don't want to let this go -- 我不想讓一切流逝
I,I don't. -- 我不想
Making my way down town walking fast -- 我很快走向市區
Faces pass -- 陌生臉孔飛逝而過
And I'm home bound -- 我在尋找回家的路
Staring blankly ahead  -- 但我只能望著前方發呆
Making my way -- 我知道我該向前走
Making a way -- 一直向前走
Through the crowd  -- 穿過這群人
And I still need you -- 而我仍然需要你
And I still miss you -- 我仍然想你
And now I wonder -- 我想知道…
If I could fall into the sky  -- 如果我能墜落到天空
Do you think time, would pass us by  -- 你覺得時間會讓我回到你的身邊嗎
'Cause you know I'd walk a thousand miles  -- 你知道的，我已經走了幾千哩
If I could just see you, now -- 我只希望現在讓我見到你吧！
If I could fall into the sky -- 如果我能墜落到天空
Do you think time would pass me by   -- 你覺得時間會讓我回到你的身邊嗎
'Cause you know I'd walk a thousand miles   -- 你知道的，我已經走了幾千哩
If I could just see you -- 我只希望讓我見到你吧！
If I could just hold you, tonight.  -- 我只希望今晚讓我抱你吧！