The power of love is a curious thing -- 愛的力量是神奇的東西
Make a one man weep, make another man sing -- 它讓一個男人哭泣，讓另一個男人唱歌
Change a hawk to a little white dove -- 把一隻老鷹變白鴿
More than a feeling that's the power of love -- 不只是感覺，它是愛的力量
Tougher than diamonds, rich like cream -- 比鑽石還堅硬，像奶油一樣濃稠
Stronger and harder than a bad girl's dream -- 比壞女孩的夢想更堅強
Make a bad one good make a wrong one right -- 讓壞的變好，讓錯的變對
Power of love that keeps you home at night -- 愛的力量讓你晚上回家
You don't need money, don't take fame -- 你不需要金錢，也不需要名氣
It's strong and it's sudden and it's cruel sometimes -- 它很強壯，但它有時也很殘酷
But it might just save your life -- 但它可能拯救你的性命
That's the power of love -- 那就是愛的力量
First time you feel it, it might make you sad -- 你第一次感覺到它時，它可能讓你傷心
Next time you feel it it might make you mad -- 下一次你感覺到它時，它可能讓你瘋狂
But you'll be glad baby when you've found -- 但你發現時，你會很高興
That's the power makes the world go'round -- 它就是讓世界運轉的力量
And it don't take money, don't take fame -- 你不需要金錢，也不需要名氣
Don't need no credit card to ride this train -- 不需要信用卡就能遨遊四海
It's strong and it's sudden it can be cruel sometimes  -- 它很強壯，但它有時也很殘酷
But it might just save your life -- 但它可能拯救你的性命
They say that all in love is fair -- 他們說所有愛都是公平的
Yeah, but you don't care -- 是的，但你不用在乎
But you'll know what to do -- 你會知道做什麼
When it gets hold of you -- 但它捉住你時
And with a little help from above -- 你不需要任何幫助
You feel the power of love -- 你能感覺到愛的力量
You feel the power of love  -- 你能感覺到愛的力量
Can you feel it? -- 你能感覺到嗎？
Hmmm -- 嗯
It don't take money and it don't take fame  -- 你不需要金錢，也不需要名氣
Don't need no credit card to ride this train  -- 不需要信用卡就能遨遊四海
Tougher than diamonds and stronger than steel  -- 比鑽石還堅硬，像奶油一樣濃稠
You won't feel nothin' till you feel -- 你開始感覺不到，直到...
You feel the power, just feel the power of love -- 你感覺到愛的力量
That's the power, that's the power of love - 那就是愛的力量，那就是愛的力量
You feel the power of love -- 你感覺到愛的力量
Feel the power of love -- 那就是愛的力量