Hello everyone, and welcome back to
English with Lucy today I am going to
teach you eight ways in which you can
improve your listening skills, your
English listening skills. Now number one
is take advantage of YouTube's subtitle
system but make sure you understand and
use it properly so in order to improve
your daily English, the English that
you'll use every day. I want you to find
vloggers and kind of daily youtubers
that document their everyday life who
actually add their own subtitles or
vloggers that don't rely on the
auto-generated subtitles. Nowadays
YouTube has some very very good subtitle
software but it's never perfect when I
post a video YouTube analyzes what I say
and it posts what it thinks I've said as
auto-generated subtitles. However, for
every single video I do pay for someone
else to actually write the subtitles and
there are a couple of reasons why I do
this. Number one, I want correct spelling
and grammar YouTube software doesn't add
in the correct punctuation and kind of
commas and quotation marks and things
like that and that's important for you
to learn. It's important for you to see
where a sentence starts and ends and
where there might be pauses. Also
sometimes the software just completely
misses out words, it misspells things, it
misunderstands what I've said. Sometimes
it puts very rude things in place of
what I've actually said so I choose to
buy my own subtitles and a lot of
creators do this and a lot of vloggers
do this and it's very very useful. Kn
fact on my own vlogging channel where
I've been documenting my life, my
personal life on the farm in rural
England, I do write the subtitles for you
so you know that what I'm saying on
screen is what is also written on screen.
How can you tell if the subtitles are
trustworthy or not?
Well one indicator is the term
'auto-generated' which will come up if
YouTube's AI system has developed the
software if you follow some vloggers
that speak a native level of English
watch their videos with subtitles every
week or every day you will pick up on so
much vocabulary vocabulary that we use
as natives in our daily lives
number two is listen to a variety of
accents and dialects now I don't just
say accents I say dialects because
different parts of my country England
have different dialects so northern
slang is very different to southern
slang in fact British English is so
unbelievably diverse so for example
something as simple for me as a can of
coke well up north they might say a tin
of coke when that would sound ridiculous
for me so to ensure that you understand
everything that you listen to or almost
everything that you listen to because
let's face it everything would be quite
the challenge because even I don't
understand everything that I hear you do
need to listen to a variety of accents
and dialects the different sounds that
they produce the different common
phrases that they use and the different
slang words as well are really really
important and I have something in the
pipeline that will massively help you
with this I'm going to talk about it
more towards the end of this video
number three
is of course speak with natives listen
to natives and speak to them but more
than that it's ask for repetition and
ask for explanation so you want to speak
with natives ask them to repeat things
and ask them to explain and justify
things a lot of students ask me how they
can find well priced native teachers or
native level teachers just because
someone isn't native doesn't mean that
they're not an excellent teacher and
this segment is sponsored by a come
and that I do genuinely highly recommend
and it's a talkie I talkie is a huge
online database of both native and
non-native teachers who will give
one-to-one video lessons with you 24
hours a day seven days a week from
anywhere in the world as long as you
have a stable internet connection an
emphasis on well priced teachers it's
incredibly affordable it's much cheaper
than an offline Academy or an in-person
tutor the teachers set their own rates
and you can browse all of them and find
the rate that's best for you and it's
also really good if you just want to
practice conversation and listening to
someone talk and asking for them to
correct your responses because not only
do they have qualified teachers they
also have community teachers who are
there to practice conversation with you
now they've given me an offer to pass on
to you you can get $10 worth of I
talking credits in your student wallet
48 hours after making your first
purchase of any amount all you've got to
do is click on the link in the
description box and sign up those
credits could actually be an entire
lesson for free or more than that
actually I've seen lessons for much less
money than that also if you are at home
and you'll find yourself with a bit of
extra spare time for an extra
motivational push you can also sign up
to their language challenge this is
where you take itoki classes and win
prizes along the way this challenge
starts on the 9th of April and lasts
until the 24th of May what do you have
to do is set yourself a language goal
and then you can earn vouchers coupons
and entries into a huge prize drawer or
you can earn prizes of up to 500 a
talkie credits so once you've signed up
to a talkie using the link down below
check out the language challenge page
set yourself a goal and start earning
those prizes right let's move on to way
number 4 now this is a really simple way
of making native speech easier to
understand
it's so simple I can't believe that
people still aren't taking advantage of
it do you know about YouTube's slowdown
function now when I look at videos that
are explaining something technical like
how to use my new washing machine or why
Mike Hoover isn't sucking sometimes I
find the person takes ages to get to the
point or to explain something so I speed
them up I click on the little cog and
then I click on playback speed and I put
them at one point two five times speed
or one point five if I'm feeling really
energetic
however the slowdown function would be
really really useful for language
learners you can slow down speech to
three-quarters of the natural pace 0.75
speed if you're watching a video and
you're interested in what that person is
saying but they are just speaking too
quickly try that 0.75 speed now 0.5
tends to be too slow the person sounds
drunk or deranged 0.75 for a very fast
talker can actually be really really
helpful even for me as a native speaker
there are some people that just go a
little more and I find it hard to follow
so if there's a vlogger or a narrator or
a presenter that you have shunned in the
past because they speak too quickly try
watching them on YouTube try slowing
them down and let me know what you think
what would be even better is if they had
their subtitles added as well so you can
watch them in slow speed without
subtitles and then watch them again with
subtitles but more about that later on
now number five this is a really common
listening tip but I'm going to talk
about it because I've got something
extra to add it is watch English movies
and TV shows now we all know this this
is one of the first tips that teachers
will give you but it can be really
really hard and really daunting to try
and work out which TV show and which
film is going to be at your level it's
so annoying to finally find something
that you want to watch after reading
loads of
and then you just can't understand it
it's also really annoying when your
computer or your network won't allow you
to access certain films and TV shows
because of where you live because your
country is not allowed to view that
specific website I have got a video
coming next week on my recommendations
for British TV shows and I start with
beginner level and move to pre
intermediate intermediate and advanced I
cover all the bases and they're all
shows that will help you develop a
British English accent and help you
understand it as well
I'll also talk about the variety of
British English accents as well now when
this video is live I will link it in the
description box so check that out
because I want to help you find
something that you can actually watch
and understand and then you can move up
through the levels number six is learn
responses that will buy you more time
because when we are listening to what
someone is saying in a language that is
not our first language we do need that
little bit of extra time to process what
they're trying to say I have a couple of
tricks and phrases that will buy you
more time things that you can say
without seeming like a strange person
going because that is what a lot of
English learners do it's a natural thing
to want to fill the gap by just making
one noise like
and you also don't want to just fill it
with silence because that can be awkward
that person might think that you've not
heard them when really you've just not
understood them what you want to do is
fill the conversation with fillers or
interjections and I've made various
videos on this topic I did a great one
with Harry from real English with real
teachers on interjections things like
ooh
I will link that down below and also
last week I did post a video on
different ways to say I know and I
understand because those are very
commonly used in conversation whilst
you're processing what someone has said
or you're just showing that you've
understood and acknowledged what they've
said again I will link that I think both
of those videos would be really really
useful they will give you phrases that
you can use to buy more time whilst
you're processing speech number seven is
listen whilst you read listen whilst you
read now I talked about this a lot in my
videos because it really really works
I'm always talking about listening to
audiobooks as you read the actual book
and I'm not just saying this for fun
this is genuinely such a good method it
trains your brain to connect written
words with spoken words it helps improve
your pronunciation it helps improve your
listening it helps improve your spelling
as well the way a word is spelt in
English doesn't necessarily give you any
indication as to how it's pronounced in
English and the way a word is pronounced
in English doesn't really help you work
out how that word is spelt this is why
English seems like such a hard language
to understand when you're listening to
it and such a hard language to pronounce
because you look at word and you just
have no idea how it should be pronounced
if you take a book that you have already
read in English or a book that you would
like to read in English and read that
book as you are listening to that same
audiobook version your problems will be
solved now it's important to find a
narrator you like and this is why I
always recommend audible audible is an
amazing platform of audiobooks they have
the most incredible selection and you
can also listen to quite lengthy samples
so you can work out if you like the
narrator's accent if you like the speed
at which they speak you can also slow
them down and you can speed them up if
you feel like you need to and the best
part is you can get one free audio book
that's a 30-day free trial or an audible
and you just have to click on the link
in the description box to sign up and
there I've put some recommendations for
great books as well audiobooks to listen
to and they're written book counterparts
it's a great method that's why I talk
about it all the time now the last tip
number 8 is to create your own
transcription exercises you know those
annoying horrible listening tests where
you have to fill in a gap right what you
hear
unfortunately they work however we want
to do something that's relevant for us
don't we so if you find something that
is particularly interesting to you have
you are interested in photography and
it's about cameras maybe you're
interested in wildlife or skateboarding
I have no idea but everybody has their
thing don't they I personally love
cooking and gardening well if you find
something that's very very interesting
to you create your own listing exercise
because it won't be so boring and
painful this exercise is all about
listening blindly meaning that you are
not looking at any visuals so you don't
see their mouth moving you don't see
their emotion nothing and you definitely
definitely don't look at any subtitles
take one sentence or if you're feeling
more advanced you can take a couple of
sentences and listen to it once then you
can listen to it for a second time and
then you have to write down exactly what
you've heard or what you think you've
heard after that you can listen to it
one more time and you can look at the
transcription or the subtitles make sure
they are accurate and there you have it
you've created your own transcription
exercise using something that is
relevant and interesting to you the
reason why these sorts of exercises are
included in so many different
examinations
by so many different prestigious
examination boards across the globe it's
because they really really work so if
you can get into the habit of every time
you're listening to something
interesting and you know there are
reliable transcriptions or subtitles
available to you if you do this and make
it a habit you really really will learn
so much and you'll get so used to
analyzing things from a listening
perspective right that's it for today's
lesson I hope you enjoyed it and I
definitely hope you take some of my
advice please feel free to add any more
advice so we can all learn from each
other in the comments section and don't
forget to check out I talk e you can
click on the link down below and get
your ten dollars worth of I talk e
credits and you can start the language
challenge don't forget to connect with
me on all of my social media I've got my
Facebook I've got my Instagram and I've
got my Twitter and I've got my personal
channel with fully subtitled vlogs of my
life here on a farm I do lots of cooking
I do lots of walking I do lots of
chatting and just organizing my home
it's meant to be relaxing for you and
I've had quite positive feedback so far
so I hope you enjoy it as well I will
see you soon
for another lesson