you're learning with nine to five
English. Business English for the
workplace. Hi Tim here with another 9 to
5 English lesson. In today's lesson we're
going to learn how to talk about likes
and preferences. Talking about things we
like is something we do all the time. Whether you're in a meeting a casual
conversation or just having lunch
there's always a chance to talk about
what you like. And sometimes talking
about what you like means talking about
a preference. By preference
I mean liking one thing more than
something else. For example maybe you
want to say you think Sony is better
than LG. How can you do that
? Well one way is to just say you prefer Sony to LG. You
could also say you're more into Sony or
that you'd take a Sony  over an LG. But what
if you're talking about doing things? Say
you prefer talking to customers instead
of sending them emails. In this case you
can say you would rather talk with
customers then send them emails. Let's
practice using these expressions for
talking about preferences. Listen to each
example then repeat it yourself. Ready?
Let's get started!
I'd much rather live in Seattle than Boston
I'm more into French food than Italian.
I prefer magazines to books.
I take an iPhone over
Android phone any day.
So we've practiced different ways of
talking about a preference but what if
you're not comparing I mean what if
you're having a conversation about cars
for example and you just want to say
that you like Toyotas well the easy way
is just to say I like Toyota's but
rather than just using the verb like you
can use adjectives such as keen on or
partial to or fond of and don't forget
which preposition goes with which
adjectives you can say you're keen on
Toyota's but not that you're fond on
Toyota's let's have a little practice
using these expressions to talk about
things you like once again repeat the
examples after you hear them I'm quite
keen on the new Samsung monitors
I'm partial to European wine
I'm fond of travel and exploring new
places
The Times is one of my favorite
newspapers
as you heard we can also use one of my
favorites to talk about likes and that's
another example of a group of words that
you use to express an idea just like
keen on or partial to one of the tricks
to learning natural English is
remembering word combinations like this
alright so we practiced talking about
what you like but what about things you
really like in other words what about
things you love for starters you can use
that word love or even say that there's
nothing you love more you might also say
you can't get enough of something or
that you're a huge fan of something once
again you might notice these are
combinations of words and you need to
remember and practice the entire
expression so let's give this a try
remember to repeat each example I really
love what the marketing department has
done
I can't get enough of Thai food
I'm a huge fan of the new Nike ads
there's nothing I love more than a
weekend by the sea
as you can hear we can use love for all
sorts of things not just people and in a
later lesson we'll have a look at the
opposite feeling as well things you hate
so how does all this sound in real life
let's listen to a short dialogue between
two colleagues one of them wants to know
about where the other person is planning
to rent an office so are you thinking of
renting a new office in London no I'd
much rather be somewhere quieter oh yeah
any place in particular well I'm a huge
fan of Cambridge did you hear how that
worked
the second person said that he would
much rather be somewhere more quiet than
London and when asked about what city
might be preferable he said he's a huge
fan of Cambridge not too difficult right
now it's your turn to practice will
repeat the dialogue but this time we're
going to beep out
the second speakers words you will have
to say those parts yourself remember to
start by saying where you would rather
work then say the name of the place
where you'd really like to have your
office here we go so are you thinking of
renting a new office in London
oh yeah any place in particular
all right so we've learned some great
ways to talk about preferences as well
as things you like and love in our next
lesson we'll talk about the opposite
things you dislike or hate until then so
long and happy learning