You're learning with nine to five
English. Business English for the workplace.
Hi Tim here with another
nine-to-five english lesson. In today's
lesson we're going to learn how to talk
about your education. Your education is
an important part of your background and
there are lots of situations where you
might talk about where you went to
school and what you studied. A job
interview is an obvious one but you
might also talk about your education in
casual conversation. The first thing you
might mention is where you went to
school. More specifically people might be
interested in which university you
attended. And there are several ways we
can tell them about that. Firstly you
might just use that verb "attend"
Similarly you could say you "went to" or
"graduated from" a certain University.
Another way to talk about your
university is to say that you're an alum
of a certain school. Alum is short for
alumnus which is a word that means a
person who attended a school. So for
example I might say I'm an alum of
Columbia University. Let's try practicing
some of this language. We're going to
give you some examples.
After each example try repeating it
yourself. Ready? Let's give it a go!
I graduated from Yale in 2008.
For my undergrad I went to the London
School of Economics.
I attended a small Technical College in
Colorado.
I'm an alum of Washington University.
Ok we've practiced some different ways
of talking about our University.
But another important aspect of your
education is what you studied. In English
we call your area of study your major.
This word can be used in a few different
ways. So for example if you studied
biology you could say that your major
was biology but you can also say that
you were a biology major so the noun
means both an area of study and a person who studies that area. We can also use
major as a verb such as I majored in
biology after you tell someone your
major you might also mention an area of
focus for example within business you
might have focused on finance or you
might mention your minor which is like
your secondary area of study and just as
we say we majored in a subject we can
say we minored in a subject there's
another much simpler way to talk about
your major and that's just to say
something like I studied biology of
course that's not the only course you
took but people understand that was your
major now there's one more way to tell
people what you studied and that's by
saying you have a degree in a certain
field your degree might be a master's
degree or a bachelor's degree and you
can use the short form of these
such as an MA or a BS which means
Bachelors of Science and is used for
degrees in technical fields such as
engineering or computers let's practice
some of these expressions for talking
about your major
once again you can repeat the examples
after you hear them I studied
international business with a focus on
finance
I majored in French with a minor in
political science
I started out as a science major but
switched to education
I have a Bachelor of
mechanical engineering
so we've learned some different ways of
talking about your University and your
major but how did these expressions
sound in a real conversation let's
listen to a short dialogue between Tanja
and Jose tanya is asking Jose about his
education so did you go to university
around here yeah I graduated from Iowa
State University in 2010 oh yeah great
school what did you study
I majored in business with a minor in
statistics as you just heard Jose says
he graduated from Iowa State University
and when asked about what he studied he
says he majored in business he also adds
that he had a minor in statistics now
it's your turn to practice will repeat
the dialogue but this time will be bout
the second speakers words you will have
to say those parts yourself remember
to start by saying that you graduated
from Iowa State University then you can
say that you majored in business and
minored in statistics so did you go to
university around here
oh yeah great school what did you study
you
all right we've learned some great ways
to talk about your education including
what university you attended and what
you studied be sure to tune in next time
when we learn how to talk about your
career until then so long and happy
learning