Business Skills 360, the podcast that looks
at the other side of English.
Hello and welcome back to the Skills 360 podcast.
I'm your host, Tim Simmons, and today I want
to finish up our series on English interview
skills.
In previous lessons, we've gone over some
of the fundamental questions about who you
are and what you've done. Today I want to
take a closer look at talking about your career
goals and researching prospective employers.
Interviewers don't just want to know whether
you've got the skills, personality, and qualifications.
They also want to know that you're a good
fit, and that they are a good fit for you.
One important question you need to be ready
for in an interview in English is "why are
you leaving your current position?" This question
makes a lot of people squirm. But it's actually
an opportunity to talk about growth and change.
Nobody stays at the same job their entire
life. And this question isn't necessarily
fishing for problems in your past.
What kinds of things can you talk about as
reasons for change? You might mention several
desires, such as the desire to learn, to take
on more responsibility, to enhance certain
skills, to relocate, to adjust your work-life
balance. All these are great reasons to change.
Of course, if you were laid off, you need
to be candid about that. I'm not suggesting
you lie. Just that you keep your answer future-focused.
And that means not badmouthing your current
boss, colleagues, or workplace.
Talking about why you're leaving your current
job will segue naturally to answering questions
about why you want this job. And the key here
is showing knowledge, suitability, and value.
By knowledge, I mean you know something about
the company, its products, its reputation,
its culture, and its values. By suitability,
I mean that you jibe with the company and
the job fits with your career goals. And by
value, I mean that your skills and experience
will help you make a real contribution.
Speaking of career goals, another common but
tough question during a job interview is "where
do you see yourself in five years?" With most
interview questions, I advise people to be
specific. But not this one. It's okay to state
very generally what your aspirations are.
For example, you might say "I'd really like
to be involved with the strategic side of
things" or "I'd like to be taking on more
management responsibilities."
Whatever your answer, it should be possible
to achieve within the company where you're
applying. They're going to sink time, money,
and resources into you. They want to know
it will pay off for them, not just you. So,
perhaps the worst thing you can say is "I
want to run my own business." The interviewer
will immediately think you're going to run
off with all their ideas!
One thing you'll notice is that most of my
suggestions require you to actually know something
about the company where you're applying. All
successful interviewees have done their homework
in this regard. You can start with the company
website, of course, but also check Google
for recent news stories and press releases.
Use LinkedIn to find out more about the company's
leaders and employees. And look through other
social media channels to get a more complete
understanding. The Glassdoor website can also
give you an inside look at company culture
- but don't get scared off by a few negative
reviews. Disgruntled people are often the
most vocal.
Researching the company will also help generate
some good questions that you can ask. It's
fairly standard at or near the end of a job
interview for the interviewer to turn the
tables with a question like "Do you have any
questions for me?" The worst thing you can
do is to say something like "no, all good
thanks." That shows a troubling lack of interest.
So, what should you ask about? Here's a few
good ones. "How will you measure the success
of the person you hire?" "What are some of
the challenges the person in this position
will face?" "Can you describe a typical day
or week in the job?" "How would you describe
the culture here?" And probably one of the
best questions, because it gets to the heart
of what they're looking for, is "In the past,
what has differentiated the people who were
good at this job and those who were great?"
That final question will impress the interviewer
and give you a good idea if you really want
the position or not. After all, unless you're
really desperate, an interview is a two-way
street. You're both assessing whether you
and the job are a good match.
And as I've explained, you'll have to do that
by talking about why you are leaving your
current position, why you want this job, and
where you see yourself in the future. And
through it all, a solid understanding of the
company is just as important as an understanding
of English for job interviews.
That's all for today.
Copyright Business English Pod Ltd. All rights reserved. https://www.businessenglishpod.com
So long, stay safe. And happy learning!