Hello and welcome back to the Skills 360 podcast.
I’m your host, Tim Simmons,
and today I want to finish off our look at
the top 10 essential business English skills.
In our last lesson, I focused on small talk
and English conversation skills such as expressing
opinions, asking questions, rejecting ideas,
and getting action.
Of course, “conversation” is what comes
to mind when someone talks about language skills.
But a lot of our English communication is
not conversation, per se.
Your skill set has to include a lot more than
expressing opinions, agreeing, disagreeing,
and making small talk.
Imagine for a second that you’re delivering
a presentation in English or conducting a
training session.
What kind of skills do you need in those situations?
Well, one thing you need to master is talking
about how something happens or how something
is done.
By that I mean describing a process or giving
instructions.
The key skill here is what we call sequencing,
or putting your ideas in a logical order and
making that order clear to your audience.
To do this, you might use simple words like
“first,” “second,” “third,” “next,”
and “finally.”
But you might also use expressions like “at
this point,” “meanwhile,” and “subsequently.”
Using this kind of language helps you organize
your ideas, and you’ll be less likely to
lose your audience.
Connecting words aren’t limited to processes
and instructions.
Adept English speakers will use all sorts
of words to connect their ideas and structure
a good argument.
Think about proposing an idea to your boss.
Will you rattle on and hope he picks up the
thread of what you’re trying to say?
Or will you present a cohesive and persuasive
argument using expressions like “because
of this,” “therefore,” “nevertheless,”
and “furthermore?”
Now I am not suggesting that you pepper your
speech with these kinds of words just to sound
intelligent.
There’s a time and place for these formal
expressions.
But the importance of organizing your ideas
holds true in any situation.
And in more casual circumstances, you can
simply rely more on simpler words like “and,”
“but,” and “so.”
Besides presentations or training, another
important situation with a special skill set
is bargaining, or negotiating in English.
And I’m not just talking about high-level
talks on corporate partnerships or negotiating
a major business deal.
Any situation that involves give and take,
cooperation, or compromise involves a kind
of bargaining.
Maybe you and a colleague are trying to design
a website together.
Or you and your boss are trying to figure
out a work schedule.
Or you are trying to get two of your employees
to agree on a project budget.
These are all situations that demand bargaining
skills.
You need to acknowledge both sides and propose
trade-offs.
Often this requires you to make conditional
sentences, using words like “if,” “unless,”
and “as long as.”
And if those statements are hypothetical,
you’ll have to make sure you get a handle
on important helping verbs like “would”
and “could.”
Okay, I’ve talked a lot today about organizing
your ideas, and about situations that require
clarity of information.
This brings me to another essential skill:
summarizing.
What happens after you’ve presented a clear
and logical argument, or you’ve negotiated
a compromise in a meeting?
Well, you need to ensure everyone can latch
on to the main ideas.
That’s when you summarize.
You might hear a summary introduced with expressions
like “to sum up,” or “let’s recap
briefly.”
But the real skill is figuring out what those
main ideas or points are and then stating
them concisely.
You can’t repeat everything that was said
verbatim.
You need to distill only what is essential
and paraphrase ideas appropriately.
Now before I do exactly that with my own ideas
for this lesson, I’ve got one more essential
but challenging skill for you: speaking clearly.
You probably know some people who seem to
just have a knack for clear speech.
But it’s not just innate talent.
You can learn to sound clear too, if you put
in the time and effort.
So practice correct pronunciation.
Try to enunciate clearly, even when it doesn’t
feel natural for your mouth to make certain
shapes or sounds.
It gets easier with practice.
But if you mumble, or don’t make the effort
to try to produce the right sounds and intonation,
then it doesn’t matter what you say, because
people won’t be able to understand you.
Now how about that summary?
I’ve covered five essential skills for every
ace English speaker.
First, there’s the ability to present a
sequence or step-by-step instructions.
Next is the skill of connecting your ideas
logically.
Then there’s bargaining and summarizing.
And finally, you need to work on your pronunciation
and intonation.
That’s all for today.
So long.
And happy learning!