You're learning with 925 English -
business English for the workplace.
hi Tim here with another 925 English
lesson. In today's lesson we're going to
learn all about how to start a
conversation.
Sometimes we call starting a
conversation breaking the ice. You can
think of the ice as that initial silence
between people. It could be between
strangers on a plane or co-workers in a
lunchroom and when we break the ice we
say something friendly to start a
conversation. So how do you do that?
What do you say and what topics our best? Well in our first lesson we had an example of
a greeting between work colleagues who
didn't know each other.
Can you remember how they got their
conversation started after the greeting?
What did they say? Let's have another
listen to that short dialogue and you
can listen for the conversation starter.
A pleasure Shelly quite the setup here
isn't it?
Yes, they have really gone to town. I
should get them to come decorate my
house. Yeah right good idea
So did you hear what the first person said? She said
quite the setup here isn't it and that
shows us that asking the question is a
great way to start a conversation
especially if you've just been
introduced. You can use simple and direct
questions or you can use a comment with
the tag question. Just a quick note on
vocabulary here. The 'setup' of the room is
the way it is organized and decorated
And 'quiet the' means impressive so amber thinks the decoration of the room is very
impressive and Shelly agrees saying
they've really 'gone to town'. If we go to
town with something it means we make a
big effort.
all right let's try a little practice
with some simple questions for starting
a conversation. Listen carefully to each
example then repeat the example yourself.
ready let's get started can you believe
how much snow we're getting so where are
you off to today
you visiting family for the holiday or
just getting away
ok so those are examples of direct
questions about things like the weather
and travel these are pretty safe topics
for starting a conversation which is why
you might hear people use them so often
and you will also hear yes no questions
like can you believe and WH questions
like where are you going today killed
those are direct questions now how about
those tag questions I talked about first
what is that a question
well to make a tag question you make a
comment then had a little question at
the end for example you might say the
airport is quite busy isn't it or you
could say you work in sales don't you
let's do a little practice with this
kind of question remember repeat each
example after you hear it
a beautiful day isn't it
funded program do you think you were in
the afternoon workshop where you
now there are
are couple of tricks to tag questions
first
the question tag needs to match the
comment
so with a beautiful day you need isn't
it because the day is the it that with
you were in the morning workshop you
don't say isn't it instead we say we
weren't you the subject has to match and
the verb tits has to match and here's
the second thing about tag questions a
positive statement is followed by a
negative tag question like a nice day
isn't it
while a negative statement is followed
by a positive tag question like there
isn't much snow is there does that make
sense
ok so remember that little dialogue
between colleagues that we heard at the
start of the lesser let's use that for a
bit of practice will repeat the dialogue
but this time will be put out a couple
of lines so you can add your own
responses you need to start with the tag
question about the set up to get the
conversation started and you'll have to
respond to the other person's comet
let's give it a go
yes they've really gone to town I should
get them to come decorate my house
showed that covers using questions to
break the ice we've practiced tag
questions and some simple direct
questions but sometimes the question
fields to direct doesn't it it might
even seem rude with someone we've never
met before so there's another way we can
start a conversation and that's with the
simple comment this is useful for
talking with strangers or someone you
haven't been introduced to what do I
mean by making a simple comment
all you do is say something about the
situation or place your in and the other
person can respond however they like
let's give it a try
will give you some good examples of
icebreaker comments you can listen and
repeat ready looks like they've got
quite the evening planned for us
you sure are a lot of people here
tonight looks like it's going to be a
full flight
sure is quiet in here today
seems simple enough doesn't it and maybe
you noticed the expression looks like
which is very useful for introducing a
comment and the words sure which is
useful for friendly emphasis it means
certainly like it certainly is a nice
day
but how does this kind of conversation
starter work in real life remember a
comment like this
invites a response from the other person
once they respond you can continue on
the same topic let's listen to a short
dialogue to see how this can work you'll
hear two travelers in an airport one of
them starts with the simple comet just
like we practiced then the other person
responds and the first person continues
with some explanation of the situation
looks like it's really starting to fill
up yeah pretty busy I think everything's
kind of backed up something about a snow
storm in the Midwest angered
so did you hear how that weren't you
just comment on something around you let
the other person respond and keep
talking then the conversation flows from
there now you can try this yourself will
repeat the same dialogue but will be put
out the first and last lines it's your
job to break the ice with the comment
then continue talking after the other
person responds ready to give it a go
yeah pretty busy
okay now we've looked at starting the
conversation with strangers but how
about talking with your co-workers
well it's not too different from talking
with people you don't know you can use a
question or a comment and it's best to
pick an easy or general topic like
sports or the weather or news let's try
a little practice listen to each example
and repeat what you hear
ok let's begin can you believe this rain
we've been having did you see that race
last night did you hear about
the latest earthquake in Japan
the Euro sure seems to be in a bit of
trouble
so what do you think
this new guy who's running finance
we offer
ask these kinds of questions after we've
already said hello to the other person
but what if you haven't said hi or hello
well that's when you can use a word like
so or pay before your question just as a
way of introducing it well that pretty
much wraps it up for today we've
practiced starting a conversation with
questions after a greeting breaking the
ice with comments and starting
conversations with coworkers don't
forget to go back and practice these
techniques again and try using your own
ideas in the examples will be back soon
with another 925 English lesson until
then so long and happy learning