You're learning with 925 English -
business English for the workplace!
Hi Tim here with another 925 english
lesson. In today's lesson we're going to
learn how to talk about the work you do
in your job. Last time we looked at how
to talk about your job, which might
include stating your position and
company and what you are responsible for,
But what if someone wants to know more
about what you actually do? For example
someone might ask what your daily
routine is like or they might ask about
your current or past projects. How can
you describe these kinds of activities?
Well let's start with talking about your
current work or projects by current. I
mean things that are happening now. When
we talk about things happening right now,
we normally say we are "doing" something.
You might use "we" if you mean your
company or team is working on something
or you might use "I" if you are talking
about just what you are doing.
Let's practice some examples of talking
about your current work in this way.
Listen to each example then repeated
yourself. Ready? Let's get started.
We're busy designing a new housing development
in California.
Right now, we're doing a big website
project.
We're getting ready for a trade show.
At the moment, I'm overseeing the
installation of a new machine.
That's not too hard, right? And you'll
notice that it's always good to use
strong or specific verbs such as "design"
and "oversee" when you talk about what you're doing.
Now what if someone asks
you about what you've done in the past?
Well to talk about your past work, it's
still a good idea to choose a strong
verb.
Just remember to put it in the past
tense. But you don't need to say "was
doing." You can just use the simple form
"did" because it's completed.
Let's try a little practice talking
about your past work. Just like last time
I want you to repeat the examples after
you hear them.
I chaired the fundraising committee last year.
I led the company's annual audit.
My colleagues and I designed the new
elementary school in clifton.
I used to work on site as an engineer
but now I've moved into management.
One really useful expression you might
have noticed is "used to."
When there's an activity in the past that you did many
times or was ongoing
you can say you "used to" do it.
Now what if someone wants to know your
current routine.
I mean how you usually spend your time
during your workday.
Well you can certainly use that exact
expression i just used. You can say you
"spend" your time doing something or you
can say your work "involves" some type of
activity. And when you mentioned the
activity use the "-ing" form like "I spend a
lot of time writing reports."
Let's practice talking about your daily
routine with a few examples.
Once again, repeat what you hear.
I spend a lot of time answering the
phone and emails.
My work involves talking with customers
and solving technical problems.
I put in a lot of time visiting
customers every day.
Most of my day is spent calling clients
and handling orders.
So that's how we talk about our daily
routines but how might this sound in a
real-life conversation? Let's listen to a
short conversation between two people
who have just met. The first person is
asking the other person, John, about his
work. Listen to how John answers the questions.
So do you guys have any new projects on
at the moment?
Actually, we've just started work on a
new factory.
You must be busy what's your day-to-day
routine like?
Most of my day is spent testing new machines and checking on
deliveries.
Can you hear how this works? John is asked
about new project, so he mentioned
something his company has just started
and when he is asked about his
day-to-day routine he explains how his
day is spent. And notice those verbs
"testing" and "checking on." Now it's your
turn to practice. We'll repeat the
dialogue but this time we're going to beep
out the second speakers words. You will
have to say those parts yourself.
Remember to start by mentioning your
current work then you'll talk about your
daily routine.
So do you guys have any new projects on at the moment?
You must be busy! What's your day-to-day routine like?
So now you've practiced talking about
your work. But another part of talking
about your job, involves talking about
your company. You'll have to tune in to
our next lesson to learn how to do that.
Until then, so long and happy learning!