Hold tight please
This is Anna on a bus going to an interview for a job as a [[sales executive(業務經理)]]
Hip hop Trading
One of London's fastest-growing companies
How are you feeling Ana
A little nervous but
I really want this job
Don't worry Anna as long as you say the right things
You'll be fine
[[You need to sell yourself (妳要推銷妳自己)]]
[[Be confident not arrogant (有自信，不自大)]]
And give examples
Like
[[A good example that comes to mind （我想到個好例子）]]
[[I'm particularly proud of（我特別自豪的是）]]
[[Timekeeping is important to me （守時對我很重要）]]
Alright
Thanks
Perhaps you can come with me
Sarjana
You're on your own now but will be listening in
You just arrived
Good luck
Coming
Hello I'm pull the manager Trading
And you must be
It's Anna yes very good thanks for coming no somewhere in this pile I've got your CV
Is that it
Thanks Hannah [[your qualifications look impressive（妳的經歷讓人印象深刻）]] but I was wondering what sales experience
Can you bring 12 jump
I work in a shop one
Sell yourself
Give a good example
Alright
Well a good example that comes to mind is
When I wasn't.
With a campaign to promote and sell a new range of clothes
I love doing it and it was
Sorry
Give me
Casualty pool
Thanks Denise
It looks like you've achieved a lot during your time at University
Could you give me an example of good teamwork injured during your time now
Sorry
Sugar
Thank you Denise
So you want an example
I was [[ a treasure of the debating society at University (大學辯論社會計)]]
That was okay I suppose
[[Be more enthusiastic （再多點熱情）]]
The debating societies exciting
I mean
I'm particularly proud of how I organized the finances for the debating Society
We had a very small budget
And I had to make decisions on what to buy
I'm particularly proud of
[[Positive but not boasting (正向但沒有吹噓)]]
You're doing well very impressive
So you're a
Good Solana Anna
We like organized people here
Loop cinema
My simplistic Taylorville CV
Do you need some help
Oh no I'm sure it'll dry out
Carry on please
Also
Timekeeping is important to me timekeeping is important to me
That's good
I always try to complete my work on time
At University I never handed my assignments in late
That's good to hear
We like punctuality here
Excuse me pool
Sorry it's a bit late
I thought you might like a biscuit with your tea
Thanks
Lovely custard creams
No
Funny I want to ask you what
Exactly made you apply for this
Don't put this company
Oh
Well
The reason I applied
Is
Yes yes yes Anna
Do you need a bit more time to think
What she going to say
How would you answer that
Join us next time just find out
Before we go his a reminder of some of the great lines and is used today
A good example that comes to mind
I'm particularly proud of
Time keeping is important to me until next time bye bye