Back to the offices of Tip Top trading has interview for a sales job continued
When we lost at goodbyes
Tip Top boss pull head up Anna
Why she wanted the job
But she said
Since then she's added
And as we join her again is saying
Well
I'm
Camel
If you can't think of the word you need
Find another way of saying it
I am
Well I really really want this job
And I'm willing to accept rahad if I get hit
So you're very motivated then
Motivated
Yes that's it
I am very motivated
Over to you Anna structure
Safer sleep
Then give you a first reason
Secondly
And then a second reason
Above all
And give a really
Really
Good Susie Astic
Final reason
Fastly
This job is an ideal match for my skills and experience
I spent several years working in sales
And I guess always people easily
Well I mean apart from the ones I don't like of course
They can me
I know deep trading is one of the fastest-growing companies in London
And I want to be part of that
Tip Top trading in the fastest-growing company in the plastic
Boot sector
But enough about the company about you Annabelle
Sorry Anna where were we
Well I say that firstly the job is an ideal match for my skills and experience
Secondly
The company is growing fast
And
Above all
The reason I want this job Ace
Yes
Denise
Is everything all right
No it's not
Everything is not okay
You look pale
Sit down
Drink what's left of my TV
What is floating in it
Hodad's just lumps of soggy biscuit
In infants if I can just get
Been out with my fingers for you
Delicious
Tell me what happened
Parable
Just as Anna was doing really well it looks like her interview as come to an end
What happened
Join us next time to find out
Before we go
It's a reminder of how Anna structured her response
Berkeley
His job is an ideal match for my skills and experience
Secondly
I know it's up trading is one of the fastest-growing companies in London
Above all
The reason I want this job is
Couldn't remember the word motivated
So she just found another way of saying what she meant
I really really want the job and I'm willing to work very hard if I get it
I swear I cannot
Let's hope you get the chance to finish your interview next week