In this American English pronunciation video, we’re going
to talk about the cultural use of hugging.
There’s something I’ve been wanting to make
a video about for a while, and that’s hugging.
It’s mostly because I think it must be weird
for non-Americans; sometimes it’s even weird
for me. If you’ve spent much time in the
US, you might have noticed that Americans
hug each other a lot. We do it in saying hello
to someone and in saying good bye.
You don’t do this with someone you’ve
never met when meeting, in that case you
probably do a hand shake.
&gt;&gt; Hey Hilah, this is my boyfriend David.
&gt;&gt; Hi David.
&gt;&gt; Hey.
&gt;&gt; I’m Hilah.
&gt;&gt; Nice to meet you.
&gt;&gt; Nice to meet…
Also, you don’t hug in business settings.
&gt;&gt; Hello, Ms. Smith. I’m Tom Kelley. Thanks
so much for coming in.
&gt;&gt; It’s my pleasure. Thanks so much for
meeting with me.
In business settings, you shake hands when
meeting or leaving someone, unless it’s
more causal, like someone you see every day
at your office. Then you can just say ‘hello’
or ‘good-bye’.
&gt;&gt; Morning Tom.
&gt;&gt; Hey. Morning, Rach.
But when it’s a friend, you hug when you
meet up or part ways with them.
&gt;&gt; Hey!
&gt;&gt; How ya feeling?
&gt;&gt; Long time no see.
&gt;&gt; It’s good to see ya.
&gt;&gt; Hi.
&gt;&gt; Hey.
&gt;&gt; How are ya?
&gt;&gt; Good. How are you?
&gt;&gt; Good. Thanks for having us.
&gt;&gt; Hey Rick!
&gt;&gt; Hi. Good to see ya.
&gt;&gt; You too.
&gt;&gt; Bye HaQuyen.
&gt;&gt; Bye Rachel.
&gt;&gt; It was great to see you.
&gt;&gt; It’s always good to see you.
This can happen even when you’ve just met
someone. Let’s say you’re at a small party,
and you meet someone for the first time.
&gt;&gt; Rachel, this is my friend Jacob.
&gt;&gt; Hi Jacob.
&gt;&gt; Hi, nice to meet you.
&gt;&gt; Nice to meet you. Thanks for having me.
At the end of the night, when you say goodbye,
you might hug that person.
&gt;&gt; Bye Jacob.
&gt;&gt; Nice to meet you.
&gt;&gt; Nice to meet you!
Men and women alike hug as a greeting and as
a good bye. Though sometimes, men do something
more of a slap than a hug.
&gt;&gt; Alright, man.
&gt;&gt; Alright.
&gt;&gt; Talk to you soon.
&gt;&gt; See ya.  Bye.
It can get awkward through. Some people are
less comfortable with hugging, and might offer
you a hand right as you offer a hug. In these
cases, you just have to figure out what to
do. If you’re not sure what to do, you can
try to wait for the other person to initiate.
&gt;&gt; Hey.
&gt;&gt; Oh… hi.
&gt;&gt; Hi.
So, in America, we hug when greeting someone,
and when saying bye.
What is the custom in your country? Let me
know in the comments below.
If you liked this video, click here to sign
up for my mailing list to stay on top of all
of the Rachel’s English videos and latest
news. It’s free.
That’s it, and thanks so much for using
Rachel’s English.