In this American English pronunciation video,
we’ll study pronunciation in real life English
while hanging out at a nature reserve in Florida.
First, we chatted with a ranger.
&gt;&gt; We, we came … he’s never … some of
these people have never seen a gator before.
Here’s an example of a dropping the H reduction.
Instead of ‘people have’, I said ‘people
uv’, dropping the H and reducing the AA
vowel to the schwa. Now ‘have’ just sounds
like a third, unstressed syllable at the end
of ‘people’, ‘people ov’. People – luv.
Try that with me. People have, people have.
Listen again.
&gt;&gt; We, we came … he’s never …
some of these people have never [3x]
… seen a gator before.
Instead of saying ‘alligator’, I’m just
saying ‘gator’. I think that’s more
common in my hometown than it is in most other
places.
&gt;&gt; Is that right? Yeah. Well, you’ll see
some right, you know, right on this side of
the trail.
&gt;&gt; Okay. Good. Because we want to give them
a good scare.
Good. We have two O’s here, and sometimes
non-native speakers make that sound more like
the OO as in BOO vowel, oo. But this is the
UH vowel, like in ‘push’, uh, or ‘should’.
Uh, uh. Listen again.
&gt;&gt; Good. Because we want to give them a good
scare.
&gt;&gt; Don’t get too close.
&gt;&gt; No, we won’t. Thank you.
Don’t get too close, I won’t. Don’t,
won’t. I’ve made a couple of videos on
these n’t contractions. Notice the T is
not released. It’s not won’t, but won’t.
With a stopped N sound, won’t, won’t,
nt, nt. Don’t. Try it yourself. Don’t,
won’t. Make all of your N’T contractions
this way: didn’t, can’t, shouldn’t.
Listen again.
&gt;&gt; Don’t get too close.
&gt;&gt; No, we won’t. Thank you.
&gt;&gt; What do you guys think of that?
Whaduhyuh. Here I’m taking ‘what’, ‘do’,
‘you’, and linking them together and smoothing
them out. What do you guys think of that?
We use the phrase ‘what do you think?’
a lot. How should you reduce and link these
words? Rather than making a T and a D, just
make one sound, a Flap T, which sounds just
like the D between vowels. What do, what do,
what do. Just bounce the tongue against the
roof of the mouth without stopping the air.
For both ‘do’ and ‘you’, reduce the
OO as in BOO vowel to the schwa: it’s faster,
simpler; those are both common reductions.
What do you, what do you. Try it, what do
you. Listen again.
&gt;&gt; What do you guys think of that? [3x]
&gt;&gt; Whoa.
&gt;&gt; He’s huge.
&gt;&gt; Prehistoric.
&gt;&gt; God.
&gt;&gt; Can you see the gators?
Can you. Here I’ve reduced ‘you’ again,
yuh, with the schwa. I’ve also reduced ‘can’.
We do this all the time when it’s a helping
verb, and it’s almost always a helping verb.
This means it’s not the main verb in the
sentence.
&gt;&gt; Can you see the gators?
‘See’ was the main verb, and ‘can’
a helping verb. Since the N is a syllabic
consonant, it overtakes the vowel, the schwa.
You don’t need to worry about making it.
So just make a K sound and an N sound, kn,
very fast. Can you. Try it, can you, can you.
Listen again.
&gt;&gt; Can you see the gators? [3x]
&gt;&gt; Yep.
&gt;&gt; So, it’s February, and winter is the
best time to come see the gators.
&gt;&gt; Yes. Especially on a sunny day.
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; Because they like to come out and soak
up the rays on the bank.
&gt;&gt; Mm-hmm.
&gt;&gt; We’ll probably pass at least 100 on this
short walk, I would say.
We’ll probably pass. I reduced ‘we will’
to this contraction. This contraction can
be pronounced a couple of different ways.
We’ll. Then it sounds like ‘wheel’.
This is the most full and complete pronunciation,
so it’s not the most common. Americans like
to reduce function words like this. It can
also sound like ‘will’. Or, it can sound
like we’ll, a very quick version of this
word, wool. We’ll,
we’ll, we’ll. I said it like ‘will’.
Listen again.
&gt;&gt; We’ll probably pass [3x]
at least 100 on this short walk, I would say.
Did you notice the ‘probably’ reduction
to two syllables? Probly. Try it. Probly. [2x]
Listen again.
&gt;&gt; We’ll probably pass [3x]
at least 100 on this short walk, I would say.
&gt;&gt; I would not be surprised.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Well, let’s keep walking and see
what all we see.
&gt;&gt; Okay.
Keep walkin’. I changed the NG sound to
an N sound. Walkin’ instead of walking.
In general, this reduction is not part of
the standard accent,. It’s a stronger habit
in certain regional dialects, for example
the south, which is where I am in this video,
and where I grew up. Normally I tell my students
not to do it, because if you do it too much,
it does start to sound like a regional dialect
and not the standard accent. Listen again.
&gt;&gt; Well, let’s keep walking and see what
all we see. [3x]
What all. Earlier, we used a Flap T to link
‘what do’, whaduh. Here I used one to
link ‘what’ and ‘all’. When a word
ends in a T (not part of a cluster), and the
next word begins with a vowel or diphthong,
make a Flap T to link the words. Instead of
‘what all’, it becomes ‘wha-dall’.
The tongue just flaps once against the roof
of the mouth, what all, what all, and it connects
those two words. Linking with a Flap T is
a great way to smooth out your speech. Listen
again.
&gt;&gt; Well, let’s keep walking and see what
all we see. [3x]
&gt;&gt; Okay.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. You’re supposed to—I’ve heard different
theories about what you’re supposed to do.
You’re supposed to. What am I saying here?
You are supposed to. You are, contracted,
reduces to you’re, you’re. Very fast.
You’re, you’re. Try it. You’re.
Supposed to. I changed a couple of things
here. I dropped the schwa to squeeze the first
and second syllables together into just one
syllable, supposed to, that begins with the
SP cluster, sp. It’s not uncommon to drop
the T and D sounds when they come between
two other consonant sounds. So I didn’t
say zdt , z-d-t. I dropped the D. Then, because
the next sound is unvoiced, I made the Z unvoiced.
That makes it an S. Supposed to, supposed
to. The final part of the reduction is changing
the ‘oo’ vowel to the schwa in ‘to’.
Very common. It’s okay if you don’t understand
all the reasons why I made every reduction.
Just know that this is a common way to reduce
‘supposed to’. Supposed to. Try it with
me. Supposed to. Listen again.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. You’re supposed to—I’ve heard different
theories about what you’re supposed to do. [3x]
In the next section of conversation, listen
for contractions with ‘they’. How many
are there? Then you’ll see the section again
with the answers on-screen.
&gt;&gt; …If one starts going after you. I’ve
heard, run in a zig-zag, because they’ll
try to follow your zig-zag pattern and they’re
not good at running in zig-zag.
&gt;&gt; I don’t know. That sounds reasonable
to me.
&gt;&gt; But why would they follow your zig-zag
pattern?
&gt;&gt; Because they’re stupid. These are small-brained
animals.
&gt;&gt; So, they’re very similar to snakes, right?
&gt;&gt; I have no idea.
&gt;&gt; Evolutionarily? They’re reptiles?
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. I think they’re pretty primitive.
&gt;&gt; …If one starts going after you. I’ve
heard, run in a zig-zag, because they’ll
try to follow your zig-zag pattern and they’re
not good at running in zig-zag.
&gt;&gt; I don’t know. That sounds reasonable
to me.
&gt;&gt; But why would they follow your zig-zag
pattern?
&gt;&gt; Because they’re stupid. These are small-brained
animals.
&gt;&gt; So, they’re very similar to snakes, right?
&gt;&gt; I have no idea.
&gt;&gt; Evolutionarily? They’re reptiles?
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. I think they’re pretty primitive.
&gt;&gt; What do you see up there, Dad?
Another ‘what do you’ reduction. What
do you see? This time was even more sloppy.
Whuh-du-see, not even a clear ‘you’ reduction.
Listen again.
&gt;&gt; What do you see up there, Dad? [3x]
&gt;&gt; Well, I was hoping to spot cranes
Hopin’ to (duh). My dad also dropped the
G in ING to make –in’ instead. Hoping
to. The word ‘to’ was reduced to the Flap
T and schwa. Here, the tongue is already at
the roof of the mouth for the N. So you don’t
actually have to flap your tongue. Think of
it as a quick D as you release the N. Hopin’
to. Hopin’ to. Listen again.
&gt;&gt; Well,
I was hoping to [3x]
…spot cranes. But I do not see any.
&gt;&gt; Uh-huh.
&gt;&gt; From miles away.
&gt;&gt; Oh yeah?
&gt;&gt; You can hear them before you can see them.
Dad did two ‘them’ reductions, where we
drop the TH and change the vowel to the schwa.
Hear them, see them. Notice notice how ‘them’
links to the word before so it just sounds
like an unstressed syllable on the end of
that word. It doesn’t feel like a separate
word. That’s what you want, words linked
together. Hear them, see them. Try it with
me. Hear them. See them. Listen again.
&gt;&gt; hear them before you can see them. [3x]
&gt;&gt; Oh yeah?
&gt;&gt; They’re really noisy.
&gt;&gt; Hey David?
&gt;&gt; Yeah?
&gt;&gt; What do you think of my home city so far?
Another ‘whaduhyuh’. Not ‘what do you’,
but ‘whaduhyuh’, ‘whaduhyuh’. Much
smoother.
&gt;&gt; What do you think of my [3x]
home city so far?
&gt;&gt; It’s pretty great.
&gt;&gt; I like it!
I hope you enjoyed this real English study.
Look in the description below for links to
related videos, for example, the ‘Dropping
the H’ video. Don’t forget to sign up
for my mailing list here to keep on top of
everything that’s happening at Rachel’s
English.
&gt;&gt; That’s it, and thanks so much for using
Rachel’s English.