In this American English pronunciation video,
you’re going to learn how to pronounce the
word ‘water’.
This video is being made on vacation. So,
the background’s weird, the lighting’s
weird, but we get the benefit of having lots
of other fun people be in this video so that
you can better learn American English pronunciation.
We’re going to learn how to pronounce the
word ‘water’. ‘Water’ is especially
interesting because it’s so different in
American English than it is in British English.
So let’s start. How do we pronounce it?
The lips will round for the W consonant. Wa-.
Then we have a vowel. It’s a lot more open
in American English than it is in British
English. I use the AH as in FATHER vowel,
wa-, ah, where my jaw drops quite a bit. The
back part of the tongue presses down a little
bit. Wa-, ah, wa-. So that’s a very open
sound. Water.
Then we have the letter T. It comes between
two vowels. So, in American English, we’re
going to make that a Flap T. It will sound
like a D. In British English they don’t
do that. They keep a True ‘tt’ sound.
Water, water. This Flap T sound is the R sound
in some other languages like Arabic, Spanish,
Portuguese. But, in American English we call
it a Flap T, and the tongue just bounces up
against the roof of the mouth. Water, -ter,
-ter. So, it’s a quick easy movement and
there’s no stop of air.
Then we have the schwa-R sound. In American
English we maintain a real R sound. In British
English, they don’t when it’s at the end
of a word. Water, -er, -er. It’s a very
closed sound. So to make the sound, the tongue
lifts up and it pulls back a little bit. So,
the middle part of the tongue is touching:
maybe the roof of the mouth, maybe the teeth,
rr, rr, while the front has pulled back and
up a little bit, so it’s not touching anything,
rr. We can hold that sound out. The tongue
shouldn’t be flapping, ruh, ruh. That’s
only for the Flap T. Here it holds in place:
water, rr, rr. You can see the lips will round
a little bit for that final sound as well.
Water.
You don’t need to worry about making a separate
schwa sound. Just go straight from the Flap
into the R. Water, water. Now we’re going
to see a little bit of video of me walking
to the well with my family to fill up our
water bottles, and you’re going to hear
the word ‘water’ lots of times.
&gt;&gt; How, like, old-fashioned are we that we
have to walk to the well to get water?
&gt;&gt; I know.
&gt;&gt; We’ll here we’re just on our way to
the well to get some water!
&gt;&gt; See, in rural Michigan…
&gt;&gt; How’s it taste, David?
&gt;&gt; Oh, the water is really good.
&gt;&gt; Jace, how was the water?
&gt;&gt; Cold and good.
&gt;&gt; How’s the water?
&gt;&gt; ???
&gt;&gt; That water tastes great.
&gt;&gt; Alright, does everyone have all the water
they need?
&gt;&gt; I have my water. Let’s go.
&gt;&gt; Wait! One more.
&gt;&gt; Do you have your water?
&gt;&gt; I got my water.
&gt;&gt; Jace, do you need more water?
&gt;&gt; Karina, can you way ‘water’?
&gt;&gt; Wa-wa.
&gt;&gt; Say ‘water’ for the camera.
&gt;&gt; Say ‘water’.
&gt;&gt; Wa-wa.
&gt;&gt; Water.
I hope this has helped you understand how
to pronounce ‘water’ in American English.
If you’re interested in exploring the differences
between American English and British English,
check out this video I made with Minoo. Don’t
forget to like the video and share it. Put
a comment below if there’s another word
that you would like me to teach you how to
pronounce.
That’s it guys, and thanks so much for using
Rachel’s English.