In this American English pronunciation video,
we're going to go over how to pronounce the
phrase 'good night'.
Hey Friends and Fans! We're going to get to
that video in just a minute. But first, did
you know that right now, I'm on an Epic Road
Trip Across America? Summer of 2014! Look
for a recap video in the fall. In the mean
time, I need your support to ensure that I
can keep making great free videos every week
for you on my Rachel's English channel. If
Rachel's English is important to you, please
click here to find out how you can help keep
it going. :)
&gt;&gt; I'm going to go to bed. Good night everybody!
&gt;&gt; Good night, Rachel!
[yawn!] I'm tired. Good night fans! Let's
listen to a bunch of different people say
that phrase.
&gt;&gt; Good night, Rachel.
&gt;&gt; Good night!
&gt;&gt; Good night Rachel.
&gt;&gt; Good night.
&gt;&gt; Night, Audrey.
&gt;&gt; Good night!
&gt;&gt; Good night Leon!
&gt;&gt; Good night.
&gt;&gt; Good night, Savannah.
&gt;&gt; Night!
&gt;&gt; Good night, Rachel.
&gt;&gt; Good night!
&gt;&gt; Night!
Did you notice how most people reduced the
word 'good' to just the G sound? G'night,
g'night! Let's hear a few people say that.
&gt;&gt; G'night Rachel!
&gt;&gt; G'night!
G'night! How do we say that phrase? Gg, gg.
To make the G sound, the back of the tongue
lifts up and touches the soft palate. To make
the N sound, the front part of the tongue
lifts up to the top of the mouth: g-nnn-a.
Then it comes back down for the AI as in BUY
diphthong. We do need some jaw drop for the
first half of that diphthong. G'ni-. Then,
for the second half, the tongue lifts up towards
the roof of the mouth, the tip stays down
but the front part lifts, and so the jaw is
less lowered. G'night, g'night!
What's happening to the T? That's a Stop T.
That means I'm just stopping the air in my
throat. G'night, g'night! Some part of my
tongue is lifting up to the roof of the mouth.
It might be the front part, like is necessary
for the T position, but it also just might
be something further back. It's a little bit
more lazy. G'night, g'night. So when I'm making
it there, the tongue tip stays down and the
middle part is reaching and touching the roof
of the mouth. But the important part is that
we're stopping the air in the throat. G'night,
g'night. That cuts off the sound, which signifies
the Stop T. G'night.
Some people drop the word 'good' altogether
and just say 'night!'
&gt;&gt; Night!
So, when you're parting ways with a friend
at night, or you're getting ready to go to
bed, this is what you can say. G'night! G'night,
guys!
If there's a phrase you would like to learn
how to pronounce better, please put it in
the comments below.
BONUS!! Did you notice how I used the word
'gonna'? I'm gonna go to bed.
&gt;&gt; I'm gonna go to bed.
Gonna, gonna. This is a great reduction. Americans
use it all the time. It's not slang, it's
not uneducated, it's not lazy. It's just a
very integral part of spoken American English.
So don't be afraid to use it.
I'm gonna go do bed. G'night, guys!
That's it, and thanks so much for using Rachel's
English.