Happy Thanksgiving everybody!
I’m here in Pennsylvania at my
boyfriend’s parents’ house.
And we’re going to celebrate
Thanksgiving tomorrow.
And I know what you’re thinking: “Rachel,
I had no idea you had a boyfriend.”
It’s true, I’ve been
keeping it secret.
But in this video, you’re
going to meet my boyfriend,
and you’re also going to have an
American English pronunciation quiz,
so watch all the way to the
end for the quiz questions.
Ok guys, are you ready?
This is my boyfriend.
His name is David.
Hey guys.
David lives in Philadelphia, which is
about two hours away from New York.
But we’re not in Philadelphia,
we’re at his parents’ house,
which is in a different location
in the state of Pennsylvania.
So, to get ready for Thanksgiving,
we’re making four pies tonight.
So, join in the fun.
Yeah, we should roll out
the crust probably,
but let’s go check the temperature
of the apple pie filling.
So, we made the apple pie filling,
and now it needs to cool
before we put it in the pie.
So we stuck it in the
garage where it’s cooler.
Where’d you put it?
On the floor, I think.
Over in the corner.
What corner?
- Back there.
- Oh wow.
Ooo, this is cold on my feet!
Oh, it’s still steamy.
Alright, well.
Let’s roll out the pie crusts, and maybe
that will have cooled down by then.
Alright.
We’re going to call that good enough.
So, this is an apple, and we decided
that we were going to put it in
the ones with the bigger edge.
Here’s one.
Yeah, the pumpkin can
just go where ever.
How about this? This can go too.
We’re doing so many ‘can’ reductions:
This can go there, that can go there.
Alright, we successfully
rolled out the pie crust,
and now we’re going
to stuff the pies.
That was totally the wrong verb.
We’re going to to fill the pies.
Stuff the turkey!
- That’s right! They’re in there, right?
- Yep.
Here, I’ll move this.
Here’s what the apple
pie filling looks like.
It’s really quite delicious.
What are you working
on there, Annabelle?
I’m making the dressing.
I’ve got the toast all
ready, and cutting it up,
and then I’ll add the
onions, celery, and butter.
And you’re actually making
it tomorrow, right?
I’ll make it tonight and
let the seasoning mellow.
Nice!
Oops.
That’s flour.
In the mean time, our apple pies came out
of the oven, they’re looking pretty good.
They’re from the 70’s.
- 70’s, mom?
- I love ’em [THEM reduction!]
You think they’re from the 70’s, mom?
I think so, yeah.
They’re awesome.
Ok. So the oven’s preheated?
- Yep.
- Alright, let’s do this.
Where’d I put that recipe? Here.
Nnnnnnnno.
Doesn’t matter.
Oh, and it’s only
supposed to be at 350?
So intimidating.
But when it comes out, it’s really worth
it, because it’s Glen’s favorite pie.
Fifteen minutes starts now.
Yep, they’re all out.
And I think they’re going
to be good tomorrow.