I'm here celebrating the 4th of July on my
rooftop. Come watch the fireworks with me.
Happy 4th everyone!
Even the Empire State Building is celebrating!
Fireworks. This is a compound word. That is,
a word made up of two other words. In compound
words, the first word is stressed. So the
stress in this word falls on 'fire', fire.
Fireworks begins with the F consonant sound.
Bottom lip up to touch the bottom of the top
front teeth. Fi-. Then we have the AI as in
BUY diphthong, fi-, fire. Next, the schwa-R
sound. 'Fire' is a one-syllable word. But
the schwa-R ending after the AI diphthong
will sort of make it feel like a two-syllable
word, with an unstressed 'er' ending. Fire,
fire. Fireworks. The lips must come into a
tight circle for the W sound. Fireworks. Then
we have the UR as in HER / R consonant sound,
-wor-, firewor-, fireworks. And finally, the
KS consonant cluster at the end. Fireworks.
&gt;&gt; That's a finale.
That's it, and thanks so much
for using Rachel's English.