In this American English pronunciation video,
you're going to come to a work day at this
beautiful farm. We'll also study pronunciation
of the letter T, using 'kinda', and the reduction
of the words 'because' and 'to'.
In this video, we're going to take a look
at some stop T endings. When a word ends in
a T that's not a part of a consonant cluster,
that T will often be a stop. For example,
the word 'out' will often be 'out', 'out'.
But when that word is followed by another
word that begins with a vowel, it will often
be a flap T because now it comes between two
vowels when linked together. So, for example,
in the phrase 'out of'. That T will go from
being a stop in the word 'out' to being a
flap in the phrase 'out of'. These are general
guidelines. You will hear people clearly pronounce
the full true T at the end of the word 'out'
sometimes. It all depends on the habit of
the speaker, and how clearly the speaker is
enunciating.
&gt;&gt; What is the assignment today?
What is. Flap T. Listen again.
&gt;&gt; What is the assignment today? [3x]
&gt;&gt; Well, you can pull up some landscape fabric,
&gt;&gt; Okay.
&gt;&gt; Or take this, break this down.
&gt;&gt; Uh-huh.
&gt;&gt; Or carry some wood over to the trees.
&gt;&gt; Okay.
&gt;&gt; Or help take this structure down.
&gt;&gt; Okay. Great.
&gt;&gt; Or snip some herbs.
&gt;&gt; Snip some herbs. That sounds like the most
fun out of everything that you just said.
Did you notice how I dropped the T sound in
the phrase 'just said'. Sometimes, we'll drop
the T when it comes between two other consonant
sounds. For example, the word 'exact'. We
will say and ending true T there. But when
we add -ly, it's not uncommon to drop the
T: exactly, exactly, just said. Listen again.
&gt;&gt; Everything that you just said. [3x]
&gt;&gt; Hi Michelle.
&gt;&gt; Hi Rachel.
&gt;&gt; What project are you working on there?
&gt;&gt; I'm tearing this down. I'm destroying it.
&gt;&gt; You're doing a good job.
&gt;&gt; Thanks. Kinda fun. You should join in.
&gt;&gt; I should help, instead of videotape, right?
&gt;&gt; It's ok. We're doing a pretty good job.
Did you notice how Michelle said 'kinda'.
She reduced the word 'of' to just the schwa
vowel and attached it to the word 'kind'.
Kinda, kinda. Listen again.
&gt;&gt; Kinda fun. [3x] You should join in.
For the record, I didn't only make a video.
I did also help.
&gt;&gt; It's stuck!
&gt;&gt; Michelle, let me help you with that.
&gt;&gt; Hey, thanks Rachel.
&gt;&gt; It's a good thing I've been
working out lately.
Working out. Stop T. Working out lately. Listen
again.
&gt;&gt; Working out lately. [3x]
&gt;&gt; Edgar is documenting me documenting.
&gt;&gt; Documenting you documenting me.
&gt;&gt; It's a meta-documentary going on there.
&gt;&gt; Notice how HaQuyen leaves off the T in
'documentary'.
&gt;&gt; Do you know why you're doing that?
&gt;&gt; Why am I doing it? Am I reducing it?
&gt;&gt; Well, it's, T is a weird letter, and sometimes
after N we do drop it. Like, in words like
'center', we'll say 'cenner'. Interview ...
&gt;&gt; 'Innerview'.
&gt;&gt; 'Innerview'. Documentary.
&gt;&gt; 'Documennary'.
&gt;&gt; Exactly.
&gt;&gt; Rachel, why'd you take off your hat and
jacket?
&gt;&gt; Because I got hot.
Did you notice how I reduced the word 'because'
to 'cuz', 'cuz'. Because I got hot. Listen again.
&gt;&gt; Because I got hot. [3x]
Also, did you notice that stop T: hot, hot.
&gt;&gt; Because I got hot. [3x] Do you remember
that awesome video I made on 'hot' back in
the summer?
&gt;&gt; Uh, no, I don't.
&gt;&gt; You actually don't need to respond. I'm
going to put a link to it then.
&gt;&gt; How can I help, Rachel?
&gt;&gt; Well, we're about to need to take all the
plants that have grown on this out.
Did you notice how I said 'about to'. And
I reduced the word 'to' to the true T and
the schwa sound. The reason why I didn't make
it a flap T is because the word before ended
in a T. So in this case, when we reduce the
word 'to', we need to keep the true T. About
to. About to. Listen again.
&gt;&gt; We're about to need to take [3x] all of
the plants that have grown on this out.
&gt;&gt; Edgar, how much time did we save you by
coming to the work day?
&gt;&gt; You saved at least a month.
&gt;&gt; Oh, wow! That's great.
Great. There I released the T, making the
ending T a true T sound. Listen again.
&gt;&gt; That's great. [3x] What are you going to
do with that extra month?
&gt;&gt; Think I'll work some more!
&gt;&gt; Get other stuff done.
&gt;&gt; Thanks for having us out.
Out. There I made the ending T a stop T. Listen
again.
&gt;&gt; Thanks for having us out. [3x]
&gt;&gt; Thank you for coming. You guys were great.
&gt;&gt; Our pleasure.
&gt;&gt; Ready? Okay.
&gt;&gt; That's it, and thanks so much
for using Rachel's English!
&gt;&gt; He was quiet for the whole take, I can
hardly believe it. Thank you.