Speaking face-to-face with customers, your boss, or any
of the other people that you work with can be a little
tricky, especially when you're dealing with problems
or difficult situations.
Your choice of words and the phrases that you use can
affect what customers and your colleagues think of you.
So, if you speak English as a second or a third language,
using the right words in the right way
is really important.
I'm Emma from mmmEnglish
and today I'm going to walk you through five situations
that are super common in just about any workplace,
to help you to avoid the things that you should never say
and
give you some really simple expressions
that will help people to see you
for the helpful professional that you truly are.
So, are you ready to get to work?
Situation number one.
Someone asks you a question
but you don't know the answer.
Excuse me, do you know if the Bluetooth adapter
will work on the Sony A6400?
Ahhh... I don't know.
When someone asks you a question
and you simply don't know the answer,
well never say "I don't know".
Even though this is the truth,
even though, those are the correct English words to say,
you're not being helpful at all!
So, saying "I don't know" in the workplace -
especially to a customer -
sounds really unprofessional in English,
even a little bit rude.
It's like saying you don't care.
So to sound more professional
and to show that you do care, try saying
"I'm not sure, but I can find out".
So, say it with me,
Or you could say "I'll find out for you."
Awesome!
Here's another one:
"Let me come back to you on that"
So, you can use this to say
that you need a little more time to find the answer
but you're assuring the person
that you will try to help them.
Excellent! You're sounding really helpful
and much more professional already!
Speaking of sounding more professional,
if you need to improve your English skills at work
when you're speaking to clients or customers
or colleagues, then listen up,
because the Lingoda Language Marathon is back!
Now this is awesome news for you
if you want to improve your English skills
in just 90 days.
But you've got to be ready to do it quickly because
this Language Marathon is going to be the
last Lingoda Marathon ever!
If you've heard me talk about the Marathon before,
then you'll know that you can complete it
as a full marathon or a half marathon.
The full marathon is one class a day for three months
and the half marathon is fifteen classes a month
for three months.
You can choose to enrol in General English
or Business English specific classes.
All of them are group classes held online
and led by native English teachers.
And the awesome thing is
if you complete your marathon successfully,
Lingoda will refund up to 100% of your class fees,
which is super cool, right?
I'm doing the Spanish Marathon right now with Lingoda
and I can confidently tell you that my speaking skills
have increased dramatically
and it's all because of the marathon.
It's helped to keep me accountable and stay motivated
to make sure that I reach my goal.
Like I said, this is the last Marathon ever
so if you want to take part in it, you need to do it now!
To register and secure your place,
you need to pay a deposit of €49
by the 9th of September.
For all of the details and to register,
use the link you see in the description below and
make sure you add this code at the checkout,
it's going to get you a €10 discount
off your deposit.
Now, it's time to get back to work!
Situation number two.
Someone asks you if you can do something
by a specific time.
So this happens all the time at work, right?
Especially if you work at a place that has deadlines.
Emma, ummm...
Our clients need this done by 2 o'clock tomorrow,
do you think you can manage that?
I'll try to finish it.
So.. Yes?
Can I tell them that we'll have it done by 2?
I'll try my best.
When someone asks you if something can be done
by a certain time,
don't use the phrase "I'll try".
I mean, of course, you'll try
and trying is great!
But in English, if you use the verb 'try',
you're not really committing to anything
You're not saying that you will or you won't
or you can or you can't do something, right?
You're not committing to a deadline at all
so you're not being very helpful
and this is not very professional at all!
The person asking you has asked a specific
yes/no question:
Can you get it done by this time?
So you need to give a really clear-cut answer, okay?
You can sound much more professional
simply by saying:
I can get it done by 2pm.
So, say it with me.
Sure, I can have it done by 2pm.
Great!
But what if you can't get it done by 2pm
or by the end of the day?
What if you can't get it done?
Well, you definitely shouldn't say
that you'll try, seriously.
Saying that you'll try might make them
go away in the short term.
But you're going to let them down in the long run
and that is really unprofessional.
You need to be honest with them
but you also need to make a commitment
to reassure them when you can get it done by.
So, in this situation try an alternative like:
I don't think I can manage it by 2,
but I can have it done by 4.
Actually, I don't think I can manage it by 2
but I can definitely have it done by 4.
I don't think I can manage it by Thursday,
but I can definitely have it done by Friday.
Would that be okay?
Nice work! Let's keep going.
Situation number three.
Uh-oh... Your boss or a customer is angry
or disappointed about something.
Now, it could be something that you did personally,
like, maybe you were late
or perhaps it's not actually your fault
but you still need to deal with this situation.
This is ridiculous! I drove the whole way down here
to pick the thing up. I even rang you this morning
and now you're telling me it's not ready?
Okay...
Okay? That's all you've got... Okay?
Yes.
Alright, so nobody really wants to deal with
angry or frustrated customers, do they?
And if something like that's ever happened to you,
you might even freeze up
and get really awkward.
it's not really a good look, right?
But of course, there's always going to be someone
who's unhappy or frustrated
about something at some point.
It's just part of working life, isn't it?
So, it's a good idea to have a plan so in those situations
you've got something to say to make the situation better
and not worse!
Lucky for you there are two really important words
that will make everything a little better.
I understand.
Simple, huh?
So before you freeze up and just say
"okay" or "yes",
just remember, all you need to say is "I understand"
With these really simple words, for just a moment,
you can make the situation better .
You'll help the other person to see that you're listening
and show them that you care about helping them
and of course, then you need to offer
something to help the situation, right? A solution.
So try these with me.
I understand. Let's see what we can do.
I'm sorry, I understand.
Let's see what we can do about this.
Notice that I used the word 'let's' and 'we' instead of 'I'.
This is a really great way to involve the other person
in the solution.
I understand you've come all this way and it's not ready.
Let's see what we can do.
Awesome!
So you're ready for the next one, right?
Situation number four, numero cuatro.
Well when you're keeping somebody waiting,
what should you do?
Maybe you're busy with another customer,
maybe you're on a phone call
or maybe you really need to go to the toilet
and you've got to leave quickly.
Whatever the case,
the worst thing that you could possibly say is:
Things are just really busy today
so it's taking a bit longer than usual.
Yeah, yeah we've just had loads of new clients come in.
Hang on a sec!
No no no no no no no. This is not good, okay?
You know this situation right? It's just rude.
But fortunately there are a couple of phrases
that you can memorise that will have you sounding
really professional and keep the person
who's waiting happy.
So the first one is:
I'll be with you in a moment.
And this expression just lets them know that you know
that they're there and that you won't be long
until you give them your full attention. So say it with me.
Brilliant! Alright and the second one is:
Sorry to keep you waiting, I'll be right there.
You try it.
Sorry to keep you waiting,
I'll be there with you in just a minute.
Can you think of any other ways to respond
in this type of situation?
If you can, add them to the comments below.
Situation number five.
So when somebody asks you a question
but you didn't quite hear them
or maybe you didn't understand them.
What should you do?
Hey Emma, do you reckon you can let the guys go early
this afternoon? I'm gonna nick off too.
What?
Never say "what". Ever.
Okay? This is one that the parents and teachers
of English speaking children are always
trying to teach them
and it's a really big no-no in the workplace.
You can sound much more professional by saying:
I'm sorry, I missed that.
You try it.
I'm sorry, I missed that. Could you say it again, please?
Awesome! So now try:
Sorry, would you mind just repeating that?
Sorry, would you mind just repeating that for me?
I missed it.
Now there are lots of different ways to let
someone know that you didn't understand them, right?
And politely ask them
to repeat themselves a little more clearly.
Can you think of any other ways that you could
say the same thing?
If you can, add them into the comments.
So I hope this lesson has given you some options
to help you sound a little more professional at work.
If you want to keep working on your professional
English, I've got a couple of other lessons right here
that are perfect for you.
And I make new videos here every week
on the mmmEnglish Channel. So make sure you
hit the subscribe button just down there
so that you don't miss out on any of them.
And thank you very much for joining me
and I look forward to seeing you in the next lesson!