Hey there I'm Emma from mmmEnglish.
Have youever been in a situation where you've met
someone for the very first time but you saidsomething that
must have been inappropriate.
You felt that tension, that awkwardness.
I mean whenyou meet someone new, you really don't
have a lot of time to make a good first impression, do you?
So today I'm gonna highlight six things that you just
should never say in a first time conversation
and we're going to look at some alternatives to make sure that you
do look good
and makea first good impression in that conversation.
Remember to like this video, give ita thumbs up, hit that subscribe
button, that way I know exactly what videos youlove
and I can keep making more for you.
In this video today, we're going to betalking about relaxed
friendly conversations, ones that take place every day
at work, at school, at universities
but these are also the places where we feel most intimidated
and nervousbecause we may be trying to impress someone
or you know, perhaps it's a more formal context.
So as I'm sharing these different expressions
throughout the video, pay close attention tothe tone,
the intonation and the way that I'm expressing these thoughts.
It's so important, youcould say the exact words
that I'm telling you to say but if your delivery is a little off
well thenit can easily get misinterpreted or misunderstood.
Make sure you try and repeat each sentenceafter me,
try to imitate the way that I say it.
Ask yourself: Where's the word stress here or
amI using a soft tone or am I being really direct?
I'll explain more about it as we gobut let's get started.
Our first one is
when someone asks you if you like your job
or youenjoy what you do.
So in that situation, do not say:
My work is so boring.
I can't stand the people Iwork with.
When you first meet someone, avoid being negative
about your place of work. Don't complainabout your job,
your boss or your colleagues, even if really you don't like it.
I know youmight be thinking:
Emma, I'm just being honest.
But complaining like that really only reflects poorlyon you
and studies show that you know if you say something negative,
the person that you're havinga conversation with will associate
that negativity with you
and not the actual situation that you'retalking about
and you don't want that when you first meet them, right?
So instead, you could startby saying something positive like:
There are some aspects of my job that I really enjoy
butI have to admit, I'm finding it difficult to
work with a colleague,
get along with my boss,
feel excited about the work that I'm doing.
These are much better alternatives.
Number two.
How much money do you make?
And how much rent do you pay?
Do you know what, insome cultures,
this question is totally okay to ask
but for people who come from places like theUS, the UK
and here in Australia, it's not okay.
People would be quite taken aback if youask that question
especially if you've only just met them.
It could make them feel quiteuncomfortable and there really isn't
a way to tactfully ask this question. It's actuallybetter to just
avoid it completely.
However
if you do really need to know this information
for some specific reason then make it an indirect question
to make it more polite.
If you don'tmind me asking, how much do you pay for rent?
Number three.
You're nicer than I thought you'd be.
If you've heard about someone before you metthem
or maybe you've seen them somewhere before
well you might think that that's a really
great way to start a conversation,
thatit's a way of paying a compliment.
And let me tell you why.
Because it impliesor suggests that you thought the person
was mean before or the opposite ofwhatever you said
so if you said:
You're so much prettier than I thought you'd be.
It kind of suggests that you thought they were ugly,
it's not a good way to start a conversation.
If youwant to pay someone a compliment then just
keep it simple and say it straight.
You're a lovely person.
You're so kind.
That way there's no confusion.
All right. Number four.
Sarah is really lazy.
Imean this applies to any negative comment about
a colleague or a friend or a classmate.
When you meetsomeone for the first time, you might point out
friends or colleagues, other people in the office
and share some information about these people.
But like I mentioned before, when you are gonna say
something negative about someone,
that negativity just reflects on you
right? Even if you're talkingabout someone else
it just makes you sound
not very nice yourself.
So instead of saying that Sarahis lazy, you could say:
We're all quite hard workers
some work a bit harder than others.
Notice I'm not saying any specific names?
Okay next one.
You look so tired!
You look so fattoday!
Now in some countries implying someone is fat is okay
because it signifies wealth
but inother countries including most English-speaking countries,
it's really inappropriate to highlightsomeone's appearance
in a negative way.
There's no
say this instead here right?
If you noticethat someone has put on a little bit of weight
don't mention it at all.
If you thinksomeone's pregnant, don't say anything.
It's just safer to wait and avoid hurtingtheir feelings
especially if you're wrong.
This reminds me of a time when I felt a littleembarrassed
and awkward in a conversation that I was having with someone
because I askedan older woman if she had any children.
She said no
but left the answer hanging there andI instantly felt
bad and uncomfortable because
you just don't know when you ask this question.
Had she tried to have children and she couldn't?
Maybe she wanted to but she never found theright person.
You know or something else.
And after the awkward silence, she said:
I know whatyou're thinking. Everyone always thinks that
but I'm really happy. I chose not to havechildren.
I really love my life.
That's also
another example of a type of question thatmaybe
is not always appropriate to ask when you first meet someone.
You just don't knoweveryone's stories, the background, right?
Whether or not you are upsetting them
or making them feel uncomfortable.
In that case, fortunately it was just mefeeling uncomfortable
and I learnt a lesson.
Okay so if you do meet someone for the first time
and they look tired and you want to comment on it
well you could first start by making a commentabout yourself
and say:
I really struggled to sleep last night.. how did you sleep?
So this ismore indirect and they'll be inclined to open up a little
rather than getting defensive.
So ifyou're sharing that you didn't get a lot of sleep
you might then allow them to say:
Oh gosh I haven't slept for days!
And it's probably then that you could say:
Yeah, you looka little tired, you look exhausted.
How old are you?
Now in some cultures, thisquestion is actually really important
so that you know how to address the person thatyou're talking to.
You need to use a certain
pronoun to show respect but this is not the casein English.
Our pronouns are more neutral so the question about age is
really uncommon. In fact, it'sunnecessary
which is why it can make people feel a little uncomfortable
especially if you ask itduring your very first
conversation with someone
because there's no benefitto you knowing it apart from
potentially judging them in some way.
It's justanother question that you should probably avoid
but if you do have to ask and not in the firstconversation
but maybe in a later conversation then again,
try making it an indirect question.
If you don't mind me asking, how old are you?
It's much more polite and it gives them thespace to choose
not to say anything.
So I hope you enjoyed this lesson and that it helped you tolearn
a few new ways to express yourself during your first meetings
and first encounters with newpeople that you meet.
And look, if you have done some of these things before
don't worry about itat all, we all have.
It's not the end of the world.
And if you're ready to keep your conversationpractice going
then make sure you join me right here in this next lesson
and if you like thisvideo,
give it a like, hit the subscribe button, turn on notifications
so that you know when my nextlesson is ready for you.
I'll see you in there!