Well hey there I'm Emma from mmmEnglish.
If thereis a place where English idioms are used
most frequently
it's at work.
Learningand using these idioms in the workplace
with your colleagues, with your clients and yourmanagers
is an essential communication skill.
You need to understand the people that you workwith
and you want to develop a broader range of expressing
your ideas in English, don't you?
You want to sound intelligent and professional
and sometimes you want to sound funny.
Learningthe business English idioms in today's lesson
is definitely going to helpyou to do that.
Are you ready?
Let's start at the very moment that you get yourjob or even
just before it because there are a couple of really fantastic
idioms that you canuse to talk about this moment.
The first is to get your foot in the door.
And this means to enter anorganisation or an industry
for the first time.
We use it to talk about starting out at a lower level
or maybe a less desirable position within the organisation
but there's a chance or an intention
of moving up and becoming more senior or becoming
more successful.
So it talks about an opportunityto get started at a company,
a company that you want to advance or progress within.
An internshipis a great way to get your foot in the door,
to get your foot in the door
of a company that you reallywant to work for.
Volunteering in your industry
will probably help you to get your foot in thedoor,
you'll get to meet some people who work in your field,
you'll get some relevant experience.
Soall of this is super helpful.
Now once you've got your foot in the door and you're starting
yournew job, there's always a period of time,
maybe a week, two weeks, a month
where you've got toget used to things.
You need to learn all the administrative processes.
You've got to meet theteam,
you've got to take over some new
projects and things that you're working on.
Hopefully,there'll be someone there to show you the ropes.
To show someone the ropes means
to show them howto do a job or an activity.
I've never worked in customer service before
but Kate showed me theropes.
Unfortunately not everyone is so lucky when they start their job.
Sometimes you just getthrown in the deep end
which means you get put into a situation without a lot of
preparationor much introduction.
You've kind of got to just work it out for yourself.
I was thrown in the deepend with my first teaching job.
I had a class of fifty children with no experience or mentor
to guideme. I'd never taught kids before.
It was stressful. I had to learn really quickly.
Have you ever beenthrown in the deep end
when you started a new job?
It's nasty.
Let me know about it down in thecomments.
See if you can use that idiom yourself.
So yeah,
that first teaching job was a steeplearning curve for me.
Have you heard about this noun before?
A learning curve.
It's often used withthe adjective steep, a steep learning curve.
So we use learning curve to talk about new skills
thatwe're acquiring at a job and that learning curve describes
the rate at which someone progresses andthey're learning
this new skill.
A steep learning curve is when you have to learn something
veryquickly in a short space of time
and this can be really challenging
like walking up a steephill
compared to walking up a nice gradual hill.
If you're starting a job with no prior experience,
it can be a really steep learning curve.
Or if you don't have anyone showing you the ropes,
the firstfew weeks are going to be difficult,
it's going to be quite stressful. It can be a steep learningcurve.
Finding someone genuine and reliable to
practise speaking English with regularly is reallyhard.
If you don't want to pay someone by the hour
and you don't have time to wade through randomstrangers
on the internet, then come and check out Hey Lady!
Hey Lady! is an online community createdjust for women.
It's a safe and supportive space where you can meet friendly
speaking partners easily and practise having real conversations
about interesting topics in English.
As long asyour English level is intermediate or above
then your English is good enough to join the community.
We offer a ten day free trial so that you can experience it
for yourself and see what you think.
The link is down in the description below so that you can
start your free trial today.
Let's focuson some idioms now that are useful to describe
the different ways of working.
If you do somethingby the book,
it means that you do something exactly as it should be done.
You follow the rules,the laws or the steps,
the procedure that you have been told to follow.
So you do everything correctly.It's by the book.
On the other hand, if you cut corners that means
you complete the task in theeasiest, the quickest
and maybe the cheapest way possible. It means that
maybe you haven't done thejob as
thoroughly as you should have done it and therefore
the end result is maybe not as good as it could have been.
Now look, the company will be audited next month
so I don't want anyone cuttingcorners.
We need everything done by the book!
Sometimes the work that you haveto do is
difficult or it's complex.
And sometimes you have a lot of work to do
and not alot of time to do it in, right?
The idiom to have your work cut out for you describes
exactly thissituation.
Geez,
you'll have your work cut out for you finishing those
reports by Friday.
It's goingto be hard work to get everything done by Friday.
There's a lot to do and not a lot of time
but thensometimes you think that a job is going to be hard
or it's going to take a lot of time but
you'resurprised when you get something done
quickly and easily.
So in this situation, we use
make light workor short work of something.
He made light work of writing the reports.
He wrote them quickly and itwas easy to do.
Now you can actually use this idiom
outside of a work context too.
Let's say I made a delicious cake
and when I came back an hour later it was all gone.
You certainlymade short work of that cake.
It's gone, it was eaten very quickly. It was finished very quickly.
Communication is an essential part of our work lives, right?
Without effective communication,
mostof our plans or our projects and our relationships,
they would completely fail.
So whether you work foryourself and most of the time you're
communicating with your own clients or maybe you work as
partof a team and you communicate with your colleagues
then there are definitely some awesome idioms tohelp you
communicate in English.
We use the idiom to touch base with somebody
in a similar wayas we use the phrasal verb check in.
So when you touch base with someone you talk to them
quicklyand you find out how they're doing
or what they think about something
or about a project thatthey've been working on.
Can we touch base next week sometime to discuss the budget?
Okay butwhat about when you're rushed, you're in a hurry,
you've got a lot of work to do and you just needto be quite direct
in this conversation, we need to
just talk about the things that are reallyimportant.
You want to cut to the chase.
This is the perfect idiom for that situation.
It means youwant to talk about the important things
straight away without wasting any time.
I haven't got muchtime so let's just cut to the chase.
How much is this gonna cost?
Just be a little careful with thisone.
Using this idiom in the wrong way
can come off a little rude at times.
You know if you're just
in a hurry and the other person is talking about something
totally unrelated or maybe you're not
particularly interested in it and you're thinking
please hurry up, come on.
Then that's not theright time to use this idiom,
to cut to the chase.
It's more something that you say when you want to
bypass or skip
the usual small talk and chit-chat and just
get to the important stuff.
We all knowwhy we're here so let's just cut to the chase.
All right, managing the differentrelationships that you have at
work, maybe with colleagues and clients and differentpeople
that you encounter at work. This is really important
and it means sometimes you've gotto
hold back
and not say what you really think, you have to bite your tongue.
I wantedto tell him that his idea was ridiculous
but I bit my tongue.
Sometimes it's just notappropriate
to say what you really think at work, is it?
And that's exactly the situation where you might need to
bite your tongue.
Zip it. Don't say anything.
You know bite that tongue.
Now unfortunately and I think we've all probably experienced it,
problems can come up at work
sohaving a few creative ways to talk about things that are
bothering you or frustrating youcan really help to
lighten the mood a little. So this one
to rock the boat,
it describeswhen you do or you say something that
upsets people or it causes problems.
Let's say youwant to talk to your boss about your new manager
who actually has been spending a lot of time
outside of the office lately and then you think
she's been so stressedlately since Jessica resigned.
I don't want to rock the boat.
Maybe I'll just waittill next month to mention this.
I don't want to change or disrupt or affect
the current situationmyself so I'm not gonna do anything.
Sometimes you have to deal with problems that are caused
byother people.
Maybe they're new and
they made a mistake or they did something by accident
or maybeyou work with a really lazy, careless colleague
and they just don't really care much about theirjob.
But when it's you spending all of your time
trying to solve these problems that other peoplehave created,
little annoying things that are stopping you from doing
your work, well,
then we canuse this idiom to talk about that,
to put out fires.
Well we launched the product update successfully
but then no one could log into the platform.
I spent the day responding to complaints andputting out fires.
So I mean I spent the day
fixing the problems that were createdby the platform update.
It was stressful, people were annoyed, it meant that I didn'tget
any of the work that I was supposed to do done.
I just spent my day putting out fires.
Haveyou ever heard anyone say they're in hot water?
Well this means they're in trouble,
they couldbe in trouble with someone.
They're probably in a difficult situation because of something
that theydid or didn't do and now they're at risk of being
criticised or embarrassed or punished.
TheCEO's in a bit of hot water about those comments
that she made over the competitors.
Okay yourwork is done.
The day is over, it's time to go home.
Then you can call it a day.
I'm exhausted. Let'scall it a day.
Okay, I think it's time to call it a day.
We'll finish the rest tomorrow.
So thereyou have it, my friends!
You just learned fifteen useful business idioms,
all of them are essential tolearn and to use at work.
The best way to do that, to learn and to use English idioms
fluentlyis to think about when and how they might apply to you
and to your work life.
So for homework,I want you to choose five of the idioms
that you learned in this lesson and tell me about
yourworkplace and how these idioms relate to you
down in the comments below.
I'll make sure I get downthere and I'll check them for you
just to make sure that you're using these idioms in the
rightcontext and in the right way.
Thank you so much for joining me today,
I will see you in this nextlesson right here.
I think you're gonna love it!