1. Friends
Tapescript one
Interview with Jade Jagger
Could you tell us a little bit about yourself
Sure
First of all, Where were you born?
I was born in London, but I've got dual nationality because my mother's from Nicaragua.
Do you still live in London?
No,I'm living in Ibiza now.
Oh, really? How long have you been there.
Not long. I moved from London with my two daughters, Assisi and Amba, about 6 months ago.
Are you happy there?
Yeah, very happy.
We love the outdoor life.
Also, my mother is a Spanish speaker and I feel more comfortable in a Latin country.
Have you made any new friends
Yeah, I've made lots of new friends here. A few English,
but my two best friends are Argentinian and Spanish.
What do you do for a living?
I'm a painter,
but I've recently started a jewelry business with a friend,
and that takes up most of my time.
I also do some modeling when I need the cash!
And what do you do in your free time?
Well, with a business and two young children I don't have much free time,
but I love reading and listening to music.
What sort of music do you like?
All sorts: pop music and classical.
Do you ever listen to the Rolling Stones.
No, never, but don't tell my father.
How often do you see your parents?
Not very often.
My mother's in New York and and my father's often on tour.
But we all love big family get-togethers.
You're obviously travelled a lot. What's your favorite place in the world?
That's a difficult question because I've been to so many amazing places,
but I think Brazil is my favorite.
The children love it there too.
Finally, Can I ask one last question -
who chose your name
I think my father chose it.
My mother wanted me to have a Spanish name.