Typescript 3
No doubt my friend last night actually she's my best friend
Have you ever met her I don't know Lisa
You told me about her
I did choose the Greek girl
She's got long dark hair and she's some petite
Yeah weed a great time
We met gosh we known each other now
About 15 years can you believe that
We met I was working for her dad he had a casino
Play those right those were wild days but we networking there together and dumb
Jesus sister a younger sister
I shouldn't get along with her very well so I always like to say that
I'm like her sister
I like the sister she never had
We don't have a lot in common but she doesn't work she's a full-time mom
She got a little boy
He's about always about 11 now
Difficult age but we still get together
About
Once or twice a month and it's always good to see her
Yeah