Dating
Typescript 9
Tom and Kathy
Kathy we last heard from you when you are about to meet Tom for the first time that's right it was
Easier for me to take time off work so I booked a flight to Denver that's a long way to go for a date
I'd rather expensive to we share the cost of the flight Tom's a very generous man
Anybody he arranged to meet me at the airport and when was that
It was almost a year ago
I felt really nervous but I couldn't wait to meet Tom
Oh yes
I spotted him immediately
He look just like his photograph was it love at first sight
I'm afraid not.
I couldn't have predicted what happened but something put me off in straightaway
I didn't even leave the airport
I just turned round and came straight back to Ireland
We haven't been in touch since that day
What was it that put you off
It's going to sound really stupid
But I hated it shoes