Typescript 9
Lisa and Joel
Are you still married yes very much so
We've been married for years now
In fact we've just celebrated our first wedding anniversary congratulations
How have your life changed
Since your unusual marriage well my mother hasn't spoken to me since the day we got married
That's the good news about it
But we've moved away from my hometown really
Why did you decide to do that
Well everybody knew about the competition in the wedding and we
Tending to tourist attractions
We couldn't walk down the street with that
Strangers coming out to us
Asking is oldest personal questions
So where do you live now
In Adelaide
We've been there for about 6 months now and we love it