Typescript 13
Interview with Jane couch
Now this is a question that everyone else
Get interested in.
I saw a documentary about women boxing in America about
6 years ago
I was I
Just a little television program is about an hour long
I want to program and it just changed my life I was just fascinated from the running
From Latin off enalapril, just one
I'm going to do that
I'm will you interested in sports
I wasn't even
Veteran Affairs
Small
I used to drink
Just don't look after myself Albany very well
This just changed
How long did it take you to get fit
It told me
Arthritis
Feel like a lot of male took me
About two years to reach
Teresa level I need you to be
Cantina how many female boxers that are in
The in Britain
In the UK
Is this about 300 women boxing is amateurs
Invisible
8 Women boxing
Professionally in the UK at the moment
Throughout the world is about 30,000 women
LOL
I want to your critics say
It was difficult it was that women should have auction off
Show between the show with the relationship alarm working after the kids and everything
Portland and she's never be as good as the man but my last freeflys has been live on TV after sign
545 Dellwood Bravo television
What do you think of the Prime
Skills to have as a boxer
Believe it or not you've got speakers survival breakup Brad speaker box where anyone can find
What's it make it to the top of Senoia scales and
You still have a pretty cute bread
And the fitness to fit inside of it's very very important
And how do you relax
Adult adult sleep mode Treasures
I want to stay with you without box in a while until I get to sleep is about me fighting just
I would really awesome just constantly working well
How do you prepare for a match
410 round
Obviously it goes training camp just outside Bristol freightways
Before each fight
Alarm
1 seconds chatting composite I don't do anything
Very good train a cockatiel
Have you ever been seriously hurt
In a match
Really seriously not lasting damage things that take a couple of weeks to mend a broken cheekbone
Crocodiles lost
She safe
Just
Your teeth look great with me for where I'm sitting
Do you think you've changed
Since your success
Change. The person
I think
I think I've changed as in
In the lifestyle I Live Now a son
It's just constantly I'm traveling to live opposuit kasbah think
As a person definitely not have to eat my feet itch
So
Firmly on the ground you won't believe that I would believe it
Big fight is going to be the end of February picking in the Macho going to be
Tell me well
Travolta
I'm where would it be
That's great thank you