Typescript 20
Second memory
The Great Mouse plot
My second and only other memory of slammed at Cathedral School is extremely bizarre
It happened a little over a year later
But I was just 9
By then I'd make some friends
But I walk to school in the mornings I would start out to loan
Ford pickup for other boys in my own age along the way
Office
Same for boys and I would set out together across the Village Green and through the village itself
Heading for home
On the way school and on the way back we always passed the Sweet Shop
No
We didn't we never posted
We always stopped
The sweet shop in 1923 was the very center of our lives
To us it was Walt
Is to a drunk
Or churches to a bishop
Without it they would have been little to live for
But he had one terrible drawback the Sweet Shop
The woman who owned it was a hora
We hated her
We had good reason for doing so