Typescript 21
A name
Was mrs. Pratchett
He was a small skinny old hag with a mustache on upper lip
And I'm not force our is a green gooseberry
She never smiled
April is grey and greasy
Eyebrows had bits of breakfast all over it
Toast crumpets and tea stains and splotches of dried egg yolk
It was her hands however the disturbance most
They were disgusting
They were black with dirt and grime
Do not forget that it was these hands and fingers that she would plunge into the sweet Jaws when we are strapped
Pennywise of treacle toffee wine gums or nut clusters or whatever
They were precious few health lower than those days I nobody
Least of all mrs. Pratchett
Ever thought of using a little shovel the getting sweets out as they do today
The other thing we hated mrs. Pratchett for
What time meanness
Unless you spend a whole Sixpence all-in-one go
She wouldn't get you a bag
Instead you got your sweets twisted up in a small piece of newspaper
Wichita waffle potable daily mirror's lying on the counter
So you can well understand that we had it in for mrs. Pratchett in a big way
But we didn't quite know what to do about it
Many schemes were put forward but none of them has any good
None of them that is
Until suddenly one memorable afternoon
We found the Deadmau5
My friends and I have come across a loose floorboard at the back of the classroom
And when we prize to help with the blade of a pocket knife
We discovered a big hollow space underneath
This we decided would be all secret hiding place for sweets another small Treasures such as conquerors and monkey
Knudsen Birds eggs
Every afternoon
When the last lesson was over
The five of us would wait until the classroom it emptied
Then we would lift up the floorboard and examine our secret hoard
Adding to it or taking something away
One day when we lifted up
We found a dead mouse lying among all Treasures
Exciting discovery
Plates to get out by its tail and waved it in front of our faces
What should we do with it he cried
It stinks someone sharted
Window
Hold on a tick I said
Don't throw it away
Thwaites hasn't dated
They all looked at me
When writing about oneself
One must strive to be truthful
Truth is more important than Mother's Day
I must tell you that
But it was I and I alone who had the idea for the Great and the daring Mouse plot
We all have our moments of Brilliance and Glory
And this was mine
Why don't we I said
Slip it into one of Mrs pratchett's jars of sweets
Then when she puts a dirty hand in to grab a handful she grab a stinky dead mouse instead
The other four standard mean one.
Then as the sheer Genius of a plot began to sink in
They all started grinning
They slapped me on the back they cheered me and danced around the classroom will do it today they cried
We do it on the way home
You have the idea they said to me
So you can be the one to put the mouse in the jar
Thwaites handed me the mouse
I put it into my travel pocket
The five of us left the school
Cross the Village Green
And headed for the sweet shop
Webull tremendously jazzed-up
We felt like a gang of desperadoes setting out to rob a train or blow up the Sheriff's Office
We will go pick those now
Mrs. Pratchett victim
She stood behind the counter
I have small malignant Pig eyes watched as suspiciously as we came forward
1 Chabot soccer please
Flight said to her holding out his penny
I kept to the rear of the group
And when I saw mrs. Pratchett Turner had to wait for a couple of seconds to fish of its sucker out of the box
I lifted the heavy glass lid of a Gobstopper jar
Drop them off scene
Ben I replaced the lid asylumtale possible
My heart was thumping like mad
And my hands are cold sweaty
As soon as we were outside we broke into a rotten did you do it they shouted at me of course I did I say
Well done you they cried what a Super Show
I felt like a hero
I wasn't gyro
It was marvelous to be so popular
The flash of triumph over the Deadmau5 with carry forward to the next morning as we met again to walk to school
Let's go in and see if it's still in the job somebody said as we approached the Sweet Shop
Tote
Whiteside family
It's too dangerous
Who passed as though nothing has happened
Has became level with a shop
We swore cardboard notice hanging on the door
Closed
We stopped instead
Never known the Sweet Shop to be closed at this time in the morning
Even on Sundays
What's happened we lost each other what's going on
We pressed all faces against the window
And look inside
Mrs. Pratchett was nowhere to be seen
Look I cried
Gobstopper jarkon it's not on the Shelf
Is a gap what it used to be
It's on the floor someone said
It smashed to bits and cops everywhere
Bears
Someone else Shahid
We could see it all
The huge glass jar smash to Smithereens with a dead mouse lying in the wreckage and hundreds of men
Gobstoppers littering the floor
She got such a shock when she grabbed hold of a mouse but you dropped everything
Somebody was saying
Why didn't she sweep it all up and open the shop I asked
Nobody answered me
Oscar Wilde
Quates brokensilenze
She must have got one heck of a shock he said
Opposed
We all looked at him
Wondering what wisdom the great medical Authority was going to come out with next
Well now
Fights went on
When an old person like mrs. Pantry suddenly gets a very big shock
I suppose you know what happens next
What we said what happens
You off my father plate said
He'll tell you
You tell us we said
It gives her heart attack
Waiting on
A heart stopped beating and she's dead in 5 seconds
Pramono to my old heart stop beating
White spongy the finger at me and said.
I'm afraid you've killed her
Me I cried
Why just me
It was your idea he said
And what's more you put a myosin
I want to something
I was a murderer
Exactly that point we had the school bell ringing in the distance and we have to gallop the rest of the way so it's not.
Late for prayers
The Headmaster is the only teacher at Randolph Cathedral School that I can remember
And for a reason you will soon discover
I can remember him very clearly indeed
His name
With mr. Coons
Mrcool not proceeded to mumble through the same old prayers we had everyday
But this morning when the lost our men have been spoken he did not turn to lead his group rapidly alcoholism
He remains standing before us
And it was clear
He had an announcement to make
The whole school is developing line up around the playground immediately he said
Little book behind and no talking
Mrcool a looking grim
Is Jaime pink face have taken on that dangerous skull which only appeared when he was extremely cross and
Somebody was the high jump
I sent the small and frightened among the rows and rows of other boys
The Headmaster with his black gown draped over his shoulders
Would like a judge at a murder trial
Michaela
Thwaites whisper to me
I began to shiver
As we made our way out into the playground
My whole stomach began to feel as though it was slowly filling up with swirling water
I am only 8 years old I told myself
No little boy at 8 is that a mud at anyone
It's not possible
I have expected to see two policemen come bounding out of the school to grab me by the arms and put handcuffs on my wrist
A single door let out from the school Under the playground
Suddenly it swung open and threw it by the angel of death Strode mr. Coombs hugin Falcon his
Tweed suit and black down
And beside him believe it or not right beside him
Coffee the tiny finger of mrs. Pratchett herself
Mrs. Pratchett
What does live
The relief was tremendous
She let out a high-pitched yell
Dirty finger straighten Thwaites
She yelled
The entire School turn to look at weights
Mr. Coombs
Shut up
Mrcool said
Misses franchise flipped over and settled in my own face
I look down
And study the black asphalt surface of the playground
Here's another of them yelling
She pointed at me now
You're quite sure
Mr. Cooper said
Of course I'm sure she cried
I never forget a face
Restore what does sly as that
He's one of them all right
Altogether
Now where's their mother free
The other three I knew very well
What coming up next
She cried out starting the air with a finger
Game
Packs of five of them all right
We don't need to look no further
Oh yeah and nasty pigs
Yoga pants
I got that name mrs. Pratchett
Mrcool was Toda
I'm very much obliged to you