News
Typescript 22
Are the news headlines
Severe droughts in Africa the president of the USA has announced that he is going to send food and Provisions
To the people of Somalia
Who have lost their homes and livelihood
Robert Holmes Minister for the environment has resigned
The Prime Minister has ordered an investigation into the mysterious disappearance of a large sum of money
A spokesman for the minister told us that he was out of the country and not available for comment
Schoolgirl pulling Gates has not been allowed back into school after the summer holidays
Because she has had her nose pierced
According to headmistress Jean Bradley
Pulling you the pissing was against the school rules
The girl will be allowed back into school
When she removes the offending ring
And finally to end on a happier note
Wedding Bells Are Ringing for 81 year-old Max Williams
Who won 16 million pounds in the lottery last month
He's going to marry 22 year old dancer Sally Lister
The happy couple posed for photographers outside the minion as luxury home in Essex
And Sally held out her hand
To show off a 10,000-pound engagement ring for the cameras