Typescript 29
Hello
Hi Becky it's Sunday
Hiya picky are you thinking tonight
Yes I'm meeting Alex and Susan about half-an-hour where you going
Cinema
Would you like to come with us give up love to where you meeting
At that house but we could meet you in front of the cinema on George Street at 8:30 okay thanks
See later
I'm going to the cinema with Becky
Good idea and next time I see David I'm going to tell him to get lost I believe that
That when I see it
Hello
Send it please
Yeah hold on a moment I'll get her for you
David
I'm really sorry I didn't call earlier but I had to work late and that's alright
I forgot you were going to bring anyway I'm having dinner with my parents
I'm going to the cinema or anyway right
Okay well I'll call you
When
I mean alright bye
You didn't tell him to get lost
He apologized and he's having dinner with his parents
Anyway I must go
Eliza
Hi Alex hi Becky with Susie
Mind at the last minute David founder and asked her to go for the meet at that new Japanese restaurant what
Now I'm definitely going to tell him to get lost