Typescript
Sissy
What do you think
A good party
Places really important
It should be big enough
But not too big
Yes
He needs to be quite crowded to make an atmosphere
Oh I don't like it when you can't see who you're talkin
I mean soft lighting
I like it when there are some decorations to you know a few balloons and things just to make it special like a children's
Cool candles and things on the wall
What time does make a nice atmosphere but you have to be careful the house doesn't catch fire
What will you come get those candle holders
The most important
Thing is the food in
Oh yes
Lots of drink and dinner food
There's enough food source of food you think is good for
You can eat with your fingers I mean you don't want a place of washing up at the end of the policy
The most
Loud but not too loud
Anderson music you can dance to
The best thing is to prepare party type
With all the best dance tracks
Then you don't have to worry about it
But what about people that's quite important
I mean the right
I need some party animal to get upset with don't think you need a mix of men and women
I went to a party recently where they were five women for every man
Sounds right to me
What to think of a three most important things and think
Music
On the right mixer
Right