Soap
Typescript 34
Pacific Heights scene 1
Pakwan
Hi Grandma
Hello dear
How's it going
Don't ask
Are you still thinking about Katie
Yes I can't get her off my mind I don't know what to do
I thought you got over her I had
Until I saw her again
When she told me she'd broken up with John all the old feelings came back
The Daniels
What about Ernie can the wedding I know I thought I loved any
When I asked her to marry me I meant it but
Now I
Not sure how I feel
Look why don't you go away for a few days and think about it
How about going to stay with Dave and Claire
They love to see you
But I thought Dave was in Mexico
Oh yeah she is isn't he
Are you could talk it through with her
Yes
That's not a bad idea
I'll go and see her tomorrow