Typescript 34
Thoughtful
Oh dear
What's going on here
Nothing
Everything's fine
Juice deer
Please
We've had a terrible day
We've been shopping to get Lua Bridesmaids
Stressthem
She says she won't wear a dress I hate dresses
Because you're a bridesmaid and bridesmaids don't wear suits
It's only for one day
What is Jumanji on Business Loop
I think you better apologize young lady
Calm down
Remember what the doctor told you it doesn't look as if there's going to be anyway I just seen
How does arm around her
Wait till I get my hands on that boy next he's not a boy
He's a man
It's his life
Leave him alone leave him alone
I don't leave them alone every messages up for me
I'll never speak to him again
Annex father is about to sign the biggest contract we've ever had
And you tell me to leave him alone max weight