Tates Creek 35
Pacific Heights seeing 3
I think I know where Charlie is
Where
He's going to see Claire
I'm sure there's something going on
Between Charlie and Claire
Claire is married to Uncle Dave
So let's a married people have affairs
Well
I don't think it's right
Anyway how do you know
I heard him talking to her on the phone yesterday
The actor of David left for America and then he said he couldn't wait to be in your arms again
What a creep
Poor Becky
Don't worry she'll get over it
Listen
I've got an idea
If it's about Charlie coming traveling with us forget it
He's already said he doesn't want to but if we catch him with Claire we can blackmail him to come traveling with us
I see what you mean don't you think we should tell Becky about him and clay
Cuerno stupid
If we tell her we won't be able to Blackmail a let's make a plan