Time
Typescript 36
Atwood Sonny Vazquez midnight in Vermont
No
Do you make the best of your time
In the studio today we've got Roberta Wilson
Who's that time Management Consultant good morning Roberta
Good morning Paul
Roberta what exactly the time
Consultants to
Well Paul it's all about helping people to organize their work in an effective way
Maximum efficiency
Minimum stress
Sounds like something I need
Who are your clients
Mainly business people but I've also worked with politicians civil servants and University lectures
Quite a range that
What sort of things help people to organize their time
I suppose punctuality is it
Important yes and no
It's easier to finish a meeting on time if it starts on time but
In international context you do have to be aware of
Cultural
For example
Well
In Britain big formal meetings usually start on time but less formal meetings often begin a few minutes
In Germany on the other hand
People expect all meetings to begin on time
In some countries for example Latin America
There's some more relaxed attitude
So you do have to adapt
To circumstance
When in Rome to some extent yes
It sounds like even if you manage your own time very well you still can't control what other people do
Well you can set limits
If you're meeting a friend who always arrives late you can say
Well
I'm going to wait for 15 minutes
If they aren't there by then
I'll leave
I've got one friend who's always late
I don't think I'd ever see her if I did
People who are always late are the ones you need to set limits with
If they know that you won't wait
Perhaps they'll make an effort
Isn't that
Rather harsh not really
Someone who constantly turns up late is putting a low value on your time
Let them know you got other things to do
Suggesting you do that with everyone
Just a sister
Latecomers
Again
Different cultures do have different viewpoints on what constitutes serious lateness
What about interrupt
I often come into the studio with
Something important I need to do
Then the phone rings
Someone comes to see me
Before I know it
The day's over and I haven't done what I planned
You need to defend your time
If you're working on something important
And someone drops in to see you
Get your diarrhea
Politely tell them you're busy
I make an appointment for another time
Is it is an important anyways I'll just go away if it is
Make an appointment when you can deal with it properly
That sounds practical
Again you do have to be careful
In some cultures particularly Latin ones this technique can upset people
Here in the United States almost
So does everything depend on culture
No
Attitudes to time or one of the big differences between cultures but
How you organize your own work is up to you
And there are lots of techniques here
For example
Imagine you got two important things to do
One of them is Pleasant
The other isn't
Always try to do the unpleasant task first
That way the pleasant tasks is a reward for finishing
If you do it the other way around you'll tend to slow down the pleasant tasks because you don't want to do the unpleasant one
I remember that
Finally what for you is a hardworking person so I'm not very interested in
Hard-working people
You can spend 12 hours a day at the office without doing very much
Interested in productive and happy people
And on that note I have to say we've run out of time
Thank you Roberta
Andover to Jasmine.