Paint stripped 38
Okay so what did you get
I've got the 20th of February 1997
7 24th of May
Then I've got the 5th of November
Change
Then there's the 31st of July
Okay
And last one
The last one I got the 15th of July next year
Right okay well let's go for the oldest 124th and may 72 what's that
That's my birthday and I'm a Gemini okay
20th of February 97
Is my cat's birthday
31st of July 91
This is the day that I left college and I got my
First job in habitat Superstore
5th of November
5th November 99
Well that's fun fun I just called all right yeah the huge party takes place
And finally what's this 15th of July next year
Well I'm going on a weld trip
Where you going I'm going to Australia Sri Lanka to India the Far Eastern to America
All over the place
Lucky you it sounds great