Typescript 39
We're supposed to start work at 9
But I often coming later because I have to take my children to school first
But then I stay a bit later
Of course if I got an early meeting
Only if I go to being Court first thing in the morning
My wife has to take the kids to school
We're supposed to work a 40-hour week
But I think most people actually would move a lot
But we're supposed to dress smartly
Particularly if we have contact with clients
So I always win a suit and tie to work
A female lawyers aren't allowed to wear trousers or even doc tights
They have to wear knee-length skirts no Minis
The secretary's goodwear Taylor trousers
But no jeans
A weekly dress down day is being introduced recently it's an idea from America where everybody
He comes into work in casual dress on a Friday
Personally I have no desire to coming to work wearing jeans and a t-shirt
I like to make a difference between work and home and I can wear casual clothes
I think people should dress my paperwork
It gives a good impression
Smoking eating and drinking a strictly forbidden in the office there's a non-smoking cafeteria downstairs
I'm smoking have to go outside
Personally I think smoking going to be banned in all public places