Typescript 39
As you can see it's a really busy office and we have to work long hours
Everybody works different hours because people are coming in and out all the time
We can have a drink at our desks but we're not allowed to bring food into the offices
There's a canteen downstairs
We're supposed to have a break every two hours but when you're walking to a deadline you can't afford to take time for a break
Sometime
I worked right through my lunch hour it's mad really
In fact you have to be mad to work here
We're not supposed to smoke in the office but some of the reporters and journalists do when they're working late you know the
They've been smoking boobs that place smells horrible in the morning as far as dresses
The editors and Senior staff dress smartly
The Identical straight shots because I've never seen him wearing anything else
The younger man that more fashion-conscious they don't have to wear suits
The women can wear trousers or skirts but we can't wear jeans smart casual clothes
It said okay