Typescript 39
As you can imagine people who work here are pretty fashion-conscious
They can wear whatever they like
But people usually choose to dress smartly for work
They're the sort of people who enjoy dressing up
They're quite competitive
Most people wear black
It's a bit like wearing a uniform really black polo neck pullovers black bootlegged
Trousers
Black leather jackets in Boots
Not just the girls
The men tend to be more imaginative with their colors
They wear nice brightly colored shirts and then color their hair to match
Personally
I go for a more elegant look
Suits and high heels
Unfortunately most of the young models who come to the agency or smokers
But they're not allowed to smoke in the building
In fact they can't smoke anywhere near the building
I give such a bad impression when you see people smoking in the entrance
The agency is open from 10 in the morning
But the staff arrive anytime after 8
They have to work a nine-hour day
But the starting and finishing times are flexible
Coffee is available whenever you want it
But food isn't allowed in the office
Nobody here eats anyway