Journey
Typescript 40
It must be very strange to be back home after such a long time
I mean it's lovely to see everybody and I really appreciate my bed
Let's look at these photos then
Well they're all mixed up at the moment I'm going to show the map this look nice where is it
What do you think it is
It must be somewhere really hot
It looks like paradise
I suppose it could be Thailand or Bali
Or could he be Thea
Nah
I'll give you a clue
It's annoying and in the Pacific Ocean
Hawaii
No
I didn't go to Hawaii
I thought you'd been everywhere AJ then that's right
That was lovely
This man wanted me to marry his daughter she was beautiful and waiting that would have been
Yeah that's what I thought
But I don't think my mom would have been very pleased
Anyway
What about this one this is a bit different
Well must be Switzerland or somewhere in the French Alps
Nut
Who's the girl by the way
Oh yes that's it
What's your name
Not
In this picture she wasn't far from home
What county auction Tina can it
Maybe chili no
It's the southern part of Argentina
Patagonia they call it the Switzerland of the southern hemisphere
Rising
It really does look like Switzerland
So anyway
Did you meet a girl in every country visited