Typescript 41
This
So
Cool with your ideal companion B
My friend Anna who's doing a cool sin Oriental studies
And how would you get around probably use one of those very fast bullet trains to get there
And go by taxi around foot
And what would you wear
Depends on the time of year
I'd want to go there in spring for the cherry blossoms so
Probably just jeans and a sweatshirt
But make sure I had a clean pair of socks and some slip-on shoes because I think you have to take them off when you visit the temples
What would you buy nothing touristy
I might buy an electronic Gadget like a calculator
The supposed to be cheaper that drink for Western food
Probably end up eating at McDonald's and roll fish and I don't like rice much either
What essential items would you take with you
My camera
The temples that the shrines in the Goblins they're all supposed to be stunning
Who would you most like to meet today
I'd like to meet Acacia who speaks English and ask lots of questions
What sites would you want to see
Visit the golden temple and the real Angie Temple I think it is
Weather put on Amazing Zen Rock Garden
Who would you send a postcard to my ex-boyfriend to show him what a good time I'm having without him
What would spoil your perfect weekend bumping into somebody from work
Although I don't think it's likely on the other side of the world and Kyoto