Typescript 41
Christina
Who would your ideal companion be my mom and her checkbook
And how would you get around on foot around the underground
What would you wear the new clothes my mom is going to buy for me there
And what would you buy
Apart from clothes maybe a painting from one of the artists to sell their stuff along the river
What would you eat and drink
At 6 and drinking lots of lovely coffee and watch the world go by essential items
Would you take with you some glasses but because they look cool
Who would you most like to meet today jumpol Gotye I love him
What sites would you want to see the obvious places so I just like
Hanging out in the Latin quarter
And who would you send a postcard to
My dad
What would spoil your perfect weekend if the shops were shut Paris is a beautiful city
Send me the main attraction is the shuffling