Typescript 41
Rick
Who would your ideal companion be definitely not my wife she can't stand
The Sun
Probably my brother because I don't see him very often
And how would you get around the foot
I want to be going from the hotel to the beach
Would you wear as little as possible
And what would you buy
Probably buy some souvenirs for my wife and children at the airport what would you
Ethan drink what's that special dish moussaka
Write who would you most like to meet that nobody until I like peace and quiet
Essential items would you take with you
A couple of good books and plenty of suntan lotion at what sites would you want to visit
The beach in the daytime and a Taverna night
Who would you send a postcard to nobody
Writing a postcard would be too much like hard work
What would spoil perfect weekend
Rain
Hello so if the island was full of other English paper Greece is a popular destination
English people