Basics
Tates Creek 42
Well here we are at last do you like it
Die nice the music not too loud I hate it when they have loud music and
Restaurants good evening how are you ready to order
We haven't looked at the menu yet we have something to drink first
What would you like
Yes that would be nice read these two glasses of red wine
And could we have a few relics with that of course I'll be back to take your order in a moment
Right
Menu
Most of the things you like
Well
I don't eat meat or fish so anything without meat or fish I suppose
Okay
I didn't know you were a vegetarian
I don't think there any vegetarian dishes on the menu
They're losing things
Well
They do omelettes anyway
Go have a
Cheese omelette in salad
Are you sure that's fine I love on it
Okay
Do you mind if I have me
That's up to you
Oh you ready to order now
Will have
Cheese omelette and salad and
Steak and Chips please
How would you like your steak dancer
Medium-rare please
And could we have some french bread and a bottle of mineral water please
Alright I don't mind
Still please
Anything else
No
Eccleston house thank you