Typescript 44
Michael
You for the opportunity to taste some of the more unusual dishes from around the world
Can you tell us something about the dungeon particular
What it taste like
Yes well
I just come back from Thailand
I'm in the winter Cyclones of grasshoppers and locusts are brought into Bangkok from the countryside because the
They make a really crisp and tasty snacks inside
Fried grasshoppers at Tasty to most people
Provided they don't know what they're eating
Feed crickets in parts of North America
And they taste just the same
I'm not sure I'd like to eat insects well you better not go to Indonesia then
Last time I was there I had a feast of insect
The main course was roasted cockroaches
What did that taste like
They're all the mortuary and crisp on the outside and then
Rich liquid on the inside which tastes quite sweet and fruity
What other insects have you eaten
Well
Did you know that in Colombia
Cinema said roasted dance instead of popcorn play what are they like
Sweet and crisp
Delicious actually
Ingleside
Barbecued lizard in South America
But that was a bit disappointing was a bit Bland
Not particularly tasty
On the other hand iguana
Made a much more interesting dish
After 10 minutes boiling in very salty water they made a very tasty evening snack
A bit too salty for my taste but very good
I've heard that they grubs in Australia
Kant believed that
Is it true
Yes
I've never eaten them roll but I have eaten them fried
Little K
Chewy
Crunchy on the outside but on the inside
I'm sorry I don't even want to think about it
Can we change the subject
How about shark fin soup have you ever tried that
Only once
In China
It's very expensive and takes ages to
Prepare
But it's delicious
The Taste depends on how the chef prepare.
It was quite spicy I'm not particularly fishy
Anyway
What about you
Have you ever eaten anything strange adventurous as you
And I've never been out of Europe
Probably the strangest I must say the most revolting thing I've ever eaten was in Scotland recently
You mean this is delicious
No it was deep fried Mars Bar
What
Like fish and chips
Mothballing tips that's right
Greasy and horribly sweet
Disgusting