13 communication
Typescript 45
Welcome to the Inside Out helpline for students of English
Are some useful numbers and addresses for information
The news and current events
The BBC website is a good starting point at www.bbc.
Co.uk
An alternative is.cnn at www.cnn.com
Listen to BBC World Service radio
You can find out about schedules and local frequencies
By dialing 44 for the UK
7 double 5 7
Double 180
You can get the latest news and reviews on the music scene at ww.w.
Tv.com
Or if it's sports results you want
Then the Reuters cited
Cam will keep you right up-to-date
Travel information
Try one of the major search engines like Yahoo at
That's all one word
Y a h
Ss.com
Forward slash Recreation
Travel
The British tourist Authority has lots of information you'll find them at ww.w.
Visitbritain
Dot-com
If you are already in the UK
The telephone number for flight enquiries to and from Heathrow is o2o
If you are outside London
87-59