Typescript 48
Hello
Mom it's Richard
Oh
Is everything alright yes yes fine
How are you oh not too bad so I'm enjoying the peace and quiet
How's Maggie she's okay
Working hard
Mom I was wondering
Do you think you could lend me some money till the end of the month
Have you got yourself into debt again because if you have
Money
I mean you've got a good job Mom it's expensive living in Bristol
What you expect if you go out every night and buy expensive computers I haven't gotten
Computer
It's a PlayStation
I mean your sister never phone's up asking for money
You spent a fortune wedding
Well I'm not going to get married so you might as well give me the money no
What would Maggie say
Silly
How much do you need
300 lb
Honesty Richard
You really must learn to budget look Mom if you can
Just help me out this time I promise I'll try to be more careful in the future
Listen to it this time but this really is the last time
If you get yourself into trouble again you'll just have to sort it out yourself
Thanks Mom I'm doing this on one condition
Yes
You never say you're not going to get married again
Okay I promise
Thanks Mom
Bye
By next time
You could phone up Jeffery chat