Age
Tates Creek 52
You look worried what's on your mind
Actually there is something I've been meaning to tell you if it's about last night
It really doesn't matter I should have said it
I suppose it is in a way I knew it
My mouth shut look I agree with you the Rolling Stones are old-fashioned and
I wish I'd never put that record on not a bad record it's my fault I shouldn't have
Colton boring old dinosaurs know it my fault
Reacted like I did
That record brings back special memories for me
Look I understand
My parents used to play The Rolling Stones to know you don't understand
I was in my teens when that record first came out
Right
I see what you mean
Well you look very good for your age
I don't care how old you are
I need to tell you
What