Tates Creek 54
Friday
How old are Freddie 12
Is this a good age to be
Yeah
Your grown-up enough to be semi independent but still young
School of Justin from being one of the oldest to my old school
To being one of the youngest in Secondary School
Which do you prefer
Well it was good being the oldest because I could bust people around
But it's quite pooping youngest too because we're lets out early for lunch when we get to go home at 2:00
Come Wednesday afternoon
Also
Having an older brother in the same school helps
What are the advantages of being 12
You know teenager yet
So you're not annoyed and uptight about everything
How do you brother
What differences are there between being 12 and being 16 smells
Also you spell exams
Have you ever wished you were older or younger than you are
Yeah
Adult should be old enough not to tell you my roof but you have to
Yeah but if I was old enough to leave home and have my own place I would love to tell you my room