Thanks script 54
Jen
How old are you
16 what's it like being 16 is that a good age to be
Why
Because of the things I could do legally like
Go to bars and clubs and
Oh yeah and vote
Are you looking forward to boating
Do you mind if I ask you who you might vote for
I don't really know
In my oil changed in two years
What do you think is the best age to be
Probably when you really young
Before you go to school
You don't have a care in the world you go to brother who's 12 haven't you
Yes unfortunately all your lies different
Responsibilities
Part-time job at the weekend and I've got more of a workload from school
I've also got a lot more freedom
He's not allowed out after 6
Do you mind if I ask you whether you got a girlfriend
Not really