Take script 54
Yvette
You've just had an important stay haven't you
Well not really
These days 18 is the important one
So
How does it feel to be 21 exactly the same as 20
Is there anything you can do now that you couldn't do before you were 21
No not really
But I suppose when you're 21 you have more responsibilities
You're supposed to be more independent and you can't depend on your parents so much
I like to I have to pay for my holidays myself now
These are the disadvantages
And people expect grown-up behavior from you
What do you reckon is the best age to be
Maybe five years old
You go to play school and you play all day
Happy Buddha spoilers you and life is just fun
Have you ever wished you were older or younger
When I was about 15 my brother was allowed out and I wasn't
He's three years older than me and I wanted to be the same age as him