Take script 54
Carmel
Do you mind if I ask you how old you are
Actually I'd rather not say
But put it this way on the wrong side of 30
Is that a good age to be
Yes pretty good
It's a lot older than 25 which is how old
What's life like when you're in your thirties
. very different from my twenties except that I'm seriously thinking of buying more expensive face creams and
Wondering if they really work
What do you think is the best age to be
Between 25 and 30 is a good age because you kind of sort it out what you want
And you know how to get it and you've got some experience of trying to guess it
At that age you don't think about the consequences of
What you do when I was when you have been told that you do tend to worry about the consequences
So
Do you wish you were still 25
No
I'm happy at the age I am now
I mean I had a good time in my twenties but I wouldn't necessarily want to relive them