Review to
Typescript 55
So if we could turn to the origin of language
Do you know when we're on
Language originated
That's a difficult question to answer the answer is no one really knows
What we doing
Eastwind language was first written down
And that was about five and a half thousand years ago
About
The Sumerians who lived in Mesopotamia
The first people to write down their language
They use symbols called
Pictographs to represent everyday objects
Egyptian hieroglyphs
And the alphabet was developed around 3,500 years ago
By the Phoenicians
Who lived on the eastern coast of what is now Syria
Today there around 65
Interesting the one used in the Solomon Islands
As only 11 letters
Under the longest
I believe it's called 74
How many languages are there in the world today
Somewhere in the region of $4,000 will ever find out the exact
Which of these are the most spoken
Well Mandarin Chinese has about a billion speakers
English is next with about half billion speakers
And Hindi Spanish Russian behind
These five languages account for half of all the conversations in the world
Scientific truth Mandarin is the biggest line
I mean
The one with the most words
It's difficult to say
The latest thing
English is actually the biggest
Largely due to the number of Technical and scientific
At least a million
Most native speakers only use about 10,000 was
1%
Only 10,000
And can you guess which of these
The most used words in English
Maybe
Be
According to recent research
Tens of thousands of hours of conversation to be
The most common word is
Be
Will be we think is the most used but
What do you think about common noun in spoken English is
The most common noun maybe something like
Why did you just said it actually apparently it's
Sing
What about the origins of word
Where does English come from English which is about 500 years old
Mainly romance and Germanic language
Greek and Arabic Kabuto provided English with many would that digital sugar
Comes from Arabic
I'm surprisingly
Alcohol
Fax medic Mini
Happy borrowed from other languages
Example
Did you know that coffee
Come from Turkish
Chest the game
Where do you think ketchup as in tomato ketchup
Comes from
I've no idea
America
It's from the Malay language
Traditional Malaysian suicide
How about shampoo
Sounds a bit Oriental to Me Maybe Japanese
It's actually a Hindi word
India
The list is endless
You mentioned India
Is another country with hundreds of languages
Well
I don't know about hundred
I think Papua New Guinea is got the most
With 850 separately
India has gone.
The banknotes
I suppose they're the main line
Most people that speak at least two or three
And one
Final question
Speak two languages fluently is difficult enough
But have you any idea what the highest number of languages spoken by one person is
That eat
What was
A Frenchman
Complement
Bespoke
31 different languages
Will say thank you very much and
Audio