you're listening to Business English Pod
the Business English podcast for professionals
on the move
in this business English Pod episode
will be looking at ways to give
and ask for opinion. We'll be looking
both more formal
or careful language as well as more
informal
or direct language. Giving and asking for
opinions
is a very important part of meetings and
discussions of all types.
first let's listen to more formal
situation
we'll be listening to part of a meeting
at Digi Soft
a multinational software company. Sheila,
a vice president, is talking to wall
George and Bruce, 3 software engineers,
about the deadline for the new software
release.
Release here means "Launch"
that is bring the product onto the
market
so let's move on to the topic of
release date.Gentleman when do you think we'll be able to launch this product?
Walt? Well, I tend to feel that
we should probably be able to start
testing the product
EN April that means that if all goes
well
we can happen this release the me all
June I say thank you walt
what's your reaction to that group May
or June
well from my point of view that sounds
about right excuse me
may I come in here I wonder if I could
say something go ahead george
what would you like to add well it seems
to me that may is much much too early
actually we are still having some pretty
major problems with bugs in the update
engine
and I just don't see how we will be able
to fix those books
okay now let's listen to george
Bruce on wall walk into the break room
right after the meeting
Sheila their boss is not here this
is a more informal situation hey guys
did you see the Chelsea Liverpool game
last night what did you think
all quite I gave her Chelsea look pretty
good
cue always have to rub it in turns you
bruise
you know unlivable fan have that you
jewish
actually that was one of the greatest
games ever see
but the way you guys keep telling the
boss we can finish the product by May
numbers are going to have time to watch
in world football games
we're all going to be working overtime
every night burning the midnight oil
so now you've heard both formal and
informal conversations
first let's look at the form
conversation
how to Sheila ass for her employees
opinions
Sheila is in charge she is the boss
and the chairperson of the meeting one
way for her to ask for an employee's
opinion
is simply to say his name with the
rising intonation
work home gentleman when do you think we
will be able to launch this product
what she'll also use some other ways
to ask firm place opinions all these
ways are relatively formal
the signal that this is a formal meeting
she says I say thank you walt
what's your reaction to that Bruce and
go ahead george what would you like to
add
together with the speakers try some
other form of races
for asking for an opinion how do you
feel about that
Cecilia
could you please share your thoughts on
that fair
what's your view on this Richard
Tony what's your feelings on the 8th
now let's look at the language wall
Bruce and George use
to express their opinions informal
situation lot says
well I tend to feel that we should be
able to start testing the product
EN April this language
I tend to feel that shows careful
formal tone what uses the stone
because he is talking to his boss and
perhaps because he's not sure
whether or not the others will agree
with them let's keep listening
I say thank you walt
what's your reaction to that group May
or June
well from my point of view that sounds
about right
Bruce likewise uses more formal careful
language
well from my point of view this makes
him some more polite
since he's talking to his boss in
addition
begins in time to think giving yourself
time to think
is another reason to use these phrases
haha George
how did he offer his opinion excuse me
may I come in here I wonder if I could
say something go ahead george
what would you like to add well it seems
to me that may is much much too early
think about the ways to George users to
express his opinion
I wonder if I could say something and
well it seems to me that these
ways expression are quite careful George
has a good reason to be careful doesn t
he disagrees with his colleagues now
let's practice some
further formal were careful phrases for
expressing your opinion
I have the impression that
he didn't really want to come
don't you think that that's a little
early
I tend to feel it's a bit too early to
start
next let's turn
a more informal discussion between will
Bruce and George
remember there in the breakroom
right after the meeting Bruce ass
georgian Walt
hey guys did you see the Chelsea luv
all-gay
last night what the debate will quiet
gave her
Chelsea look for a ticket this is an
informal relaxed discussion among
colleagues
you can tell it's informal because Bruce
uses the informal word
guys to address george wall also
he says what do you think this is an
informal way to ask for an opinion
what says cue always have to read the
tendency to bruise
you know am a Liverpool fan to rub
something in
is an Indian it means to remind someone
on purpose
something that is uncomfortable or
painful here
it's done as a joke it sounds like Walt
is a Liverpool fan
and he's unhappy because Chelsea won the
game
let's keep listening how bad you jewish
actually
that was one of the greatest games ever
see how about you
is another direct way to ask for an
opinion next
notice how George start a sentence with
actually
actually is a direct or informal way to
state an opinion
it shows us the George has something new
were surprising decide with George
practice more direct ways to state an
opinion the point
ease we doing very well in this market
the way I see it we're heading for
trouble
obviously his only one choice
basically I think we have two options
finally let's listen to the and the
dialogue again
have that you jewish actually that was
one of the greatest games ever see
but the way you guys keep telling the
boss we can finish the product by May
numbers are going to have time to watch
him win football games
George means that Bruce on wall keep
telling the boss
that they can meet the may deadline
everyone is going to have to work very
hard in fact
they're going to have to work so hard
that they won't have any time to watch
football games