You're learning with 925
English - Business English for the workplace.
Hi Tim here with another
nine to five english lesson.
Today we're going to learn how to give
instructions in english.
Telling people what to do isn't just
something the boss does.
Anytime you're helping someone with a
problem
training someone giving technical advice
or telling a colleague how to do
something
you're giving instructions.
Of course it's very important to be
clear when you're giving instructions.
And for that reason we sometimes explain things
step by step in a sequence
of instructions. This means
using words like first
secondly and thirdly.
Or you might use other words like
next and at the end of your sequence
finally or lastly.
Let's practice some ways of using these
words
to give a sequence of instruction.
Listen to each example then repeat it
for yourself
Ready let's get started.
First try closing the program and opening it again.
Secondly i'd like you to complete the
rest of the form.
Next you'll have to choose a password.
Finally don't forget to log out at the end of the session.
So did those instructions sound like
orders i mean do you think
giving instructions means saying do this
and do that well
not exactly in fact in
english we don't like to be too direct
in most
situations that's why we say
can you try closing the program instead
of
close the program or
you'll have to choose a password instead
of just
choose a password one way to avoid being
too direct in
english is to use special words
called modals modals are words
such as can and need to
and could and should
using modals is easy you just
put the modal between you and
the main verb for example
you might say first
you need to open an account
let's try some examples of giving
instructions
using modals. Remember to repeat the
examples after you hear them.
You'll need to enter your username and
password to begin.
Okay you can now open the app and create an account.
Could you try restarting your device?
You need to start by launching the
program from the main menu.
Did you notice that one example came
in the form of a question? that's an
extra polite way of telling someone to
do something.
Not every modal can be used that way
however. Only can and
could will work. For example,
could you check if your password is
correct
is just a nice way of saying check your
password is correct
you can also combine sequences
and modals to find the right balance
between being clear
and polite. But what if you're not
sure whether you've been clear enough?
What if you don't really know whether
the other person has understood?
fortunately we have lots of different
ways of
checking understanding. And the best way is just to ask directly like
do you understand you might also
ask if people are clear or whether
everything makes sense these
are just different ways of asking if
something has been understood
let's try some practice with checking
understanding
using these expressions. Once again
repeat the examples after you hear them.
So is everyone clear on what they have
to do?
Okay do you understand how this works now?
Does that make sense to you?
Any questions about what you need to do?
As you heard one other way to check
understanding is to ask if there are any
questions.
that way you can find out exactly what
people
don't understand.
Okay, so we've practiced some useful ways of
giving instructions
and checking understanding. But what do
these expressions
sound like in a conversation?
Let's listen to a short dialogue between
Sean and Kim. Sean
has asked for help using a machine
and Kim is giving him instructions
on how to use it. Let's listen.
Could you help me with this?
Sure, first try turning the machine on.
Okay i did that what's next?
Next you can turn the dial on the front to 50.
Does that make sense? Kim begins by
instructing him to turn the machine on
then to turn the dial to 50.
She uses the sequence word next
and the modal can.
Now it's your turn to practice.
We'll repeat the dialogue but this time
we're going to beep out the second
speaker's words.
You will have to say those parts
yourself.
Remember to say that first Sean
should turn the machine on then
say next and instruct
him to turn the dial on the front to 50.
Could you help me with this?
Okay i did that what's next?
All right that's all for this lesson.
We've learned some great ways to give
instructions
and to check understanding.
We'll be back soon with some more
useful english expressions. Until then
so long and happy learning!