You're learning with nine to five
English. Business English for the
workplace.
Hi Tim here with another
nine to five english lesson
In today's lesson we're going to learn
how to end a phone call in english.
last time we looked at lots of useful
expressions
for answering the phone and starting a
call
but what about ending a call?
if you finished your conversation what
can you say
to end the call politely
well for starters one thing you want to
avoid is just suddenly saying
goodbye to end a business call
professionally there are three simple
steps
to follow first you signal
that you want to end secondly
you review your action points
and finally you say goodbye
now signaling that you want to end a
call
often starts with a word like well
so or okay
these words show that you want to change
the subject then you can thank the
person
and say you need to go or
make a general comment let's
practice some of these ways of showing
that you want to end a call listen
to each example then repeat it
for yourself ready let's get started
well i should probably get going
it's been great to chat
so thanks for all the information
okay i've got to run here
as you can hear these types of comments
signal an end to the conversation
you might have noticed two different
expressions
that mean you have to leave a situation
first was i should probably get
going and the second was
i've got to run these are just
friendly ways of saying i need to leave.
now a business call is like a little
meeting
so the second step in ending a call
is reviewing the actions you've
discussed often
this means stating what you will do next
like i'll send you the file tomorrow
and if you want to confirm what the
other
person will do or what you'll both do
you can turn your statement into a
question
using a tag that might sound like
so you'll review the proposal next week
right let's try some
other examples of reviewing next
steps remember to repeat the examples
after you hear them
so i'll send you that file tomorrow and
you can let me know what you think
all right so we'll be chatting again
next week right
i'll have that package sent off right
away
i'll look out for your email later today
one expression you might have noticed
there
is isle or i will
have that package sent off for example
what does it mean to have something done
it means you make sure the thing
is done it might be you
it might be someone else but you will
make sure
it's done all right
so you've signaled that you want to end
the call
and you've reviewed next steps
now you're ready to sign off
or say goodbye there are many ways to
say goodbye
in english you can wish someone
a great day or a
good weekend or good luck
with something and we often say
take care or mention when we'll talk
again
let's practice some more ways to sign
off
at the end of a call once again
repeat the examples after you hear them
have a great day bye now
take care amy we'll talk again soon
all right then have a good weekend
good luck with your presentation
did you hear that expression by now
you might also hear people say bye for
now
or maybe by then
these are just common and friendly ways
of saying goodbye so
we've practiced some useful expressions
but how do these sound in a conversation
let's listen to a short dialogue between
mark
and leslie both people are signaling
they want to end the conversation
and using expressions to sign off
let's listen
well i hope your interview goes well
thanks kevin it's been great to chat for
sure
glad we could catch up all right then
have a good weekend
how did that sound leslie thanks
kevin for saying he hopes her interview
goes well
then she makes a comment about their
conversation
mark responds with his own comment and
leslie signs off by wishing him
a good weekend now
it's your turn to practice we'll repeat
the dialogue
but this time we're going to beep out
the second speaker's words
you will have to say those parts
yourself
remember to thank kevin and say
it's been great to chat then
you'll wish him a good weekend
after using the expression all right
then
well i hope your interview goes well
for sure glad we could catch up
well that's all for this lesson
we've learned a three-step process to
ending a business call this includes
signaling you want to end the call
reviewing the steps and saying
goodbye we'll be back soon
with some more useful english
expressions
until then so long
and happy learning