You're learning with 925 English!
Business English for the workplace!
Hi Tim here with another 925 English
lesson. Last time we had a look at how to
start a conversation. In this lesson
we're going to learn how to keep a
conversation going. After all there's no
point in striking up a conversation with
someone if you can't keep it going. But
what does that involve? I mean it's more
than just asking and answering questions
right? So what kinds of things can we say
or do to make the conversation flow
naturally? Well one important way that we
keep a conversation going
is by showing interest in what someone
says.
If the person makes a comment about
something like the weather or work,
you need to respond with interest.
So what can we say to show we are interested?
Well there are a few ways we can do this.
First you can give an expression of
interest like 'really' or 'is that right'.
Then you can make a comment or a
question about it. You might also just
pick out one idea that the person
mentioned and make a little question
about it. Let's practice some examples of
showing interest in this way.
Listen to each example then repeated
yourself. Ready? Let's get started!
Is that right? Wow, I hear it's beautiful
this time of year.
No kidding! That must be such an exciting job.
Oh really! That must have been amazing
Is that right? So then what did he say?
Okay, so showing interest is important but
how does it sound in real life?
Let's listen to a short dialogue between two travelers. They're talking about where
they are 'headed' or traveling to.
And where you headed? Home to seoul if we ever get out of here.
South Korea, hey? Never been but I've
heard great things. You like it there?
Yeah for sure. You know it's a big crazy
city with lots happening.
Did you hear the expression of interest
there? One person mentioned he is going
to Seoul and the other person invited
more information about that topic.
And you might notice that in a casual
conversation like this we don't talk too
long about one thing before giving the
other person a chance to talk.
And now's a good time to give you a chance to talk.
So let's try a little practice.
We'll repeat the dialogue but this time we're going to beep out the response that
shows interest. You will have to say that
part. Remember that to show interest we
make a little comment and then ask a
question. Here we go.
And where you headed?
Home to seoul we ever get out of here.
Yeah for sure. You know it's a big crazy
city with lots happening.
Nice work! Now a conversation doesn't just continue on
one topic forever right? At some point
the speakers change the subject but you
can't just suddenly start talking about
something different that would be
strange because natural conversation
flows;  it doesn't jump around.
So exactly
how do we change the subject?
Well you need a little transition. Just a
little word or expression that means
"hey let's talk about something different now"
That might be just a word like now or it
might be a phrase like by the way.
Let's practice changing the subject with a few examples. Remember to repeat what you hear.
Ready? Let's give it a try.
Speaking of summer, how does our third
quarter look?
Oh before I forget, are you going on the
trip next month?
By the way, did I tell you that we're
headed to Hawaii at Christmas?
And you? Has it been a good month?
As you can see you can change the
subject to several different topics.
You might want to move the conversation
toward work or to recent events or to travel plans.
Or, if you think you've
talked a lot about yourself, you might
want to change the topic to the other
person.
So as we've seen conversation
flows from topic to topic and back and
forth between people but what about
ending a conversation? What do you say
when you want to draw it to a close?
Well all you need is some kind of excuse
or reason for leaving. Maybe you need to
use the restroom or make a phone call.
And when you give your excuse you can
introduce it with something like "I
should" or "I need to."
Let's practice some examples of ending a conversation.
Once again, repeat the examples after you
hear them. Ready?
It's been nice chatting but I suppose I
should go find my seat.
It's getting pretty late and I should
really be heading home.
If you'll excuse me, I just need to make a quick call.
Well, I  shouldn't leave my husband sitting there alone for too long.
Okay, now how about listening to how
ending a conversation works in real life?
Let's listen to the end of a
conversation between two people chatting
at an office party.
So you live here in the city then? Yeah
in Delgado
Is that right? I've got a
cousin in that area. Pretty nice.
And convenient
Indeed lovely place.
Well Shelly it's great to talk but I've got
to go and freshen up and find a table.
Maybe run into you later
So did you hear how that worked?
Amber said she needed to freshen up
which is a nice way for a woman to say
she needs to use the restroom. And she
started by saying "it's great to talk"
which we often used to indicate that the
conversation is coming to an end before
we give an excuse to leave.
Now it's your turn to practice.
We'll  repeat the dialogue but will beep out the end of the conversation.
You can fill that in
yourself by saying it was nice to talk
and then giving any excuse to leave.
Ready? Here we go.
Is that right? I've got a cousin in that area. Pretty nice.
And convenient.
All right! Now that we've looked at how
to end a conversation, it's time for us
to end this lesson.
Besides learning how
to end a conversation we've looked at
some ways of keeping it going by showing
interest or changing the subject
We'll be back soon with another 925
English lesson. Until then so long and
happy learning!