(♪ INTRO) -- (♪ 開場音樂)
Wasn’t that great, Squeaks?! -- 那不是很棒嗎，史奎克斯？
(Squeaks squeaks) --(史奎克斯叫聲)
What was your [favorite(最喜歡的)] part? -- 你最喜歡的部分是什麼？
(Squeaks squeaks) -- (史奎克斯叫聲)
Yeah, the [roller coaster(雲霄飛車)] was great! -- 是的，雲霄飛車真的很棒！
Oh, hey there! Squeaks and I just got back from the [carnival（喜年華）]! -- 哦，嗨！史奎克斯和我剛從嘉年華回來！
We rode on lots of fun rides, played carnival games… it was -- 我們體驗了很多有趣的遊樂設施，玩了嘉年華遊戲... 真是太有趣了！
But do you know my favorite part of a carnival? -- 但你知道我在嘉年華最喜歡的是什麼嗎？
The food! -- 是食物！
Hot dogs, ice cream, and… cotton candy! -- 熱狗、冰淇淋，還有... 棉花糖！
I love [cotton candy(棉花糖)]! -- 我喜歡棉花糖！
It’s super [fluffy(蓬鬆)], and really sweet. -- 它超級蓬鬆，而且非常甜。
And it comes in so many different colors and flavors. -- 而且有很多不同的顏色和口味。
Like pink or blue, vanilla or bubblegum. -- 像粉紅色或藍色，香草或泡泡糖口味。
(Squeaks squeaks) -- (史奎克斯叫聲)
Oh, what’s your question, Squeaks? -- 噢，史奎克斯，你有什麼問題？
What’s it made out of? -- 它是由什麼做成的？
Well, [even though（即使）] we call it cotton candy, this stuff isn’t really made out of cotton. -- 嗯，即使我們稱之為棉花糖，但它並不是真的由棉花製成的。
Cotton candy is made out of sugar, but we call it “cotton” candy -- 棉花糖是由糖製成的，但我們稱之為「棉花」糖
because it reminds some people of cotton. -- 是因為它讓一些人想起棉花。
Do you see any similarities between
the candy and the cotton plant? -- 你看到糖果和棉花植物之間有任何相似之處嗎？
(Squeaks squeaks) -- (吱吱叫聲)
Yeah, they both have a super fluffy texture, with lots of soft, wispy strands. -- 是的，它們都具有超級蓬鬆的質地，有著許多柔軟、纖細的絲狀物。
So some people call this food “cotton” candy because their texture -- 因此，有些人稱這種食物為“棉花”糖果，因為它們的質地
looks and feels so similar. -- 看起來和感覺非常相似。
Other people call cotton candy
“sugar floss” or “fairy floss”, -- 其他人稱棉花糖為“糖絲”或“仙女絲”，
because of how teeny tiny
the little sugar strings are. -- 因為這些小小的糖絲非常細小。
(Squeaks squeaks) -- (吱吱叫聲)
Yes, a little like [tooth floss（牙線）] for a [fairy（仙女）]! -- 是的，有點像仙女用的牙線！
But even though it might look like cotton or little fairy strings, -- 但即使它看起來像棉花或小仙女絲，
this candy is just sugar, which is why it tastes so sweet. -- 這種糖果其實只是糖，所以才會那麼甜。
(Squeaks squeaks) -- (吱吱叫聲)
Hm, you’re right that sugar doesn’t always look fluffy like in cotton candy. -- 嗯，你說得對，糖不總是像棉花糖那樣蓬鬆。
Here, let’s take a look at some sugar like we’d find in our [sugar jar（糖罐）] really closely! -- 來，讓我們仔細看看糖罐裡的一些糖！
If we look really closely, this sugar is [solid（固體）], -- 如果我們仔細看，這些糖是固體的，
with tiny shapes that don’t change much. -- 有著微小的形狀，並且不太變化。
This sugar is small and kind of round, almost like little rocks. -- 這些糖很小而且有點圓，幾乎像小石頭一樣。
We call this special solid form of sugar crystals. -- 我們稱這種特殊的固體糖晶為。
(Squeaks squeaks) -- (吱吱叫聲)
Well, solid crystals can’t really
change their shape too much. -- 嗯，固體晶體實際上無法改變太多形狀。
So to change the sugar’s shape into the fluffy wisps of cotton candy, -- 因此，為了把糖的形狀變成鬆軟的棉花糖，
we need to use [heat(熱] to help us. -- 我們需要用熱來幫助我們。
When sugar crystals are put into a cotton candy machine, -- 當糖晶體被放入棉花糖機中，
they start as solid crystals. -- 它們開始時是固體晶體。
These sugar crystals usually have [food coloring（食用色素）] and [flavoring（香料）] added to them, -- 這些糖晶體通常會加入食用色素和香料，
so they’ll be extra colorful and tasty. -- 這樣它們會更加豐富多彩和美味。
Next the cotton candy machine starts to heat up, -- 接下來，棉花糖機開始加熱，
and that heat begins to [melt（融化)] the sugar, changing the sugar -- 熱量開始融化糖，改變糖的狀態
from solid crystals into something new. -- 從固體晶體轉變成全新的物質。
What state do you think the
sugar will melt into, Squeaks? -- Squeaks，你認為糖會融化成什麼狀態？
(Squeaks squeaks) -- (吱吱叫聲)
That’s right! When solid sugar melts, it melts into [liquid（液體)] sugar. -- 沒錯！當固體糖融化時，它會變成液體糖漿。
While the sugar is a liquid, it can change shape much more easily. -- 當糖是液體時，它可以更容易地改變形狀。
That means the machine can stretch the liquid sugar into long, thin lines. -- 這意味著機器可以把液體糖拉伸成長而細的線條。
The cotton candy machine has a lot of teeny, tiny holes inside -- 棉花糖機內部有很多微小的小孔，
for the liquid sugar to go through. -- 讓液體糖漿通過的小孔。
Little drips of liquid sugar go through as the machine spins, -- 當機器旋轉時，液體糖漿會滴下來，
and when they fling into the big empty space in the middle, -- 當它們擺動到中間的大空間時，
they cool down really quickly and change back into solid sugar. -- 它們迅速冷卻，重新變回固體糖。
The liquid sugar can turn back into a solid as it cools down, -- 當液體糖冷卻下來時，它可以變回固體，
just like it melted when it got hot. -- 就像在受熱時融化一樣。
But it looks a bit different now… -- 但現在它看起來有點不同...
(Squeaks squeaks) -- (吱吱叫聲)
Yeah, just like threads of cotton candy! -- 對，就像棉花糖的線條一樣！
When the liquid sugar cools back into a solid, it keeps the long, thin shape -- 當液體糖冷卻回到固體時，它保持了長而細的形狀，
that allowed it to go through the cotton candy machine holes, -- 這使它能夠通過棉花糖機的孔洞，
instead of turning back into the larger, hard crystals of plain sugar. -- 而不是變回更大、更硬的晶體糖。
Those little sugar threads are rolled up into a big, fluffy puff -- 這些小糖絲被捲成一個大而鬆軟的球狀
that we recognize as cotton candy. -- 就是我們認識的棉花糖。
The sugar changes a lot when it’s heated up and cooled down. -- 當糖受熱和冷卻時，它會發生很大的變化。
It went from a solid crystal, to liquid, to a thin, fluffy solid. -- 它從固體晶體變成液體，再變成薄薄的鬆軟固體。
Still, some things stayed the same, like its sweet flavor! -- 然而，一些東西保持不變，比如它的甜味！
I have a great idea! -- 我有一個好主意！
Do you want to go back to the carnival tomorrow to get more cotton candy -- 明天你想回到嘉年華會場再買更多棉花糖嗎？
and take a closer look at how the machine works, Squeaks? -- 並且仔細觀察一下機器是如何工作的，Squeaks？
(Squeaks squeaks) -- (吱吱叫聲)
Alright! -- 好的！
Have you seen cotton candy being made? -- 你看過製作棉花糖的過程嗎？
What other ways do you think people can change sugar to make new sweet treats? -- 你覺得人們還能用什麼其他方法改變糖來製作新的甜點呢？
Thanks for exploring how to
make cotton candy with us today. -- 感謝你今天與我們一起探索如何製作棉花糖。
Remember, if you want to keep learning new things with Squeaks and me, -- 記住，如果你想繼續和Squeaks以及我一起學習新知識，
and all of our friends, hit the subscribe button, -- 以及我們所有的朋友，按下訂閱按鈕，
and we’ll see you next time, here at the Fort. -- 下次見，就在堡壘這裡。
(Squeaks squeaks) -- (吱吱叫聲)
(♪ OUTRO)