I'm here because I got a divorce. -- 我來這裡是因為我離婚了。
I wanted to take on a new challenge -- 我想接受新的挑戰。
and just sort of [reset my life]. -- 並且重新啟動我的生活。
You'll get all the badges, make lots of friends. -- 你會獲得所有徽章，結交很多朋友。
This is an adult camping trip.
Yes.
-- 這是一個成人露營之旅。
是的
It's not camp. -- 不是夏令營。
Yes. [Archery badge]. -- 是的。射箭徽章。
No archery. No.
Okay.
--
不能射箭。不行。
好吧
We'll be working our way through some of Connecticut's 51 miles -- 我們將穿越康乃狄克州的51英里
of the Appalachian Trail. -- 阿巴拉契亞山徑。
These people here... -- 這些人在這裡...
...are your team. -- ...是你的團隊。
It's hike day, baby! Whoo! -- 今天是遠足的日子，寶貝！耶！
Like some coffee, Ellen?
My name is Helen, with an H.
-- 要喝點咖啡嗎，艾倫？
我的名字是海倫，開頭是H
Really? With an H, Helen? Hm. -- 真的嗎？帶個「H」的，海倫？嗯。
I'm Hugh. I'm old enough not to discuss my age. -- 我是休，我已經老到不需要討論我的年齡了。
She knows what I'm talking about. -- 她知道我在講什麼。
I am taking a vow of silence on our hike. -- 我在這次遠足中守口如瓶。
Okay, people. -- 好了，大家。
Well, let's gather around. -- 好吧，讓我們聚在一起。
Should we expect to see a bear around here? -- 我們應該預料會在這附近看到熊嗎？
I'd say expect anything. -- 我會說預料可能會有任何事情發生。
What about [large stray dogs]? -- 那大型流浪狗呢？
[That is very unlikely]. -- 那是非常不可能的。
I sense [tension] between the two of you. -- 我感受到你們之間的緊張氛圍。
Oh, no. We actually know each other.
He's my little brother's best friend.
-- 喔，不是的。我們實際上認識彼此，
他是我小弟弟最好的朋友。
Why are you here? People [get seriously injured] on these hikes. -- 你為什麼在這裡？在這些遠足中人們會受到嚴重的傷害。
That's where you're wrong.
This is the new and improved Helen. -- 你錯了，這是新的、進化過的海倫。
This Helen [spits in the face of danger]. -- 這個海倫勇於面對危險。
Ow! -- 哎喲！
How did you find the sharpest rock in the forest? -- 你怎麼找到了森林中最銳利的岩石？
I got it, thank you. I got it. -- 我拿到了，謝謝。我拿到了。
Why did you come here? -- 你為什麼來這裡？
I think I just sort of [got sick of being fed up with myself]. -- 我想我只是厭倦
Every night, I write three good things that happened to me. -- 每晚我寫下三件發生在我身上的好事。
And, what, just like that you're happy? -- 就這樣你就開心了嗎？
All you talk about is how [your breakup is clinging to you], -- 你一直在談論你的分手如何困擾著你，
but that's not what I see. -- 但我不這麼認為。
Why do you sound like a [jealous boyfriend]? -- 為什麼你聽起來像個嫉妒的男朋友？
You were too good for him. -- 你對他來說太好了。
If you like him, just tell him. -- 如果你喜歡他，就告訴他。
You've got to [look closer at the big picture]. -- 你必須更仔細地看待整個情況。
I remember you seemed to really like your life, -- 我記得你似乎真的喜歡你的生活，
and you laughed all the time. -- 你一直笑個不停。
Yeah, I was young. -- 是的，那時我還年輕。
Well, you're still really young. -- 嗯，你仍然很年輕。
You don't realize it, but [life really takes a toll]. -- 你沒有意識到，但生活真的會耗盡你的精力。
Figure out a way to [fight back]. -- 想辦法反擊。
[To the trail]. -- 出發上山徑。