how's it going pregnant man oh yeah too easy mandon't know what all the fuss is about oh good --
well soon you'll start feeling the baby kickingoh no I'm sure that's not for a little while ow --
kick kick kick --
oh you never forget that first kick okay that's a wrap kids come on unclip --
no not yet you haven't had the baby --
too bad how do you get this thingoff you said if you're going to do --
something do it properly ah thatadvice doesn't apply to me hello --
he's having a baby --
what happens now what are you asking me foraren't you the midwife no I'm just a friend I --
work at a petrol station what I'm out wellwho's gonna deliver my baby I true blue is it me --
and you yes is it mum and dad is it er lucky star can you giveus a hand with something yeah no worries bluey --
I didn't know this was the something lightenup pat but I don't know how to deliver a --
baby I thought you grew up in a farm wegrew sorghum dad the cricket started I'm --
busy mate just shout if there's a wicket okaywell how hard can this be I'll just gravel it --
hey where are you going I'm not going anywherebingo that tickles well we'll see about that --
i've got a foot ooh she's got my belly hair --
it's none for six dad any boundaries one boundary two singleswho got the boundary focus oh yeah sorry --
I can see the butt I can seethe butt you can watch lots --
more bluey on BBC iPlayer askyour grown-up to search bluey --