I have a lot of memories from when I was
a child one that's always stuck out to
me though was when I was about 10 years
old and I was in school and I struggled
and I didn't struggle with English math
or science I struggled holding still and
I would try to listen and focus and
process ideas but I couldn't help myself
then to be honest I would sit there and
then I would just start tapping and the
students in the class would look at me
and they'd say hey stop tapping a lot of
the time I didn't even realize I was
doing it and then eventually even the
teachers got after me and they would
yell at me and they say Clint you have
to stop tapping
it got so bad that I got sent to the
principal's office for tapping and he
said to me kid maybe when you go back to
class
just try sitting on your hands so I did
I went back to class and when I felt
myself starting to tap I just I did this
i sat on my hands and that works for
about five seconds
one time I was tapping in class and my
teacher mr. Jensen he looked at me and
he yelled and he said Clint stay after
class and I thought to myself this is it
I am done now I've always been the type
of person that believes that a single
moment in time can change a person's
life and this was one of those moments
for me that I will never forget it so I
was sitting there with mr. Jensen and an
empty classroom and he walked past me
and he sat next to his desk and he said
Clint come here I'll talk to you and as
he looked me right in the eye he said
you know I need you to know something
you're not in trouble but I do have just
one question that I have to ask you
and he asked he said have you ever
thought about playing the drums and in
that moment mr. Jensen he leaned back
and he opened the top drawer of his desk
and he reached in and he pulled out my
very first pair of drumsticks and he
held them in his hands and he looked at
me he said hey Clint you're not a
problem
I think you're in trouble
[Music]
from that moment on I've never put those
six down I've toured recorded and play
drums all over the world my whole
college education was paid for with
drumsticks in my hand
just because of a single moment in time
when somebody believed in me and he saw
something in me that I didn't even see
within myself
and from that moment I learned that
there's a difference between being the
best in the world and being the best for
the world
[Music]
you