I threw a wish in the well -- 我向許願池裡許下了個願望
Don't ask me I'll never tell -- 別問我，我絕不會脫口透漏
I looked at you as it fell -- 我充滿愛意的看著你
And now you're in my way -- 而你就這樣走入了我的生命
I trade my soul for a wish -- 我以我的靈魂交換一個願望
Pennies and dimes for a kiss -- 用幾個分、角銅板換一個吻
I wasn't looking for this -- 我並不是真的在尋求這個
But now you're in my way -- 但如今你就這樣佔據了我的生命
Your stare was holding -- 你堅定地凝視著我
Ripped jeans Skin was showing -- 破牛仔褲透出你的肌膚
Hot night Wind was blowing -- 火熱的夜晚伴隨著微風拂面
Where you think you're going baby? -- 你覺得自己還能去哪裡呢，寶貝？
Hey I just met you -- 嘿，我才剛遇見你
And this is crazy -- 而這聽起來有點瘋狂
But here's my number -- 但這裡是我的電話號碼
So call me maybe -- 所以可以的話打給我好嗎？
It's hard to look right at you baby -- 直視你的雙眸實在是件難事，親愛的
But here's my number -- 但這裡是我的電話號碼
So call me maybe -- 所以可以的話打給我好嗎？
Hey I just met you -- 嘿，我才剛遇見你
And this is crazy -- 而這聽起來有點瘋狂
But here's my number -- 但這裡是我的電話號碼
So call me maybe -- 所以可以的話打給我好嗎？
And all the other boys -- 而且有其他男孩
Try to chase me -- 想要追我
But here's my number -- 但這裡是我的電話號碼
So call me maybe -- 所以可以的話打給我好嗎？
You took your time with the call -- 你花了好長一段時間才打給我
I took no time with the fall -- 但我沒過多少時間便陷入愛情
You gave me nothing at all -- 你尚未對我付出些什麼
But still you're in my way -- 但你仍深入我的世界裡
I beg and borrow and steal -- 我用乞求、借取甚至用偷竊的各種手段來感受
At first sight and it's real -- 第一眼見到你並感受到這如此真實
I didn't know I would feel it -- 我從未知曉我能體會到這個
But it's in my way -- 但一切就這樣闖入我的世界中
Your stare was holding -- 你堅定地凝視著我
Ripped jeans Skin was showing -- 破牛仔褲透出你的肌膚
Hot night Wind was blowing -- 火熱的夜晚伴隨著微風拂面
Where you think you're going baby? -- 你覺得自己還能去哪裡呢，寶貝？
Hey I just met you -- 嘿，我才剛遇見你
And this is crazy -- 而這聽起來有點瘋狂
But here's my number -- 但這裡是我的電話號碼
So call me maybe -- 所以可以的話打給我好嗎？
It's hard to look right at you baby -- 直視你的雙眸實在是件難事，親愛的
But here's my number -- 但這裡是我的電話號碼
So call me maybe -- 所以可以的話打給我好嗎？
Hey I just met you -- 嘿，我才剛遇見你
And this is crazy -- 而這聽起來有點瘋狂
But here's my number -- 但這裡是我的電話號碼
So call me maybe -- 所以可以的話打給我好嗎？
And all the other boys -- 然後有其他的男孩
Try to chase me -- 想要追我
But here's my number -- 但這裡是我的電話號碼
So call me maybe -- 所以可以的話打給我好嗎？
Before you came into my life -- 在你來到我生命前
I missed you so bad -- 我就很想你
I missed you so so bad -- 我就非常非常想你
Before you came into my life -- 在你來到我生命前
I missed you so bad -- 我就很想你
And you should know that -- 而且你該知道
It's hard to look right at you baby -- 直視你的雙眸實在是件難事，親愛的
But here's my number -- 但這裡是我的電話號碼
So call me maybe -- 所以可以的話打給我好嗎？
Hey I just met you -- 嘿，我才剛遇見你
And this is crazy -- 而這聽起來有點瘋狂
But here's my number -- 但這裡是我的電話號碼
So call me maybe -- 所以可以的話打給我好嗎？
And all the other boys -- 而且有其他男孩
Try to chase me -- 想要追我
But here's my number -- 但這裡是我的電話號碼
So call me maybe -- 所以可以的話打給我好嗎？
Before you came into my life -- 在你到來我的生活之前
I missed you so bad -- 我便已經強烈的思念你的存在
I missed you so bad -- 我已經非常的想念你
I missed you so so bad -- 我真的強烈的想要你、非常的
Before you came into my life -- 在你到來我的生活之前
I missed you so bad  -- 我已經非常的想念你
And you should know that -- 而你該知道這些
So call me, maybe -- 所以可以的話打給我好嗎？
www.RentAnAdviser.com