I stay out too late -- 昨晚熬夜熬太晚
Got nothing in my brain --   害我腦袋一片空白
That's what people say, mmm-mmm -- 大家都這麼說
I go on too many dates [chuckle] -- 我約了好多次約會
But I can't make them stay -- 但我沒法留住他們
At least that's what people say, mmm-mmm -- 反正大家都這麼說
That's what people say, mmm-mmm -- 反正大家都這麼說
But I keep cruising  -- 但我持續前行
Can't stop, won't stop moving --  停不下來
It's like I got this music -- 就好像這首歌
In my mind -- 老早就在我心底
Saying, "It's gonna be alright." -- 說一切都會好轉
'Cause the players gonna play, play, play, play, play -- 因為玩咖一直玩玩玩玩
And the haters gonna hate, hate, hate, hate, hate -- 黑特一直黑黑黑黑
Baby, I'm just gonna shake, shake, shake, shake, shake -- 我只是一直搖搖搖搖
I shake it off, I shake it off -- 通通甩掉
Heart-breakers gonna break, break, break, break, break -- 劈腿族一直劈劈劈劈
And the fakers gonna fake, fake, fake, fake, fake -- 騙子一直騙騙騙騙
Baby, I'm just gonna shake, shake, shake, shake, shake -- 我只是一直搖搖搖搖
I shake it off, I shake it off -- 通通甩掉
I never miss a beat -- 我從來不掉拍
I'm lightning on my feet -- 我的腳步輕盈
And that's what they don't see, mmm-mmm -- 那是他們看不到的
That's what they don't see, mmm-mmm -- 那是他們看不到的
I'm dancing on my own (dancing on my own) -- 我繼續跳我的舞
I make the moves up as I go (moves up as I go) -- 移動我的腳步
And that's what they don't know, mmm-mmm -- 這是他們不知道的
That's what they don't know, mmm-mmm -- 這是他們不知道的
But I keep cruising   -- 但我持續前行
Can't stop, won't stop grooving -- 我停不下來，也不會停止律動
It's like I got this music -- 就好像這首歌
In my mind  -- 老早就在我心底
Saying, "It's gonna be alright." -- 說一切都會好轉
'Cause the players gonna play,play, play, play, play -- 因為玩咖一直玩玩玩玩
And the haters gonna hate, hate, hate, hate, hate  -- 黑特一直黑黑黑黑
Baby, I'm just gonna shake, shake, shake, shake, shake -- 我只是一直搖搖搖搖
I shake it off, I shake it off -- 通通甩掉
Heart-breakers gonna break, break, break, break, break  -- 劈腿族一直劈劈劈劈
And the fakers gonna fake,fake, fake, fake, fake  -- 騙子一直騙騙騙騙
Baby, I'm just gonna shake, shake, shake, shake, shake -- 我只是一直搖搖搖搖
I shake it off, I shake it off -- 通通甩掉
Shake it off, I shake it off, -- 通通甩掉
I, I, I shake it off, I shake it off, -- 通通甩掉
I, I, I shake it off, I shake it off -- 通通甩掉
Hey, hey, hey -- 嘿嘿嘿
Just think while you've been getting down and out about the liars and the dirty, dirty cheats of the world, -- 想想，當你被這個世界的謊言和極盡骯髒的騙局，搞得窮困潦倒
You could've been getting down to this sick beat. -- 你大可選擇跟著節奏熱舞
My ex-man brought his new girlfriend -- 我前男友帶著新女友
She's like "Oh, my god!" but I'm just gonna shake. -- 她滿臉ＯＭＧ  但我只想盡情搖擺
And to the fella over there with the hella good hair -- 那個頂著時尚髮型的小伙子
Won't you come on over, baby? We can shake, shake, shake -- 你何不走近一點呢 寶貝 我們可以盡情搖擺
Yeah ohhh
'Cause the players gonna play, play, play, play, play  -- 因為玩咖一直玩玩玩玩
And the haters gonna hate, hate, hate, hate, hate (haters gonna hate)  -- 黑特一直黑黑黑黑
I'm just gonna shake, shake, shake, shake, shake -- 我只想搖搖搖搖
I shake it off, I shake it off -- 通通甩掉
Heart-breakers gonna break, break, break, break, break (mmmm) -- 劈腿族一直劈劈劈劈
And the fakers gonna fake, fake, fake, fake, fake (and fake, and fake, and fake)  -- 騙子一直騙騙騙騙
Baby, I'm just gonna shake, shake, shake, shake, shake -- 我只是一直搖搖搖搖
I shake it off, I shake it off -- 通通甩掉
Shake it off, I shake it off,-- 通通甩掉
I, I, I shake it off, I shake it off,-- 通通甩掉
I, I, I shake it off, I shake it off-- 通通甩掉
Shake it off, I shake it off,-- 通通甩掉
I, I, I shake it off, I shake it off,-- 通通甩掉
I, I, I shake it off, I shake it off-- 通通甩掉
Shake it off, I shake it off,-- 通通甩掉
I, I, I shake it off, I shake it off (you've got to),-- 通通甩掉
I, I, I shake it off, I shake it off,-- 通通甩掉
I, I, I shake it off, I shake it off-- 通通甩掉
www.RentAnAdviser.com