Spreading out on a fresh green carpet -- 在新鮮的綠色地毯上展開
Snow-white fishes are swimming in the skies -- 雪白的魚兒在天空中游泳
It makes me doze off in sweetness -- 它讓我在甜蜜中打瞌睡
I close my ruby cast eyes for now -- 我現在閉上了我的紅寶石眼睛
I hear you -- 我聽見你
Run run -- 在奔跑
As fast as you can -- 用你最快的速度
You have no time to lose -- 你沒有時間可以浪費
You won’t get to anywhere -- 你不會去任何地方
You have no idea -- 你不知道
I'm not losing I'm just trying not to get there super fast -- 我沒有輸我只是盡量不要太快到達那裡
There are too many moments of happiness to just rush -- 有太多的幸福時刻 匆匆忙忙
Dwelling on the happy moments -- 沉浸在幸福的時刻
I'm going to stroll -- 我要去逛逛
One step two step -- 一步兩步
Taking every -- 把每一步
step nice and gentle -- 走得緩慢且優雅
🐰
Resting on the burgundy ground -- 在酒紅色的土地上躺著休息
Floral fishes are swimming in the lake -- 花樣的魚在湖里游泳
It makes my mind go blank and -- 它讓我的大腦一片空白
I forget where I was heading to for now -- 我忘記了我現在要去哪裡
I hear you -- 我聽到你
Run run -- 在奔跑
You will fall behind -- 你會落後
You have nothing but a dream -- 你除了夢想一無所有
You will end up losing -- 你最終會輸
You will be forgotten -- 你會被遺忘
You have no idea -- 你不知道
I'm not losing I'm just trying not to get there super fast -- 我沒有輸我只是盡量不要超快到達那裡
There are too many moments of happiness to just rush -- 有太多的幸福時刻 匆匆忙忙
Dwelling on the happy moments -- 沉浸在幸福的時刻
I'm going to stroll -- 我要去逛逛
One step two step -- 一步兩步
Taking every -- 把每一步
step nice and gentle -- 走得緩慢且優雅
I'm not losing I'm just trying not to get there super fast -- 我沒有輸我只是盡量不要超快到達那裡
There are too many moments of happiness to just rush -- 有太多的幸福時刻 匆匆忙忙
Dwelling on the happy moments -- 沉浸在幸福的時刻
I'm going to stroll -- 我要去逛逛
One step two step -- 一步兩步
Taking every -- 把每一步
step nice and gentle -- 走得緩慢且優雅
🐰