Hi, Tim here with another 925 English lesson.
In today’s lesson, we’re going to learn
how to talk about possibility.
What do I mean by “possibility?”
I mean answering questions like: will the
stock market go up?
Will you get that job you applied for?
Will your manager be in a good mood today?
Maybe?
Probably?
Or probably not?
This is how we talk about possibility.
Let’s start with “probably.”
That means you are pretty sure something will
happen.
You’re not certain.
It’s not 100%.
But you can say you’re “fairly certain
that something will happen.”
That’s like saying it’s 80 or 90 percent.
Another way of saying the same thing is “there’s
a really good chance.”
In that case, “chance” doesn’t mean
opportunity.
It means “probability.”
How about a bit of practice with these expressions
for saying something will probably happen?
Listen to each example, then repeat it for
yourself.
Ready?
Let’s get started!
• Hiro will probably take the job at our
European office.
• It seems likely that our marketing budget
will be approved.
• There’s a
really good chance we’ll beat our targets
this month.
• I’m fairly certain that we’ll pass
the safety inspection.
In one of those examples, we used the word
“likely.”
You can use this word just like “probably,”
so we can say something like “it will likely
rain.”
But it also works as an adjective.
In other words, you can say that “rain is
likely.”
So, it can be used to mean both “probably”
and “probable.”
But what about when you’re not so sure?
What if there’s a fifty percent chance of
something happening.
Maybe it will, maybe it won’t.
Well, this is when helping verbs like “might,”
“may,” or “could” are useful.
For example, “I might get the job, but I’m
not sure.”
And if you think a fact might or might not
be true, you can say “it may be that”
something is true.
For example, “it may be that we can’t
increase sales.”
That’s a way of saying “maybe we can increase
sales, but maybe we can’t.”
Let’s try these different ways of expressing
the idea of something maybe happening.
Remember to repeat the examples after you
hear them.
• Well, we might see a drop in sales next
month.
• Judy could come by this afternoon, but
I’m not sure.
• It may be that we need more office space
next year.
• There’s a 50-50 chance we can get this
contract.
Great work.
And did you hear another “chance” expression?
This time, we said there’s a fifty-fifty
chance of something happening.
In other words, there’s a 50% chance it
will, and a 50% chance it won’t.
It’s “fifty-fifty.”
So we’ve talked about probably and maybe,
but what about probably not?
There are a few ways to say that you think
something probably won’t happen.
For one, you can say that you “doubt”
it will happen.
To make it even less probable, you can say
you “seriously doubt” it will happen.
You might also say “I don’t think we can
count” on it happening.
That’s just like saying you doubt it will
happen.
We also have an adjective that is the opposite
of likely, and that’s “unlikely.”
And for extra emphasis, you can say something
is “highly unlikely.”
But here’s one tricky thing: you can say
“it will likely rain” but you can’t
say “it will unlikely rain.”
That word “unlikely” is only an adjective,
not an adverb.
So you can say “rain is highly unlikely.”
How about some more practice?
Let’s try these ways of saying “probably
not.”
Once again, repeat the examples after you
hear them.
• I seriously doubt Dan will want to come
work for us.
• Finishing the project by May is highly
unlikely.
• There’s very little chance that the
delivery will be here by noon.
• I don’t think we can count on nice weather
for the event.
Did you notice the “chance” expression
in those examples?
This time, we said “there’s very little
chance” of something.
That just means it probably won’t happen.
All right, we’ve practiced some useful ways
of talking about possibility, but we should
really hear how this sounds in a conversation.
Let’s listen to a short dialog between Jane
and Robert.
They are talking about the possibility of
their company moving to another city.
Let’s listen.
Jane: I hear we might be moving to Chicago.
Robert: Actually, I seriously doubt we’ll
do that.
Jane: Oh really?
What have you heard?
Robert: Well, it seems likely that we’ll
move to Cleveland instead.
Can you hear the possibility expressions?
Jane starts by saying they “might” move
to Chicago.
But Robert “seriously doubts” that will
happen.
Instead, he says it “seems likely” that
they’ll move to Cleveland.
Now it’s your turn to practice.
We’ll repeat the dialog, but this time we’re
going to beep out the second speaker’s words.
You have to say those parts yourself.
Remember to start by saying you seriously
doubt what Jane says.
Then say it seems likely you’ll move to
Cleveland.
Ready?
Here we go:
Jane: I hear we might be moving to Chicago.
Robert: Actually, I seriously doubt we’ll
do that.
Jane: Oh really?
What have you heard?
Robert: Well, it seems likely that we’ll
move to Cleveland instead.
All right, that’s all for today’s lesson!
We’ve learned some useful ways of talking
about possibility, and saying whether you
think something will happen or not.
We’ll be back soon with some more useful
English expressions.
Until then, so long and happy learning.