business skills 360 the podcast that
looks at the other side of business English
hello and welcome back to the
skills 360 podcast I'm your host Tim
Simmons and today I want to look at how
to prepare for an interview in English
when I say prepare I'm not talking about
making an appointment at the hair salon
or picking out a clean shirt I'm talking
about doing some research anticipating
what you'll be asked and practicing how
to respond yeah I know I'm always going
on about preparation but this time it's
not just a suggestion it's essential if
you do it right you'll be able to head
into the interview feeling relaxed and
confident and that will increase your
chances of landing the job now here's
the thing most interviews cover the same
basic territory sure you might get a
couple of curveballs but for the most
part you can predict what questions
you'll be asked and that means you can
plan your answers I don't mean script
your answers it's pretty tough to appear
authentic and natural while delivering a
memorized response but you can outline
your answers and practice your delivery
so how do we go about doing that well
let's start by talking about how to
introduce yourself in an interview in
English the old tell me about yourself
question it's a
amazing how many people are thrown by
this question or fumble through an
awkward response as they wait for the
real interview questions but first
impressions are important and you need a
good answer for tell me about yourself
my advice is to keep it succinct instead
of rambling on keep it professional but
show passion and keep it positive and if
you need a formula try present past
future how does that work check out this
example I'm currently a marketing
manager with a medium-sized software
firm since I was young I've loved
writing and design and all things tech
so in university marketing felt like the
perfect fit and I went straight from
college to IBM where I worked for five
years I'm happy with what I've
accomplished but I'm really looking for
a new challenge now and I love what you
guys are doing in that example you heard
me mention my current position my
educational and work background and the
change I want in the future if you
master your tell me about yourself
pitch you can practice responding to the
next most common English interview
question what are your strengths first a
don't don't give them a laundry list of
random skills like well I'm good at
communication organizing teamwork and I
take the initiative all the time
that's totally forgettable instead
choose two or three important strengths
that relate directly to the position
you're applying for
choose ones that will set you apart from
others and give some evidence so if
you're applying for a marketing manager
position you might say people tell me
that I'm a creative manager I can
motivate a team and make people feel
appreciated for example our team
recently tackled a tough project for a
really demanding client and did you
notice that I said people tell me that
I'm a creative manager it's not just
your opinion you're telling them that
other people think so too
now I wouldn't necessarily take the same
approach to the next type of question
you're bound to face and which you
probably dread answering the what are
your weaknesses question yes you're sure
to get this question in a job interview
so you'd better be ready for it three
bits of advice first don't choose
something that's actually a strength I'm
talking about the old well sometimes I'm
too much of a perfectionist they've
heard that before it doesn't fly anymore
secondly choose something that isn't
central to the position you're applying
for thirdly talk about how you've worked
to improve this weakness let's say
you're applying for a marketing manager
position and you're asked about a
weakness you might try something like
this in the past I've struggled with
public speaking giving presentations to
large groups of people at a conference
for example is a real challenge
that said I've joined Toastmasters and
I've been working hard to develop more
confidence with this other good
weaknesses to talk about being patient
when working on a team
delegating responsibilities giving
feedback or analyzing data if one of
those isn't central to the role it could
be a good one to mention all right how
about a quick recap of these tips first
practice a good response - tell me about
yourself that's professional passionate
positive and succinct second talk about
strengths that are related to the job
and set you apart from others and third
talk about a weakness that doesn't blow
up your chances of getting the position
and that you've worked to improve that's
all for today if you'd like to test
yourself on what we've just covered have
a look at the business English pod
dot-com website
there you'll find a quiz about today's
show as well as a PDF transcript so long
and see you again soon