You're listening to business English Pod the business English podcast for professionals on the move.
Welcome back to business English Pod
My name is Edwin and I'll be your host for this episode
In which we're going to take another look at one of our most popular and important podcasts
Today, we're talking about using the telephone. This is something we all do but we don't all do well
Talking on the telephone has become an extremely important part of business
You need to be able to answer a call professionally and create a good image of yourself and your company with only your voice
Having effective telephone skills leaves a good impression on your customers clients and colleagues
People are busy, so you want to be very clear polite and organized in
This lesson we'll begin by looking at a bad example of answering a call and taking a message
We'll discuss. Why it's a bad example, and then we'll go into a good example of answering a call
[I'm] sure you'll see a clear difference
before we listen
Let's talk a bit about the basics of handling a call our tone of voice needs to be pleasant and positive
We don't want to make people feel like they are bothering us
Some people try smiling when they speak even though the other person can't see them this trick helps to maintain a good tone
Second we should always be prepared whether you're receiving or making a call you need to be ready
We also need to make it clear from the beginning who the person is talking to
This means identifying ourselves and our company
From there we need to leave the conversation and find out how we can help the caller
the caller should not have to ask for help [and]
Finally we need to remember that listening is half of the conversation
We need to listen and respond to what the other person is saying
For our bad example. We'll listen as Justin an employee with drove, Esco calls a shipping company called Dane line
Just is hoping to speak with sylvie peterson, but it is a receptionist named amy who answers the phone?
As you listen try to answer these questions
One how [would] you describe amy's attitude?
To does Justin seem prepared
Hello, hi, who's this? Amy is this dane line? Yes? What can I do for you?
Hi, yes
just a second there ah
There it is may I speak to Sylvie Peterson
Sylvie
Sorry, she's not [here]. Can't leave a message sure go ahead um
Let's see my name is Justin Thomas. I'm with Travis co it's about the construction schedule for 2008 ah
And my number is wait a second 3 9 0 9 - 9 - 107
Sorry could you say [that] again? I'm looking for a pen which part all of it, okay
[what's] your [name]?
This is not the way that a business telephone call should usually go neither amy or Justin did a very good job did they?
So what exactly is the problem? We know the basics of what makes a good call?
So what is wrong with Amy and Justin?
Hello, hi, who's this? Amy is this dane line? Yes? What can I do for you?
Let's begin with how amy answers the phone
She simply says hello that may be what you say when you answer your telephone at home, but it's not okay in a business setting
Amy doesn't say her name or her company's name. She also doesn't ask how she can help the caller and
Listen to her voice is it Pleasant does it make the caller feel good of the interaction?
Think about the impression this makes
Justin has to ask who is answering the call and make sure that it is actually the right company
Remember the person who answers the phone should make it clear who the person is calling?
Finally amy asks the caller what she can do
Hi, yes, just a second there
There it is may I speak to silby Peterson
Sylvie
Sorry, she's not [here]. Can't leave a message
Justin has to ask who is answering the call and make sure that it is actually the right company
He's really not prepared for this call and has to take a moment to figure out who he actually wants to speak with of
Course Amy should put Justin on hold while she looks for Sylvie Peterson
But she doesn't she just puts the phone down and calls out sylvie
Again, this is something [that] might happen at home, but should definitely not happen at work
notice too [that] it is Justin who asks if he can leave a message that something amy should have asked and
How does she handle it?
Sure, go ahead um
Let's see my name is Justin Thomas. I'm with Travis co it's about the construction schedule for 2008 [ah]
And my number is wait a second 3 9 0 9 - 9 - 107
Sorry could you say that again? I'm looking for a pen
Neither speaker is really prepared
Justin's not sure of his own number and amy doesn't have a pen handy even though she told Justin to go ahead with his message
Amy really needs to be better prepared and be a better listener
Now let's leave the bad example behind
You've seen quite clearly what we should not do
We'll listen to a good example of answering a call. This time. We'll hear mark rand who has replaced Justin
Mark is calling line and amy has obviously received some telephone training
As you listen try to answer these questions
One what information does amy include in her first sentence?
- how does Mark Ran to introduce himself?
Hello, Daneline. This is amy. How may I help you hi. Amy my name is [Mark], [Rand]
I'm calling for Sylvie Peterson, just a moment, please all right
Thanks for holding
This sounds a lot different from the bad example doesn't it?
Mark and Amy accomplish as [much] in two lines as Justin and amy didn't six
First [amy] answered the phone very professionally
Hello, Daneline. This is amy. How may I help you
In this simple sentence [amy] has included the four important parts of answering the phone
the greeting her company name
her name and
an offer of help
The greeting doesn't always have to be hello. There are several other things you can say
Hello
Hi
Good morning
Good afternoon
Good day
Hi is slightly more informal than the others, but it is still acceptable in some contexts
Second you should say the name of your company
It's not really necessary to say this is before the name just the name is enough
You may also want to identify your department for example you can say sales department or just sales
Next say your name
Amy says this is amy notice that she doesn't say I am amy which is never used on the telephone and
Remember that we don't say this is in other situations like when we're answering a door or introducing [ourselves] face to face
How else can we say our name on the telephone?
My name is Sebastian
This is Ray Turner
pat here
Finally you should make an offer to help like this
How can I help you?
What can I do for you?
These are the four parts of a standard telephone greeting in North America in some situations
We might omit certain parts or leave them out for [example] if we know that this is an internal call
I mean from inside your own company, then you might just say your name and department
Still many companies expect the four part greeting at all times
And if you're not sure whether the call is external or internal
Remember that it's always better to be too formal than too informal
Why don't we practice this four part greasing?
You will hear a prompt
Use the ideas in the prompt to practice the four part greeting
morning Dave dixon construction help
Example answer good morning. This is Dave at [Dickson] construction. How can I help you?
Okay, what happens after [amy] answers the phone?
Hi, Amy, my name is Mark Ran. I'm calling for Sylvie Peterson
Mark starts with a very nice personal greeting for Amy
Then he gives his own name if you are the caller, and you know the person you [are] calling you can use this is
But if we've never met before it's best to use my name is for your introduction in
This case you could also mention the company you work for but it's not necessary
Mark then states the purpose of his call he wants to talk to sylvie Peterson, and he uses the expression
I'm calling for
What are some other ways that we can ask for a person on the telephone?
may I speak to Benedict struck
His Arnold there
Yes, I'm calling to speak to [Ravi] Montero
Now amy needs to check where the [sylvie] is available and to do this she puts mark on hold
Just a moment, please all right
There are a couple of other ways that amy could have done this
Could you hold please?
Would you mind holding please?
don't forget to actually listen for the caller's answer when you ask if the person can hold
Mark says all [right] and waits to find out whether Silvia is in and you'll have to wait as well