Hi Bob the Canadian here.
We’ve all lost things.
You know that time when you just can’t find
what you need.
Maybe you’ve lost your car keys, the remote
to your television, or maybe you’ve lost
your glasses or your sunglasses.
Well in this video I’ll help you learn some
English words and phrases to talk about the
things you’ve lost, and how to ask someone
to help you find them, and then what you say
when you finally do.
Hey welcome to this video if this is your
first time here don’t forget to click the
subscribe button and the bell icon below and
give me a thumbs up at some point during this
video as it helps you learn English.
So you’ve lost something.
The first thing you’re going to want to
do is you’re going to want to declare or
say what you’ve lost and the simplest way
to do that is to just say that you’ve lost
it.
So in this situation let’s say I’ve lost
my keys.
I would say, “I lost my keys.”
Maybe I’m saying it to a family member,
maybe a friend but I want to say to them,
“I lost my keys.”
You could also say, “I can’t find my keys.”
“I can’t seem to find my keys.” or maybe
you just want to say, “I need my keys and
I don’t remember where I put them.”
All of those are great ways to just declare
or to make the statement that you have lost
your keys.
So while you’re saying that you’ve lost
your keys someone may ask what you’re doing
because you’re probably moving around the
house or apartment quite frantically as you
search for the item that you’ve lost.
So in that situation, where there’s actually
someone else who might be able to help you
find what you lost you could ask them questions.
So in English if we wanted to ask someone
to help us find something we could say, “Have
you seen my sunglasses?”
So in this situation we’re looking for our
sunglasses.
“Have you seen my sunglasses?”
Maybe you think that person put them somewhere
and you could say, “Where did you put my
sunglasses?”
Usually I lose things and then somehow I think
other people have moved them instead of admitting
that I put them in a funny spot, sometimes
I just say to someone else, “Where did you
put my sunglasses?”
You might even ask them, “Could you help
me find my sunglasses?”
That would be a much nicer thing to say to
someone.
“Hey I’ve lost my sunglasses, could you
help me find my sunglasses?”
That person may respond by saying a number
of things.
They’ll probably ask you questions to help
you remember where you put them.
They may ask questions like, “Did you look
on your desk?”
“Did you look by the front door?”
“Where did you use them last?”
That’s always a good question.
Especially with keys.
If can remember where you went last with that
vehicle sometimes it helps you remember where
you put the keys.
“Did you leave them on the kitchen counter?”
So depending on what you’ve lost the person
may try to kind of help you remember where
you’ve put them by asking you questions
like that.
Sometimes I leave my keys on the kitchen table.
Sometimes I leave my sunglasses in my vehicle,
in my van, and then I don’t remember that
I left them there the time before.
And then finally when you do find that item
it’s so fun to say, “Found them!” or
“Found it!”
Just to declare especially if someone’s
helping you that you actually found that item,
or maybe you’re by yourself and you still
want to just celebrate and say, “I found
them!
Found it!
Found them!”
Both great ways to celebrate finding something.
Well that was some English words and phrases
to help you declare or to state that you’ve
lost something.
To kind of describe what you’re looking
for, and ways to ask someone to help you nicely
and sometimes not so nicely to find what you
are looking for and some of the questions
someone may ask you in English as you’re
looking for something.
Bob the Canadian here.
Thanks for watching this video, don’t forget
to give me a like and subscribe below by clicking
the red button and the small bell icon.
This was a great video to make.
I hope it helped you as you continue to learn
English.
Don’t forget to come and find me on Facebook
and Instagram, the links are below in the
description.
I’m planning something a little bit new
for my Facebook and Instagram pages, I’d
like to help people work on pronunciation.
Bob the Canadian here.
Hope you’re having a great day, and I’ll
see you in the next video.