Hi Bob the Canadian here.
Sometimes you wanna just go outside to have
some fun.
In this video I’ll help you learn all of
the English words and phrases that you’ll
need to know to describe going outside to
have fun.
Hey welcome to this video.
If this is your first time here, don’t forget
to click the red subscribe button below and
for everyone watching if at some point during
the video you could give me a thumbs up that
would be awesome.
Thanks a lot.
So, you wanna go outside to have some fun.
One of the first things you might do outside
for fun involves two legs and two feet.
You might go for a walk.
You might go for a run, or you might go for
a hike.
If you go for a walk you will most likely
be walking on the sidewalk.
Which is kind of a concrete path along the
side of the road.
If you go for a walk you might be going to
the park.
Or you might just be going for a walk around
your own yard.
But either way, getting outside for a walk
just involves an enjoyable day appreciating
the sun and being outside for a time.
You might also be going out for a run.
And if you go for a run, you will most likely
be running in one of three places.
You might go for a run or a jog, jogging is
the same thing as running.
You might for a run along the side of the
road.
You might go for a run on a sidewalk.
Or you might have a school or other place
near you that has a track.
And you might be going for a run on a track.
I don’t usually go for runs.
I’m more of a walking kind of person.
You might also in the two foot, two leg getting
outdoors category, you might go for a hike.
A hike usually involves going to someplace
where there is a hiking trail.
Maybe when you go hiking you have special
hiking boots.
And maybe you have some walking sticks that
you take with you.
But generally hiking is done somewhere where
there’s lots of trees, where you’re out
in nature, where you’re outdoors.
And you just enjoy some time walking, hiking,
through the woods.
I in particular love hiking cause, because
usually there’s shade.
A second thing you might do if you wanna get
outdoors to have fun is go to the park.
A park is a great place to go, it’s a great
place to take kids, it’s a great place to
take your dog.
When you go to the park you can go by yourself.
You can take a blanket and just enjoy being
outside while reading a book.
Maybe with a friend you’ll take a frisbee
and you’ll play catch.
Maybe you’re even playing frisbee with your
dog.
And for sure if there is playground attached
to the park, you can take your children, you
can take your kids and they can enjoy some
time playing on the playground.
The park is a great place to go when you wanna
do something outdoors.
A third thing you might do when wanting to
get outdoors to have fun, is to go to the
beach.
The beach is a great place to go.
At the beach obviously you’ll find lots
of water to go swimming in.
You’ll find lots of sand and you’ll be
able to put your towel down, or a blanket
down on the sand and soak up some rays.
Soaking up some rays just means sitting in
the sun or laying in the sun.
You’ll be able to go swimming.
You’ll be able to just enjoy cooling off
in the water.
A lot of times in English when we go swimming
we enjoy cooling off in the water.
And then enjoying basking in the sunlight.
The beach is a great place to go.
It’s also a great place to play some football,
to play some frisbee, or to play some volleyball
if those are the kinds of sports that you
like doing at the beach.
The only thing I don’t like about the beach
is when it gets too hot.
I don’t like it when it’s super hot at
the beach.
I like it when the water’s fresh.
That means the temperature that’s not too
cold.
It’s cool enough to cool me off.
And I don’t like it if it’s too hot at
the beach, but I certainly do like going.
A fourth thing you might do outside to have
fun is to go for a ride, or a drive.
You might decide that you like biking, and
you might decide to go for a bike ride.
A bike ride is when you get out your bike,
you jump on your bike, and you pedal around
town or through some country roads to just
enjoy some time outside while cycling.
The cool part about cycling is that it allows
you to get places fairly quickly and the part
I like about cycling is that when you’re
going downhill, you don’t have to pedal.
So it’s a little easier to do for me.
You might also have a nice car.
And you want to go for a drive.
So you might go for a bike ride.
You might take out your car and go for a drive.
Going for a drive is beautiful as well, you
can enjoy the countryside, you can go to local
towns that you haven’t visited.
But sometimes it’s just enjoyable when you
want to get outside to go for a drive.
And years ago I had a motorcycle.
Going out for a ride on a motorcycle is super
fun as well.
So you might go for a ride ON a bike, you
might go for a drive IN a car, or you might
go for a ride ON a motorcycle or a motorbike.
Notice the difference there: You ride ON a
bike.
You ride IN a car.
And you ride ON a motorcycle.
The last thing, the fifth thing, that you
might do if you wanna go outside to have some
fun is to go camping.
Now this is one that I wasn’t sure I was
going to put in the video because I myself
do not like camping.
Camping is when you go to a campground and
you bring a tent and you bring all of your
camping supplies, and you basically live in
nature for a few days.
So you set up your tent.
You sleep in your tent.
You cook all of your food outside.
You probably have a fire pit where you can
cook food, and where you can sit around the
fire at night.
And you most likely will also have a picnic
table on your campsite.
So notice all of the English words I used
there: Campground is the place where you go
to camp.
Campsite is the small place where you’re
allowed to put your tent.
And picnic table, fire pit, those are all
parts of a campsite and camping.
I don’t really enjoy camping because sometimes
it’s really warm.
In Ontario Canada there’s lots of mosquitos
that buzz around and bite you.
So I’m not a big fan of mosquitos.
And sometimes it’s just nicer to be in an
air conditioned house, so I do find it kind
of funny that I’m making a video about enjoyable
things to do outside, when I don’t actually
have a lot of things myself that I enjoy to
do outside.
But there you have it.
There’s five things that you can do outside
if you like this video, don’t forget to
give a thumbs up!
And if you wanna have fun outside now you
know some of the English words and phrases
that you would need to use to be able to describe
them.
Have an enjoyable day!
Bob the Canadian here.
Learn English with Bob the Canadian.
And I’ll see you in the next video.