Hi Bob the Canadian here.
Sometimes when you know you're going to have
an English conversation, it's a good idea
to think about the things that you're going
to talk about.
One thing that's really easy to talk about
is to ask people about some of their favourite
things.
In this video I'll help you learn some English
questions and responses to be able to talk
about your favourite things and to be able
to ask people about theirs.
Hey welcome to this video, if this is your
first time here don't forget to click the
red subscribe button below, and as you watch
the video don't be afraid to leave a comment,
or to give me a thumbs up at some point along
the way.
So.
You're going to be having a conversation in
English and it's a good idea to plan some
things to talk about in advance.
One of the easiest things to plan for is to
be able to ask people about their favourite
things, and be ready to answer with your favourite
things.
So let's look at a few of them.
The first thing you might ask someone is,
"What is you favourite colour?" a faster version
of that question would be, "What's your favourite
colour?"
And in reverse someone may ask you the same
question.
What's your favourite colour?
So let's look at what my favourite colour
is.
Here's how I would answer if you asked me
that question.
Hey Bob the Canadian, what's your favourite
colour?
My favourite colour is orange.
But we shouldn't just stop there.
If you ask someone about their favourite colour,
or if someone asks you about it, you should
be able to also ask, "Why?"
and answer, "Why?"
So why is orange my favourite colour?
Well orange is my favourite colour because
when I was really little in school the teacher
was asking everyone what their favourite colour
was.
And no one was saying orange.
And I kinda felt bad.
So I said orange was my favourite colour.
As you can tell it still is today.
If you look at my thumbnails and my Youtube
channel, it's all in orange.
It's still one of my favourite colours.
Another thing when talking about favourites
that's very common to ask is, "What's your
favourite place?"
What’s your favourite place to go?
And to answer you would say, “Ah my favourite
place to go is…”
So let’s do this, let’s ask me Bob the
Canadian, what is your favourite place to
go?
Well my favourite place to go, of all things,
is nowhere.
My favourite place to go is to go home.
So when I’m somewhere else, my favourite
place is to be home.
Another thing that you can ask people about
or someone may ask you about is, “What is
your favourite food?”
What’s your favourite food?
If someone was to ask me this question I would
say my favourite food is pizza.
I have loved pizza for a very, very long time.
And if someone was to ask, “Why, Bob the
Canadian, is pizza your favourite food?”
or “Why’s pizza your favourite food?”
I would have to say when I was little kid,
again, on Friday nights my mom would make
homemade pizza.
And we would get eat homemade pizza and it
was very very very tasty.
So for my whole life I have always loved pizza.
Another thing that people may ask you about
in terms of favourites, or you may ask someone
else is, “What’s your favourite movie?
What’s your favourite T.V.
show?”
So many of us go see movies, many of us have
seen movies that we liked, we have seen movies
that we didn’t like, but sometimes there’s
movies that are our favourites.
If someone was to ask me, “Hey Bob the Canadian,
what’s your favourite movie?”
I would have to say my favourite movie is
any of the Lord of the Rings movies.
In particular, I like the very first Lord
of the Rings movie.
So if someone was to ask, “Hey Bob the Canadian,
what’s your favourite movie?”
I would say The Lord of the Rings.
Another thing that people might ask in addition
to what’s your favourite movie is, “Who
is your favourite actor of actress?”
Who’s your favourite actor Bob the Canadian?
I would have to say, my favourite actor is
Matt Damon.
Most movies that have Matt Damon in it are
movies that I have liked.
In particular I liked all of the Jason Bourne
movies, and I really liked the movie The Martian.
So Matt Damon is my favourite actor.
Why is he my favourite actor?
I think because I like action movies.
I like movies where there’s a really fast
good storyline, and usually Matt Damon is
in those kinds of movies.
The last favourite, the last question that
people might ask about your favourites is,
“Who’s your favourite person?”
And this is a tricky one, because you have
to be careful when you’re talking about
who your favourite person is.
My favourite person in the world is my wife
for obvious reasons.
I don’t think I need to give any, but people
might ask things like, “Who’s your favourite
student?”
To which I would not give an answer because
I don’t think it’s a good idea to choose
favourites among students.
If someone was to ask me, “Which of your
children is your favourite?”
I would probably just say, I would probably
just say, “I love them all equally.”
So that’s a number of questions about favourites,
and a number of answers that I’ve given
about favourites.
Your job now is to think about if you had
to answer those questions, how would you answer
them?
Bob the Canadian here.
Learn English with Bob the Canadian.
If you appreciated this video please give
me a thumbs up, if you have not yet subscribed
please click the red subscribe button below.
Leave a comment.
Leave a question below and I’ll be happy
to answer them.
And I’ll see you in the next video.