Hi Bob the Canadian here.
Let’s learn English downtown!
If this is your first time here and you’re
learning English don’t forget to click the
subscribe button down below and give me a
thumbs up at some point during this video
if it’s helping you learn English.
Hey Bob the Canadian here.
I thought that we would take some time today
to learn some English downtown.
Downtown is how we describe the parts of a
town or city where it originally started.
So this is the downtown area of my local town.
And it has a lot of things for us to look
at and along the way I’ll teach you a little
bit of English.
So this is downtown Dunnville!
So in a downtown area you’ll find sidewalks,
you’ll see a sidewalk over here.
Where the sidewalk meets the road is what
we call the curb.
So this right here is the curb.
It’s a little hard to see because of all
the snow.
And then usually on each side of the street
you’ll see what we call parking spaces or
a parking spot.
In some towns there will be a small meter,
a parking meter where you can put money in
in order to pay for the parking spot, but
in this town, yeah you can see the lines right
here, you’re allowed to park on each side
of the street for free.
So that’s kind of cool!
The parking areas that you find in a downtown
area sometimes have a sign that tells you
what the parking rules are.
So this parking spot says you can park from
8AM to 2AM but only for 2 hours.
And above that it says it’s a snow route
from November 15th to April 15th and you’re
not allowed to park there from 2AM to 8AM.
That’s to let the snow plows come through
and clear out the snow.
Another thing you’ll see in a downtown area
are storefronts.
So you can see along the other side of the
road there that there’s a number of stores
and if I turn around you can see behind me
there’s also a row of storefronts.
So storefronts usually have of course the
entrance, let me see if I can find an entrance
here, this green door is an entrance, but
they also have their front display window.
You’ll find all sorts of different stores
in a downtown area.
In this downtown there’s a music store,
there’s a sweets shop where you can buy
candies, there’s a couple of restaurants.
Across the street there’s a jewelry store,
there’s a bank, and there’s also an electronics
store.
So generally in a downtown area you can find
almost any kind of store you want.
When I look across the street I see a shoe
store, I see a drug store, and two more banks.
I guess banks are important because you can
get money to go buy something.
Another nice thing about downtown is you usually
have streetlights.
You can see along this street here there are
a few streetlights and there’s one above
me as well.
I’ll give you a closer look at it.
You can see that these streetlights are still
decorated for Christmas.
But the nice thing about a downtown is it
has streetlights, it has the storefronts,
and at night you can come down and do a little
bit of shopping because there’s lots of
light.
If you listen you can hear a bird singing.
I hope that means Spring is coming!
Another thing you’ll have downtown are places
to park your bikes or a bike rack.
So you can see here even though it’s winter
in Canada, someone still rode their bike to
the downtown area today and they have a bike
lock on it, you can see the bike lock here
attaching it to the bike rack.
So a lot of times in a downtown you’ll find
a bike rack where you can park your bike and
lock it up.
Another thing you’ll see in a downtown area
are a lot of fire hydrants.
So fire hydrants are a place where firefighters
can come with their fire truck if there’s
a fire and it’s a source of water where
they can hook up their hoses in order to fight
the fire.
So you’ll see a lot of fire hydrants in
a downtown area as well.
So because a downtown area is a place where
the town wants people to come and enjoy themselves
you usually have some park benches.
So even though we’re not in a park you can
see that there are some park benches here.
As well there will often be lots of garbage
cans.
It’s nice to keep the downtown clean so
you’ll almost always see garbage cans and
benches along the way just to create a nicer
area for people to spend time in.
So you’ll often find a mailbox in a downtown
area where you can still mail letters.
The letters go in the top here.
You can open it up, put your letters in.
By the way if you haven’t sent me a postcard
yet you still can.
My address is down in the description.
In Canada where it freezes in the winter you’ll
see a lot of this.
This is a bucket of salt or a container of
salt.
And we have that there because we put salt
down when it’s really cold and frozen and
there’s ice on the sidewalks and the salt
will actually melt the ice.
So quite often in downtown area you’ll have
businesses but above the businesses you’ll
have small apartments.
So you have stores or businesses on the bottom
level, but in these buildings the next two
levels are actually small apartments where
people live.
So you could rent an apartment and live in
the downtown area above a small business.
There’s a pigeon that lives in this town.
I’m not, I’m not sure what, I’m not
sure what he’s doing but he was up on this
roof and he just flew down here so.
In a lot of bigger cities you’ll see a lot
of pigeons.
I think ‘cause people feed them.
That would be my guess.
So the place between two buildings is called
an alley, or an alleyway, or a back alley.
So you can see there’s a building on this
side and there’s a building on this side
and this area here between the buildings is
called an alley, or alleyway, or back alley.
Here’s what this town looked like a long
time ago.
It’s kind of cool because you can see the
old cars, but a lot of the buildings are still
the same as the buildings that, that we were
just looking at.
So it’s pretty cool.
A nice old picture of the downtown.
Well hey that was a look at the downtown area
of one of my local towns.
I hope this video helped you learn some English.
I’m Bob the Canadian here.
Learn English with Bob the Canadian.
Thank you so much for watching.
Don’t forget to subscribe below if this
video helped you learn some English.
Give me a thumbs up and share this video with
a friend and I’ll see you in the next video.