Hi, Bob the Canadian here.
Let’s learn English at the park!
Hey, Bob the Canadian here.
Welcome to this video.
If this is your first time here please click
the subscribe button below and at some point
during this video give me a thumbs up!
Hi, Bob the Canadian here.
I thought today would be a great day to come
to the park.
And I’m at a park that has everything that
I would want to have at a park to be able
to do a video where I can help you learn English.
So let’s walk around and I will show you
a whole bunch of things that, that a park,
that a city park would have.
Often at a park you will find a playground.
A place for kids to come and play.
There will usually be a playground area like
this, and usually there will be swings.
I should go try one of these swings right
now, what do you think, let me just aim the
camera a little closer and let me run over
and, and let me see how this goes.
I think I’m getting too old for that.
Let’s, let’s move on to the next part
of the park.
One thing that I really like at a park is
if people keep it clean.
It’s really nice if people pick up their
garbage and put it into a proper garbage can.
This particular park has a really nice path
where if you wanted to go for a walk, or if
you wanted to go for bike ride, or if you
just wanted to go for a run.
It’s nice when a park has paths.
This particular park also, I’m not sure
if you can see them in the distance let’s
turn for a sec, actually has light poles way
over there.
You can even come here at night if you needed
to go for a run and you could do it safely.
Often times at a park you’ll also find outdoor
covered areas.
This particular covered area we would call
a gazebo in English.
It’s just really nice if it’s a really
hot sunny day or if it’s a rainy day you
can still come to the park and sit in the
gazebo.
You can bring a book, there’s some benches
where you can sit.
This is what we would call a pavilion.
Sometimes in the summer you can rent a pavilion
at the local park, and you can have a family
reunion in the pavilion.
A family reunion is when you just get together
with all of your family, and all of your extended
family, just to see how everyone’s doing
and what they’ve been up to.
Sometimes at the park the landscaping is even
more extensive.
We’re going to walk to the top of this in
a minute.
I think this is here and it’s up on a hill
so that you can watch ships go by.
I don’t think there’s a ship going by
today in the canal.
I was really hoping there would be, but we’ll
walk to the top and we’ll see what we can
see.
So I’m not sure how well you can see this,
but behind me is the actual Welland Canal.
When I was a kid every once in a while we
would come to the canal and we would wave
at all the sailors on the boats.
And it would be people from all different
countries.
People from some of your countries that would
be on huge ships.
They would come through the Welland, they
would come through the Welland Canal on their
way out to Lake Ontario, and the eventually
making their way down the St. Lawrence River
to the Atlantic Ocean.
But today, there’s no boats.
Sorry.
I was really hoping there would be a boat.
One of my favourite things at the park is
really big trees.
I just love trees that have lots of shade.
Normally if I do go to the park in the summer
I end up sitting under a tree like this one.
I’m not a big fan of really warm days and
lots of sunshine.
There’s , so, parks are cool because there’s
big trees and there’s usually lots of grass
and just lots of green, so you feel really
close to nature.
If you’re lucky, the park you’re at will
have what we call a skate park.
A skate park is a place where you can bring
your skateboard, your roller blades.
This is for much younger people.
I, Bob the Canadian does not come to the skate
park, but you can come to the skate park,
usually there’s a bunch of people here.
Today it’s kind of empty, but anyways, one
of the things you might find at a park is
a skate park.
Somebody forgot their helmet at the park.
I think I’ll just leave it here and while
I’m making the video maybe they’ll come
and pick it up.
It’s really nice if a park has restrooms,
or bathrooms, or in Canada we call them washrooms.
But sometimes you just need to go to the bathroom,
you need to use the restroom and it’s nice
if a park actually has that.
Some smaller parks don’t, but usually a
larger park like this park will have a restroom
where maybe you’re here with your family
and your little kids, it’s nice to come
to a park where you can just take them to
the bathroom.
Well, hey, that was super fun to be able to
show you what a park looks like in Canada.
I’m sure in your cities you have parks.
They probably have even more flowers, if you’re
in a warmer place.
But it was super fun to be able to show you
the park and all of the different areas here.
I’m Bob the Canadian.
You can learn English with Bob the Canadian.
Please subscribe to this channel by clicking
the subscribe button below, it’s the red
one.
Please give me a like by giving me a thumbs
up below and please do share this video.
Leave a comment.
I love comments from my viewers and I’ll
see you in the next video.