Hello, hello.
Welcome to today's live English lesson, here
on the Speak English with Vanessa YouTube
channel.
I'm Vanessa, thanks so much for taking time
out of your busy day to study English with
me.
Today I have a special advanced listening
lesson for you.
You're gonna be learning, first of all, how
you can understand fast native English.
I know a lot of you can understand me, maybe
you've been watching my English lessons for
a long time, or maybe you just joined me.
Have you ever thought why can I understand
Vanessa, but I can't understand news reporters,
or TV broadcasters, or TV shows and movies?
Well here I'm speaking with you.
We're not having a quick conversation chit-chat
back and forth.
The style of speaking is different.
Well I want to help you be able to understand
that, because that is the key to having great
friendships and communications in English
is understanding what other people are saying.
Today I'm gonna help you understand, first
of all, how to understand native English speakers,
especially when they are speaking quickly.
Second of all, we're gonna do it, we're gonna
practice this technique together.
Finally, I'm gonna help you continue to study
like this because today's lesson is just maybe
twenty, maybe thirty minutes ... it's good,
but you need to continue, so I'll help you
learn at the end of this lesson how you can
continue to study with this style, and improve
your speaking so that you can understand and
speak like a native speaker.
Thank you so much for everyone whose joining
me live today.
I see we have friends from Brazil, Dominican
Republic, Kurdistan, Syria, Mexico, Myanmar.
Thank you so much for joining me live.
Let's talk about our first point.
How in the world can you understand fast native
speakers?
Maybe you've heard some tips like you should
listen to English.
Listen, listen, listen as much as you can.
Well what happens if you just watch a TV show
in English 50 times?
Will you eventually understand it?
Maybe, but if you understand only 10%, after
you watch it 50 times will you understand
100%?
It seems like it's not the most effective
method to me.
If you watch TV shows that you feel overwhelmed
by because it's just too fast, and there's
too much going on, we need to take it back
a little bit, we need to scale down, we need
to step back and shorten the material.
Something that I often recommend to my students
is if you feel overwhelmed by a big chunk
of material, take a small piece of it.
We call these bite sized chunks.
Bite sized chunks means small, easily accessible
pieces, and study that small piece.
When you analyze a small clip from a real
conversation, you're getting the chance to
see really how native speakers talk, but in
a more accessible piece of information.
Just maybe one minute, maybe even thirty seconds
of material.
That's what we're gonna do today.
We're gonna take a look at a short clip, it's
only thirty seconds, you're gonna study it,
you're gonna listen to it, and I hope that
you'll be able to understand it by the end
of this lesson.
So I want you to get a pen and a paper, because
I want you to study today.
This is an active lesson.
Make sure you are preparing, and not just
watching me.
Make sure you are actively participating.
We are gonna be analyzing a short conversation
for idioms, phrasal verbs, sentence structure,
pronunciation.
There's a lot of natural linking that happens,
a lot of reductions that happen, and maybe
some expressions that you've never heard before.
We're gonna quickly study those together.
The four steps we're gonna follow today are,
first of all, we're gonna listen to a fast
English conversation clip like I mentioned.
Thirty seconds, twenty seconds, maybe up to
a minute.
Then we're gonna listen to a slow version
of that clip.
This version is not a natural speed, this
clip is much slower because I want you to
understand every single word.
When you listen to that slow clip you will
probably realize oh, that's what they were
saying, now I understand.
Hopefully you'll have a light bulb moment.
This expression, a light bulb moment, means
that you suddenly realize something, you suddenly
understand.
Oh, I can understand what the fast version
is saying.
When we slow it down you'll realize okay I
understand this word, and this word, and this
word, and then we'll go back to the fast version
and I hope that you'll be able to pick it
up, because while you're listening to that
fast and slow version, the third step is to
write down everything that you hear.
Because it's a short clip we're not talking
about a full movie, we're talking about just
a short clip, you'll have the chance to write
down word for word what you hear.
Then we'll listen to it again, and I want
you to check your writing with the original
transcript.
This way you can see which words you missed,
which words were more difficult for you.
Maybe there's a specific sound, or a specific
type of linking that's difficult for you.
When you study it and analyze these small
clips hopefully you will have a light bulb
moment and say aha!
I never realized that this sounds was difficult
for me, but now I know.
So you can specifically study that sound and
practice it yourself again and again.
This is just helping you to become master
of your own English learning so that you can
take charge and improve.
So we'll check your writing, and then we'll
take a lot at some clips.
If you enjoy this style of learning that we're
about to do, right now there is the 30 Day
English Listening Challenge that uses this
technique every day for 30 days.
You can study five to ten minutes every day
for 30 days.
Last year we did this twice.
There was the listening challenge pack one,
listening challenge pack two, now the listening
challenge pack three is available.
This will be available until the end of the
year, December 31st.
If you're watching this after December 31st,
you can check out the link in the description
to see when the next listening challenge will
be open.
But I hope this technique will help you in
the new year as your New Year's resolution
to improve your English.
Okay, so what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna share
my screen with you.
I'm going to show you the worksheet.
This is what I want your paper to look like.
So here we are, I'm going to quickly share
this worksheet with you ... because we're
in a live lesson sometimes it takes a moment
to switch between things.
Are you ready?
Alright, let's take a look at this worksheet.
Here we have day 30 English listening challenge
three.
This is the day 21 lesson, this is pretty
typical for all of the days.
You'll see on the worksheet, this is what
I want you to write down; Vanessa, Bruce,
Vanessa, Bruce- Bruce is the person I'm talking
with, Vanessa, Bruce.
Or you can write V, B, V, B, V, B. You'll
hear us have a conversation back and forth,
and I want you to write that down.
Let's zoom in really quick so you can take
a look at that.
I know some of you are studying on your phone,
so it's a little bit difficult to see the
small script.
This is a quick summary of what you're gonna
hear.
In this conversation Bruce explains that it's
difficult to get a job at the hospital.
Can you hear his accent from Chicago?
Bruce is from Chicago so you'll be exposed
to a slightly different accent than mine.
I want you to write down on your paper Vanessa,
Bruce, I believe it's three different times.
Vanessa, Bruce, Vanessa, Bruce, Vanessa, Bruce.
Then you'll hear us have a conversation.
Try to write down exactly what you hear.
Okay we're back, so I'm gonna let you listen
to this conversation in the fast version three
times.
Are you ready?
I want you to take a deep breath.
It might seem a little bit fast, or maybe
it won't seem fast.
If you feel like you can understand everything
I challenge you to write down exactly what
you hear, because I've found that students
who took the 30 day listening challenge course
in the past, they felt like oh I can understand
this okay but when they tried to write down
everything they were surprised that there
were quite a few words that they missed.
Maybe these are small words, but these words
are essential for really speaking naturally,
and using correct grammar.
Challenge yourself to write down exactly what
you hear.
I'm gonna switch over my microphone so that
you only hear Bruce.
You'll only just see my face, but you won't
see Bruce, you'll just hear it.
So you're gonna be testing your ears to see
if you can hear him accurately.
Alright we're gonna listen to Bruce, and we're
gonna listen to him three times.
Are you ready?
Alright, let's listen to him.
V: How did you decide to work at the hospital?
B: I’d been applying at the hospital for,
like, three years.
V: Really?
B: Super hard to get into.
Yeah.
V: Does, like, everyone want to work at the
hospital?
B: Yeah, it's one of the largest employers
in the area.
V: How did you decide to work at the hospital?
B: I’d been applying at the hospital for,
like, three years.
V: Really?
B: Super hard to get into.
Yeah.
V: Does, like, everyone want to work at the
hospital?
B: Yeah, it's one of the largest employers
in the area.
V: How did you decide to work at the hospital?
B: I’d been applying at the hospital for,
like, three years.
V: Really?
B: Super hard to get into.
Yeah.
V: Does, like, everyone want to work at the
hospital?
B: Yeah, it's one of the largest employers
in the area.
Alright, that was the fast version three different
times.
You already knew that Bruce worked at the
hospital.
He's talking about how difficult it is to
get into the hospital.
Now what we're gonna do is we're gonna listen
to the slow version three times.
This is not Bruce's voice, this is my voice
with my husband Dan's voice.
So hopefully this is a voice you might be
familiar with, or a voice that might be easier
for you to understand.
The purpose of this slow version is for you
to catch each of the little words and then
we'll go back to the fast version.
So take your notebook, take your pen, and
try to write down everything that you hear.
You can try to write it down in the comments.
You can try to write it down in your notebook.
This is a good test exercise.
Alright, let's listen to the slow version
three times.
Are you ready?
Alright, just a moment I've gotta switch over
my microphone.
Okay.
Let's get started.
V: How did you decide to work at the hospital?
B: I’d been applying at the hospital for,
like, three years.
V: Really?
B: Super hard to get into.
Yeah.
V: Does, like, everyone want to work at the
hospital?
B: Yeah, it's one of the largest employers
in the area.
V: How did you decide to work at the hospital?
B: I’d been applying at the hospital for,
like, three years.
V: Really?
B: Super hard to get into.
Yeah.
V: Does, like, everyone want to work at the
hospital?
B: Yeah, it's one of the largest employers
in the area.
V: How did you decide to work at the hospital?
B: I’d been applying at the hospital for,
like, three years.
V: Really?
B: Super hard to get into.
Yeah.
V: Does, like, everyone want to work at the
hospital?
B: Yeah, it's one of the largest employers
in the area.
Alright, how did you do?
Was it easier to understand that slow version?
Probably.
I wanna ask you a quick question.
How many years had Bruce been trying to apply
to work at the hospital?
Did you hear that number that he said?
And what was the specific phrase that he used
about the hospital?
It is one of the largest ... what did he say
there?
Did you catch every word he said?
What I'd like to do now, if you would like
to finish writing down what he said go ahead.
I'd like to show you the transcript so you
can see word for word everything that he said.
Hopefully it will help you to pick out the
words that were the most difficult for you.
Alright let's go on to the transcript.
I'm gonna share my screen with you one more
time.
Alright, here you can see the transcript.
We're gonna zoom in.
Day 21, Hospital.
You can see Vanessa, Bruce, Vanessa, Bruce,
Vanessa, Bruce.
This probably looks familiar from the worksheet
I showed you a moment ago, and maybe you wrote
that in your notebook.
We have word for word what we said.
I said, "How did you decide to work at the
hospital?"
Notice the pronunciation of this word hospital.
In American English this T changes to a D.
I want you to say that correctly, hospital.
Hospital.
Repeat with me, hospital.
Then Bruce said, "I'd been applying at the
hospital for three years."
A lot of you got that number correct, three
years, but I'm curious.
How many of you got this correct?
I'd.
What does that D stand for?
That D stands for had, I had been applying
at the hospital for three years.
Here he is using that past perfect tense,
I had been applying, and the reason why he
uses the past perfect is because in the past
it was a continual action.
It happened a lot in the past, but now something
has changed.
He is not applying anymore, and I can understand
that he's not applying anymore because he
used I had been applying.
That means that he either stopped applying
or he got a job there.
Then I continued and said, "Really?"
I'm surprised because three years is a long
time to apply for a job.
He said, "Super hard to get into."
Did you get this phrasal verb?
We'll talk about that in just a moment.
"Super hard to get into, yeah."
Then I say, "Does everyone want to work at
the hospital?"
I'm trying to find a reason why, why did it
take three years?
And he said, "Yeah, it's one of the largest
employers in the area."
Here we have that wonderful phrase, employers
in the area.
In the area.
Did you get all of this?
Maybe there were a couple of words that were
difficult for you to get.
Maybe the phrasal verb, maybe the specific
verb up here.
Let's go on to the bottom of this page where
we talk about these three red vocabulary expressions.
Every day in the 30 Day English Listening
Challenge there are three different expressions
because its useful to understand the words,
but you need to know what they mean as well.
So let's go on to the bottom of this page
and check out I had been applying, we just
talked about this.
Why he uses the past perfect tense, and then
there's the lovely phrasal verb, get into.
This mean you're accepted.
I'm trying to get into Harvard.
I'm trying to get into the school of my dreams.
I'm trying to get into the hospital because
I want to work there.
I couldn't get into my apartment because I
forgot my key.
You can see we're entering here you're accepted.
What about that final part, in the area?
This is a pretty common daily expression.
Instead of saying the hospital is one of the
largest employers in my city, or in Asheville,
which is the city where I live, he said in
the area.
This is quite a general expression to just
mean this city or region, it's not very specific,
it's a general expression.
So I hope that these three expressions help
you to gain a deeper understanding of what
he said.
This specific transcript here is quite useful
for that.
Alright, before we go on to the final step
which is re-listening to that fast version,
I want to know- how did you do?
When you look at this transcript, what words
were difficult for you?
Let me know in the comments.
Now we're gonna listen to the fast version
again three times, and we're gonna look at
the transcript at the same time.
So that you can see which words maybe were
difficult for you.
You can see exactly as he's speaking.
This is the technique I recommend using in
the 30 days English listening challenge.
Test yourself first, listen to the fast, then
the slow, then write it down and then go back
and listen to that fast version again.
See, oh I can understand more, I can really
see what he's saying.
Alright, let's listen to that fast version.
I'm gonna show you the transcript and you'll
be able to see every single word as he's speaking.
Let me share my screen one more time as we
listen to this audio.
I'm going to open the audio for you ... this
original audio.
Alright.
Okay, I'm gonna switch over ... my screen
so you can see that as well.
Alright, let's listen.
V: How did you decide to work at the hospital?
B: I’d been applying at the hospital for,
like, three years.
V: Really?
B: Super hard to get into.
Yeah.
V: Does, like, everyone want to work at the
hospital?
B: Yeah, it's one of the largest employers
in the area.
V: How did you decide to work at the hospital?
B: I’d been applying at the hospital for,
like, three years.
V: Really?
B: Super hard to get into.
Yeah.
V: Does, like, everyone want to work at the
hospital?
B: Yeah, it's one of the largest employers
in the area.
V: How did you decide to work at the hospital?
B: I’d been applying at the hospital for,
like, three years.
V: Really?
B: Super hard to get into.
Yeah.
V: Does, like, everyone want to work at the
hospital?
B: Yeah, it's one of the largest employers
in the area.
Oh, sorry about that.
I didn't turn my microphone over.
I want to know how did you do?
I hope that this will be able to test your
listening skills, but also launch you into
the real world because these listening skills
are great for having natural conversations,
having a business meeting, traveling to New
York when you want to go to the US.
But when you have those conversations you
can't say, hey stop I need to look at the
transcript, because there's not a transcript
when you're having a real conversation.
So I hope this practice time will launch you
into understanding better in those real situations,
especially if you study this every single
day for 30 days in the 30 Day English Listening
Challenge.
You'll really be able to improve those skills.
What I'd like to tell you now, is we've already
talked about how to understand, analyzing
those small clips, we've practiced this together
with Bruce's clip about the hospital, and
now finally how can you continue this?
Well I have some good news, today December
21st, 2018 until December 31st, 2018, until
the end of the year, the 30 Day Listening
Challenge pack three is available.
So you can really practice listening every
single day and test your listening skills,
but it's only gonna take five to ten minutes.
I know it's difficult to do something every
single day, so I wanted to make these lessons
accessible, bite sized chunks, ones that you
can say oh I woke up a little bit early today
before breakfast, my family's not awake yet,
I'm gonna study it.
Or, oh I need to go to bed, but I'm gonna
study this lesson real quick.
These lessons are real fast, five to ten minutes.
You saw the audio clip is not very long, so
you can study it again and again in five to
ten minutes.
Your listening will improve every day.
So what I'd like to share with you is on my
screen, I'm gonna share the inside, sneak
preview into the course so that you can see
really what each day inside the course is
gonna look like.
Okay, I'm gonna share my screen again.
Okay, this is inside the 30 Day English Listening
Challenge pack 3.
It is zero percent complete at the moment
because the course hasn't started yet.
You can see here all of these days.
Day one, day two, day three, all the way down
here, day 21 is hospital, that's what we studied,
and there are 30 days all the way down.
Let's click to the start here, because if
you join today you'll immediately gain access
to the day zero material.
Let's open here.
Here you're gonna find the course guide.
This is how to use the material.
When you're not studying in a classroom you
need some guidance as to how to use the material
because there's not a teacher present in your
house telling you do this, now do this, now
do this.
So this guide is my recommended study guide
about how to follow the lessons.
Really this is exactly what we did today.
You're listening to the original clip, you're
listening to the slow version, you're writing
it down, you're comparing it to the transcript.
Great, this is gonna take you step by step.
The next thing you'll find on this page is
a calendar.
Each time in the listening challenge I've
made this calendar so that each day when you
finish you can check, check, check.
You can check off each day, and a lot of students
who've completed the challenge said that this
was a small motivation to help them see how
many days they finished.
Oh wow, I finished 15 days already, I can
keep going.
Or it was just a motivation to say oh I didn't
check off the next day, I need to continue.
So I hope that this calendar will just motivate
you a little bit because when you complete
it you can send me an email and get a certificate
of completion.
This is an unofficial certificate, but it's
my way to thank you for your hard work, and
also for finishing all of this.
Hopefully it will help you to see that you
have certainly improved.
Let's go over to the page.
If you click the link in the description of
this YouTube video you'll go to this page.
This page is where you can join the 30 Day
English Listening Challenge.
Here you can see there's ten days, ten hours,
32 minutes, 26, 25, 24 seconds, 23 seconds
to join the pack three version of the Listening
Challenge.
You can check out some more information about
it, including some other sample lessons, some
sample information, so that you can go over
that again, and a bunch of frequently asked
questions.
How can you download them?
Yes you can download every lesson.
What's the price?
The price is $30 if you join before the end
of the new year.
Just one one-time payment, one price, $30
if you join before the new year it's $30.
The next time that the course opens it's gonna
be more expensive, so this is the special
early bird entrance into the pack three because
it's new.
The first lesson will begin on January 1st,
so on January 1st you'll begin the day one
lesson, then day two on January 2nd, day three
on January 3rd, and so on.
If you have any questions about this material,
I'll be answering them through email, in the
YouTube comments, and also next week I'll
be doing a quick live lesson again, maybe
about ten or fifteen minutes answering any
of your questions about how to use this material,
and also how you can participate.
Because every day during the month of January
you can ask me questions.
The comment section below each lesson is quite
active.
I respond to almost every single question,
every single comment, so that I can share
it with you and give you some feedback.
That's one of the benefits of having a teacher
is having some feedback.
To let you know quickly, the material in the
listening challenge, even though it is only
for 30 days, you'll have access to it forever.
So if you want to go back, maybe for you day
seven is challenging.
Well you can go back at the end of the course
and study day seven 50 times, because you'll
have access to this course for as long as
it's available.
You'll be able to go back and study it again,
and again, and again, and that's something
that's useful for the calendar.
You can circle days that are most difficult
for you, because all of these are natural
conversations with different native speakers,
do you'll be exposed to different styles of
speaking, different speeds, different accents.
These are all American English, but there's
a lot of different accents within the US,
so you'll be able to study those.
Maybe one is more difficult than another,
so you'll circle that one on the calendar,
and go back, and study it later.
If you would like to join me, click the link
in the description or at the end of this video.
I hope that you'll be able to improve your
English over the next 30 days.
This is the key to studying English really
consistently, every single day.
Thank you so much for joining me today for
this live lesson.
I hope that you learned a lot with the sample
we did in the middle of this lesson with Bruce.
I hope you improved your English, and feel
free to continue with me in the 30 Day English
Listening Challenge pack three that's open
right now, only for $30, one-time payment.
You get basically 30 lessons, one dollar per
lesson, every day in the month of January.
Thanks so much, and I'll see you again the
next time.
Bye.