Vanessa: Hi, I'm Vanessa from SpeakEnglishWithVanessa.com.
Are you ready to test your listening skills?
Let's get started.
Today, I'm gonna test your listening skills.
Do you wanna understand fast native speakers
in movies, in TV shows and in regular daily
conversations, yes.
There are countless reductions, and linking
in spoken English, so the best way to study
this is to study real conversations, and that's
what we're gonna do.
You're gonna hear five short conversations.
And for each conversation, you're gonna see
three words.
What I want you to do is, I want you to listen
carefully for which word is used in that conversation.
These conversations are all the 30 Day English
Listening Challenge, pack three, that will
come out on December 20th, 2018, so make sure
that you have downloaded my free e-book to
get some email updates about that.
We'll talk more about that next week.
Are you ready for the first conversation?
I want you to listen carefully for the world,
all right, although or almost.
Which word do you hear in the conversation?
Let's listen.
Dan: I have my own phone.
We don't share these things.
Although, for a time we did share a smartphone.
I have my own phone.
We don't share these things.
Although, for a time we did share a smartphone.
Vanessa: Which word did you hear, although,
all right, almost?
I hope that you heard the word although.
Dan used the word although to contrast to
something that he previously said.
He said that we have our own phones.
We don't share a phone.
But, in the past, we did a share a phone.
So he said, "Although, in the past we shared
a phone."
He's showing that he's contrasting between
something that's happening now and something
that used to happen before.
So, let's listen again to that quick conversation.
We're gonna listen to the key sentence, and
I want you to listen for the word although.
Dan: I have my own phone.
We don't share these things.
Although, for a time we did share a smartphone.
I have my own phone.
We don't share these things.
Although, for a time we did share a smartphone.
Vanessa: Did you hear that keyword, although?
I hope so.
Let's move on to the second conversation and
I want you to listen for three key words,
interested, eager or involved.
Which one do you hear?
Let's listen.
Faith: I was just really shy and timid, and
it was hard for my mom because she wanted
to get me involved in things.
I was just really shy and timid, and it was
hard for my mom because she wanted to get
me involved in things.
Vanessa: Which word did you hear, interested,
eager or involved?
I hope you heard the word involved.
In this conversation, Faith said this keyword,
involved, pretty quickly.
She explains that when she was younger she
was really shy, but her mom wanted to encourage
her to participate events or, we could say,
to get involved.
It means to participate in events.
I also used another word, optimum, that I
talked about in a recent vocabulary quiz here
on my YouTube channel.
You can watch it up here, if you'd like to
learn more about that word.
Let's listen to the key sentence again, and
I want you to listen for the word involved.
Faith: I was just really shy and timid, and
it was hard for my mom because she wanted
to get me involved in things.
I was just really shy and timid, and it was
hard for my mom because she wanted to get
me involved in things.
Vanessa: Did you hear that word?
I hope so.
Let's move on to conversation number three.
You're gonna be listening for one of these
three words, challenge, change or child.
Which one is in the conversation?
Let's listen.
Brad: Well, I think visiting family is a wonderful
thing, and part of what makes it so wonderful
is getting to see them change and grow every
time you see them.
Well, I think visiting family is a wonderful
thing, and part of what makes it so wonderful
is getting to see them change and grow every
time you see them.
Vanessa: Which word did you hear, challenge,
change or child?
I hope you heard the word change.
In this conversation, Brad said that he loves
to visit family occasionally.
Occasionally means, maybe three times a year,
not every day, because he enjoys seeing how
things are different each time when he sees
his family.
Things have changed each time when he sees
Let's listen to that clip one more time.
I want you to hear that keyword change, so
we'll listen to that sentence.
Brad: Well, I think visiting family is a wonderful
thing, and part of what makes it so wonderful
is getting to see them change and grow every
time you see them.
Well, I think visiting family is a wonderful
thing, and part of what makes it so wonderful
is getting to see them change and grow every
time you see them.
Vanessa: Did you hear the word change?
I hope so.
Let's go on to the fourth conversation.
We're gonna be listening for one of these
three words, teen, two or ten.
These are number related words, so listen
carefully.
So how did you start this?
Let's start at the very beginning.
How did you get into massage therapy?
Sarah: I became a massage therapist about
10 years ago.
Vanessa: So how did you start this?
Let's start at the very beginning.
How did you get into massage therapy?
Sarah: I became a massage therapist about
10 years ago.
Vanessa: Which word did you hear?
I hope you heard that Sarah has been a massage
therapist, some who gives massages, for how
many years?
10 years.
I hope you heard the word ten.
Listening for numbers is essential in conversation.
So if you'd like to practice pronouncing some
of the most difficult numbers, you can watch
this lesson which is How to Pronounce the
Top 33 Most Difficult Words.
Let's listen to that key sentence again and
see if you can hear the word ten.
So how did you start this?
Let's start at the very beginning.
How did you get into massage therapy?
Sarah: I became a massage therapist about
10 years ago.
Vanessa: So how did you start this?
Let's start at the very beginning.
How did you get into massage therapy?
Sarah: I became a massage therapist about
10 years ago.
Vanessa: Did you hear the word ten?
I hope so.
Let's move on to the fifth and final listening
quiz question, which I think is the most tricky
so listen carefully for the word especially,
specifically or special.
Let's listen.
Anna: My mom co-owned a horse for a little
while.
A lot of people go in on one together so that
you don't have to pay all of the expenses,
especially with any vet calls that might happen.
My mom co-owned a horse for a little while.
A lot of people go in on one together so that
you don't have to pay all of the expenses,
especially with any vet calls that might happen.
Vanessa: Which word did you hear?
Did you hear the word especially?
This is technically the correct word.
But in this conversation Anna uses a common
spoken reduction for the word especially.
She cuts off the E at the beginning and she
says 'specially, 'specially.
This is pretty common.
It might be a little bit tricky to hear the
first time around.
We'll listen to it again in just a moment
so that you can hear it.
Listen for 'specially.
In this conversation, Anna mentions that it's
expensive to own a horse, so sometimes multiple
people will buy one horse and they'll share
the expenses.
Let's listen to this key sentence again, and
listen for the word especially that has been
reduced to 'specially.
Anna: My mom co-owned a horse for a little
while.
A lot of people go in on one together so that
you don't have to pay all of the expenses,
especially with any vet calls that might happen.
My mom co-owned a horse for a little while.
A lot of people go in on one together so that
you don't have to pay all of the expenses,
especially with any vet calls that might happen.
Vanessa: Did you hear the word especially
or 'specially?
I hope so.
Let me know in the comments, what was your
score?
Did you get all five of these right, or maybe
you got none of them right.
Feel free to repeat this lesson as much as
you need.
If this listening quiz was a good challenge
for you, then I'm sure that the 30 Day English
Listening Challenge will help to boost your
listening skills and help you to understand
native English speakers.
What if you could understand all five of these
conversations 100%, no problem?
That'd be amazing, right?
Join me on December 20th, 2018 for the 30
Day English Listening Challenge, pack three.
Thanks so much for learning English with me
and I'll see you again next Friday for a new
lesson here on my YouTube channel.
It's gonna be a special live listening lesson,
so make sure that you subscribe, click the
bell so that you get a notification when we
have the live lesson.
Thanks so much.
I'll see you the next time, bye.
The next step is to download my free e-book,
Five Steps to Becoming a Confident English
Speaker.
You'll learn what you need to do to speak
confidently and fluently.
Don't forget to subscribe to my YouTube channel
for more free lessons.
Thanks so much, bye.