Hello, hello.
Welcome to today's live English lesson here
on the Speak English with Vanessa YouTube
Channel.
I'm so glad that you're taking time out of
your day to improve your English.
Today, I hope that you will improve your listening
skills and especially listening to fast English
speakers.
A lot of my students have told me that they
can understand me, but they can't understand
TV shows or movies or other native speaker
friends, because they talk really fast, so
today I'm going teach you a technique that
will help you to understand native English
speakers and also improve the skills step-by-step
every day.
Today, first we're going to talk about how
can you understand fast speakers, then we're
going to practice this technique together,
and then at the end, I'm going to help you
continue this style for the month of June
in the 30 Day English Listening Challenge.
We did this listening challenge in January
of 2018 with a big success.
A lot of you really enjoyed this challenge
every day, improving your listening skills,
so we're doing it again for the month of June.
At the end of this lesson, I'll give you some
more details, but if you would like to know
now, you can click the link in the description
to learn more about the 30 Day English Listening
Challenge Pack Two.
How can you understand native English speakers?
Is there a trick?
I know a lot of people think that if they
just listen a lot, if you watch Star Wars
five million times, eventually you'll understand
what they're saying.
But if you have ever tried to watch an English
TV show, if you've ever tried to watch Breaking
Bad, or Game of Thrones, or an older show
like Friends, and you understood hardly anything,
you probably felt a little bit overwhelmed
or frustrated because there's a lot of vocabulary,
a lot of expressions, and a lot of reductions
in pronunciation.
A lot of different things that you're not
used to hearing on a daily basis, so can you
really just watch these things millions of
times to understand?
Maybe you could, but it's not the most efficient
method.
If you hardly understand anything of what
you're listening to, you need to take a step
back, and use the technique that we're going
to talk about today.
And that technique is going to be analyzing
short real conversations.
When you take a real conversation, not one
of my videos ... My videos are teaching English.
I'm speaking to English learners.
But when you watch and listen to real English
conversations, you're going to hear the natural
reductions, the natural vocabulary, the natural
linking styles.
When you take short clips from conversations
like that, and analyze it, listen to it, again
and again and again, you'll start to realize,
"Oh, maybe I can understand this short segment.
I know which sounds are difficult for me,
which sounds are easy for me.
Maybe which ones are different from my native
language."
Analyzing those short clips, that is a key
to understanding long TV shows, understanding
your co-workers when they speak in a business
meeting, understanding when you call your
hotel in Florida when you're going to Disney
World.
You need to understand the receptionist on
the phone, but she's probably going to speak
fast.
This is a key to help you take your listening
skills to the next level.
Analyzing those short segments.
Of course, you can listen to Star Wars five
million times.
It's possible.
But if you want to be more efficient and understand
multiple English speakers, this is the technique
that we're going to practice today.
If you're joining me live for this lesson,
I want to thank you.
Thank you from Taiwan, Korea, Paraguay, Brazil.
Thank you so much.
If you are watching the replay, no problem.
We're going to be practicing this technique
of analyzing short real conversations today.
Make sure that you have a pen, some paper,
and be prepared to be active during this lesson,
because it's good to passively listen, but
when you're active, that's when your brain
makes those connections that it needs to really
remember these things in the future when you're
using it in the real world.
Take your pen, take your pencil, we're going
to be analyzing a clip.
Let's go to the second section, and I'm going
to tell you what we're going to be listening
to.
We're going to be doing four things.
The first thing is, we're going to listen
to a fast clip.
This is a quick conversation that I had with
my mother-in-law.
She is American.
She is a native English speaker.
She speaks quickly.
She uses natural pronunciation.
All native English speakers are able to understand
her.
But maybe for you, she speaks in a different
way than you're used to, or she speaks faster.
She speaks like you're used to hearing in
TV shows.
But it's a little fast, so the second thing
we're going to do is we're going to listen
to a slow version.
This slow version is actually going to be
the same exact conversation, but it's going
to be reduced.
It's going to be slowed down to a kind of
unnatural speed.
You might think that it's not helpful to listen
to unnatural slow conversations, but when
you hear the fast version, and then you hear
the slow version, it is going to be key.
It is going to be the key to your success
because you're going to hear every single
word and when you listen to the fast version
again, you'll realize, "Oh, I do understand
everything."
The second thing we're going to do is listen
to that slow version, and then we're going
to check your writing.
I guess the third thing is to write.
The third thing is to write exactly what you
hear.
I want you to use your pen, use your pencil.
You can write it on your phone, but there's
some studies that show when you physically
write something, you remember it better.
I recommend writing exactly what you hear,
and trying to imitate exactly that same speaking
style.
When you hear some words that maybe you don't
know, just try to write it down, and we'll
listen to the fast version a couple of times,
and then we'll go back and listen to the slow
version.
When you listen to the slow version, this
is your chance to pick up on any words that
you didn't understand in the fast version.
"Pick up on" is a great phrasal verb that
just means, "Oh, I can hear those.
I can understand it.
I can understand those little segments."
When you listen to the slow version, you'll
be able to pick up on those little details
that you might have missed in the fast version.
And when you finish writing, the fourth step
is to compare your writing with the original
transcript.
What did Margie, who's my mother-in-law, what
did Margie actually say in that conversation?
And when you can compare her speaking to what
you wrote, then you'll realize, "Aha!
This is word is always difficult for me.
Why can't I hear it?"
Or maybe you'll realize, "Oh, that's what
it sounds like in a real conversation."
When it's reduced, when it's linked together,
"Aha.
Now I can understand it."
And in the 30 Day Listening Challenge, you're
going to have these four things: The fast
version, the slow version, you're going to
write.
I'm going to give you a worksheet so that
you can write, and then a transcript so that
you can check your writing every day.
A lot of my students in the first listening
challenge in January, they said that the first
couple days were pretty tough.
It was fast.
It was a new technique, a new strategy for
them, but on the second week they noticed
a huge improvement.
All of a sudden, their ears were getting used
to hearing and they felt more comfortable.
And by the third week, the fourth week, it
just got better and better.
This is your first lesson.
This is kind of a practice technique, so if
you feel like it's too fast, "Oh, I can't
do it", be patient with yourself, try to do
this lesson a couple of times when it's finished,
and then if you would like to join the 30
Day English Listening Challenge, this is the
week when it's open, May 25th to May 31st.
You'll be able to continue to use this technique
over the month of June and you can continue
improving your listening skills.
If it is after the month of June, or after
May when you're watching this, you can just
click on the link and see when the challenge
will open again.
All right, what we're going to do now is,
I'm going to share my screen and I'm going
to show you the writing style that you can
have.
I would like to show you exactly the kind
of thing that you're going to see.
All right, here on my screen you can see 30
Day English Listening Challenge 2.
Here is the conversation outline that you're
going to see.
First, Margie is going to say something, then
I'm going to say something, then Margie, Vanessa,
Margie, Vanessa.
If you have a piece of paper right now, I
recommend writing at least M, V, M, V, M,
V. Try to write this so that you can, at least,
prepare yourself for what you're going to
hear.
This is actually day 16 of the Listening Challenge
that is open right now for $30.
This is day 16.
On June 16th, you'll have this conversation,
but I wanted to give it to you as a free sample.
You'll see here, in this conversation, Margie
describes her decision to home-school her
children.
This is a quick little summary of what you're
going to hear.
It's only going to be a couple seconds, maybe
30, 40 seconds, so we're going to listen to
the fast version a couple times.
All right.
Are you ready to listen to the fast version?
Let's listen to the fast version a couple
times.
I'm going to show it to you, or let you listen
to it three times.
You're going to hear the conversation, but
you're not going to see any words.
You're only going to see my face, so this
is really going to test your listening skills.
I'm going to turn off my microphone and I
want you to listen to this original fast audio
version.
Are you ready?
We're going to listen to it three times.
Okay.
Let's listen.
Margie: I home-schooled my children, and that
was a big thing way back when.
Vanessa: Not the norm?
Margie: Not the norm, yeah.
Vanessa: That's kind of typical of the US,
though, that people do do things differently.
Margie: Yeah.
Vanessa: Not everyone follows the same pattern.
Margie: I home-schooled my children, and that
was a big thing way back when.
Vanessa: Not the norm?
Margie: Not the norm, yeah.
Vanessa: That's kind of typical of the US,
though, that people do do things differently.
Margie: Yeah.
Vanessa: Not everyone follows the same pattern.
Margie: I home-schooled my children, and that
was a big thing way back when.
Vanessa: Not the norm?
Margie: Not the norm, yeah.
Vanessa: That's kind of typical of the US,
though, that people do do things differently.
Margie: Yeah.
Vanessa: Not everyone follows the same pattern.
Okay.
Thank you for your patience the first time.
The sound wasn't on, but the second time it
was.
I hope that you got a chance to listen to
that clip three times.
It was pretty quick.
Margie mentioned that she home-schooled her
children.
Let's listen to the slow version.
I want you to hear every single word slowly.
This version is not with Margie, it's with
me and Dan, my husband.
We're reading it really slowly.
I hope that it will be easier for you to understand,
but if you have your pen, make sure that you're
writing down everything you hear.
All right, are you ready?
I'm going to turn over my microphone.
I'm going to turn it off, and I want you to
hear the speakers, so that you can check out
exactly what you're listening to.
Okay, let's listen.
Day 16.
Typical.
Dan: I home-schooled my children, and that
was a big thing way back when.
Vanessa: Not the norm?
Dan: Not the norm.
Vanessa: Yeah.
That's kind of typical of the US though, that
people do do things differently.
Dan: Yeah.
Vanessa: Not everyone follows the same pattern.
Day 16.
Typical.
Dan: I home-schooled my children, and that
was a big thing way back when.
Vanessa: Not the norm?
Dan: Not the norm.
Vanessa: Yeah.
That's kind of typical of the US though, that
people do do things differently.
Dan: Yeah.
Vanessa: Not everyone follows the same pattern.
Day 16.
Typical.
Dan: I home-schooled my children, and that
was a big thing way back when.
Vanessa: Not the norm?
Dan: Not the norm.
Vanessa: Yeah.
That's kind of typical of the US though, that
people do do things differently.
Dan: Yeah.
Vanessa: Not everyone follows the same pattern.
All right.
We listened to the fast version three times,
actually six times, but the first three times
didn't work.
It's okay.
Then the slow version three times.
You heard Dan say what Margie was saying,
and I was saying what I was saying, but also
slower.
Did you think that the slow version was easier
for you to understand?
If you heard that fast version, and you felt,
"This is too fast", that's probably also how
you feel when you watch English TV shows or
movies, maybe when you talk on the phone with
a business client.
That same feeling of, "I can't understand
the majority of what they're saying", or,
"I don't understand these little expressions."
Well, when you're listening to the slow version,
you're going to be able to pick up on those
little details, and it's going to help you
build your fluency and build your listening
skills.
Let's go to step number four.
I hope that you were writing what you were
listening to, or at least listening closely.
We're going to take a look at the worksheet.
Actually, the transcript.
I'm going to show you the transcript.
We're going to go over the transcript.
I'm going to explain three vocabulary words,
because every day in the 30 Day Listening
Challenge, there are three vocabulary expressions
that I'll tell you more about from each clip.
Let's take a look at the transcript.
I'm going to share my screen again.
And we're going to look at exactly what was
said.
All right.
Here, you can see 30 Day English Listening
Challenge 2, The Transcripts.
Does this look familiar?
You saw on the worksheet Margie, Vanessa,
Margie, Vanessa, Margie, Vanessa.
And here we have exactly the what we said,
so I hope that as you were writing, your paper
looks similar to this.
And then, at the bottom, we have vocabulary
expressions.
Let's talk about these in just a moment.
But first, I'd like to go over the transcript.
I'm going to read this slowly, and after we
finish talking about the transcript, we're
going to go back and listen to the fast version
a couple times so you can see, "Oh, I do understand
more, and I do know what this means."
In the beginning, Margie said, "I home-schooled
my children, and that was a big thing way
back when."
I'll explain that expression in just a moment.
Then I said, "Not the norm."
And Margie repeats, "Not the norm."
I said, "Yeah, that's kind of typical of the
US, though, that people do do things differently."
Margie agrees, she says, "Yeah."
And I said, "Not everyone follows the same
pattern."
All right.
I hope that you heard something similar to
this, at least in the slow version.
Let's talk about these three vocabulary expression,
because they're essential for understanding
the meaning of this short clip.
Margie says, "Home-schooling was a big thing
way back when."
This expression "way back when" is super common.
We say this all the time to talk about an
undefined time a long time ago.
You're not saying 10 years ago.
That's specific.
Way back when is a general time a long time
ago.
Maybe you might say, "Way back when, women
didn't wear pants, they wore skirts or dresses."
This is not a specific time, but it's just
a general time a long time ago.
She said, "I home-schooled my children.
That was a big thing."
That means it wasn't common.
It was unusual way back when, so 20 years
ago when her children were younger.
I kind of repeated the idea.
"Not the norm."
The norm.
I made a video on YouTube several years ago
about the expression "the norm".
And this means normal.
It's not normal.
That wasn't normal.
We can say, casually, "Oh, that's not the
norm", or, "It is the norm."
You might say, "In my country, it is the norm
to eat dinner late.
We eat dinner at 8:00 p.m., 9:00 p.m.
It's the norm to eat dinner late."
Let me know, what is something that is the
norm in your country?
That's the second vocabulary expression that
we talk about down here.
And finally, why in the world did I say, "People
do do things differently"?
Why did I repeat do twice?
Well, this is another thing that I made a
YouTube video about quite a long time ago.
We often use do as emphasis.
If you said to me, "Vanessa, you don't like
cats?"
Well, I like cats, so I could respond, "I
do like cats."
I'm adding do before the verb.
And here, the verb happens to be do.
That's why it seems a little strange that
they're together, because we could say, "People
do things differently."
But instead, I decided to emphasize what I
was saying.
"Oh, people do do things differently."
You might add do in front of something else
that is emphasized.
All right, so those are the three vocabulary
words here.
I'm going to go back to my video for just
a moment.
Before we take a look at the fast version
and then take a look at the transcript so
you can read them and listen at the same time,
I want to let you know that every day for
the 30 Day English Listening Challenge, you're
going to get three new vocabulary expressions
like this included in the transcript.
Because, yes it's good to improve your listening
skills, but you need to know what they're
saying too.
Maybe you can understand, you can hear each
word, but can you understand it?
Can you use those expressions yourself?
Well, that's what the vocabulary is for.
And because it's such a short clip, I hope
that it will help you to repeat it a lot of
times, to be able to engrain it in your memory.
Okay.
Let's look at the transcript.
I'm going to share my screen and we're also
going to listen to the fast version a couple
times.
I want you to follow along with your eyes,
check your paper that you were writing on,
and make sure that you wrote it accurately.
And if you didn't write something accurately,
circle it.
Go back and decide, "Oh, every time that she
said and, I wrote an.
I didn't add a D. I couldn't hear that sound."
You know, for you, that's a difficult thing
to hear.
Make sure that you go back and analyze your
own difficulties with that.
Let's go ahead and listen to the fast version
together.
All right, I'm going to play it here and share
my screen.
Let's do that.
Margie: I home-schooled my children, and that
was a big thing way back when.
Vanessa: Not the norm?
Margie: Not the norm, yeah.
Vanessa: That's kind of typical of the US,
though, that people do do things differently.
Margie: Yeah.
Vanessa: Not everyone follows the same pattern.
Margie: I home-schooled my children, and that
was a big thing way back when.
Vanessa: Not the norm?
Margie: Not the norm, yeah.
Vanessa: That's kind of typical of the US,
though, that people do do things differently.
Margie: Yeah.
Vanessa: Not everyone follows the same pattern.
Margie: I home-schooled my children, and that
was a big thing way back when.
Vanessa: Not the norm?
Margie: Not the norm, yeah.
Vanessa: That's kind of typical of the US,
though, that people do do things differently.
Margie: Yeah.
Vanessa: Not everyone follows the same pattern.
All right.
How did you do?
As you saw the transcript, and you listened
to the fast version, did you hear more than
you heard the first time?
Because we listened to the slow version, we
talked about that vocabulary a little bit,
I hope that you could understand more and
it was useful for you to take that first step
in improving your listening skills.
Imagine if you studied like this for five
to 10 minutes every day for 30 days.
Your listening skills would skyrocket.
Skyrocket means improve a lot.
And this is exactly what other people who
joined the course in January told me.
They said that during the month some lessons
were more difficult, some lessons were more
easy, but by the end of the month, they felt
like they had analyzed and listened to these
short, real clips so many times, and really
dedicated themselves for 30 days so their
listening fluency improved, and the most important
thing is, feeling like you can continue that
and use it in the real world.
It's great to understand the lessons and that
short little clips, but can you take it into
the real world?
And yes, you definitely can.
That's something that you need to do no matter
where you are.
If you're using English, you're going to hear
it, so improving your listening skills is
really important.
I'm going to show you, as we continue ... If
this lesson was useful to you, I hope that
you can join me to learn like this for 30
days.
The 30 Day Listening Challenge Pack Two is
open right now.
Yesterday was the first day to join, so you
only have one week to join the 30 Day Listening
Challenge for $30.
Next time that it opens, it's going to be
a higher price and the enrollment will close
in one week, so make sure that you join before
June 1st, because on June 1st, I'm going to
send you the first lesson.
Today, we studied the ... Which one was it?
The 16th lesson.
And you're going to be able to study Day one,
two, three, four, all the way up until 30.
I'm going to take a moment to share my screen
and show you exactly what you're going to
be learning in the course.
All right.
Let's take a moment to take a look at my screen.
There's a lot going on right here, isn't there?
I'd like to show you the 30 Day English Listening
Challenge Pack Two course material.
Here, you're going to have access immediately
to day zero.
Today is day zero.
Any day before the course starts on June 1st
is day zero.
Let's take a look at the day zero material.
Welcome to the 30 Day English Listening Challenge.
You're going to find a course guide, which
is here.
This is the course guide.
A course calendar so that you can track your
progress, and also a zip file.
I know some students want to download all
of the courses on the first day, so they don't
have to keep going online to view them.
No problem.
Or you can just view them every day.
In the course guide, I give you a recommended
study guide.
But I'm going to give you a little tip.
This is exactly what we did today.
You're going to be able to download the files,
print the worksheet and the transcript, listen
to the original conversation clip two or three
times, like we did today, then you can write
exactly what you hear, listen to the slow
version, which is what we did, as well, and
then check your writing with the original
transcript, which we did.
You're welcome to also write expressions and
sentences using the special vocabulary words
every day.
That's kind of a bonus material.
You also get a calendar for the month of June.
On June 1st, I'm going to send you the first
lesson.
We studied this day 16 lesson over here, but
you're going to have access to all of these
lessons throughout the month of June.
And each day you'll have access to a new lesson.
Right now, these are not available because
June hasn't started yet, but on the first
day you'll have access to day one, the empty-nesters
lesson.
Day two, you'll have access to the free-for-all
lesson, etc, throughout the rest of the month.
If you enjoyed today's lesson, but you just
want some more details, no problem.
Let's take a look at the page that is linked
in the description below this video.
If you go to SpeakEngliswithVanessa.com, which
is my website, /listeningchallenge2, or you
can click the link in the description, you'll
see this page.
At the moment that we are making this live
lesson, there are six days, 10 hours, 26 minutes,
53, 52, 51 seconds left to join the course.
The enrollment closes on May 31st, so make
sure that you join before June 1st when the
first lesson comes out.
If you would like to learn more about the
course, I recommend taking a look at this
page.
You can see another sample conversation.
This is a sample from day one.
You can listen to it.
Listen to the fast one, the slow one, see
the worksheet, the transcript, and you'll
also see some of the bonuses; these 90 expressions,
the calendar, and at the end of the month,
I'll send you a special unofficial certificate
of completion with your name on it.
And it is only $30.
If you would like to join the course now,
it is your best deal because later, if I decide
to open this course again, for Pack Two it
will be a higher price.
At the moment, Pack One is $47, but if you
want to get both of them together, you can
get it for $60.
This is special promotion with both packs,
but you can get just Pack Two.
It's the same level, same style material,
but just different lessons.
You can get either one.
Pack One could start today if you want, or
you can have access to these lessons forever.
There's no rush.
I recommend studying them with us on June
1st, but you have access to it forever, so
if you go on vacation for a week, don't worry.
You can always come back.
There's also some frequently asked questions.
"Can I download the lessons?"
Yes, you can download them and keep them forever.
"What's the price of the challenge?"
$30, or one dollar a day.
"When will I get the first lesson?"
June 1st.
Excellent.
"What level is this?
What's the refund policy?
How should I use the course?"
You can check out all of these questions in
the link in the description below, or you're
welcome to send me an email, as well.
All right.
I hope today's lesson was useful for you,
and that you could see this technique that
will help you to improve your listening skills.
If today was pretty short for you, you'd like
to go back, no problem.
You can repeat this lesson as many times as
you would like, and in the 30 Day Listening
Challenge, I recommend five to 10 minutes
every day.
Five to 10 minutes maybe after breakfast or
before you go to bed.
Repeat the short clip a couple times.
Repeat it five times, 10 times, three times.
It's your choice.
And try to write exactly what it is.
It should be really short, so that you can
complete it successfully every day.
That's the goal.
The goal is to be able to complete it, because
at the end of the month, you'll really see
that your progress and your hard work paid
off.
Thank you so much for joining me today.
If you would like to join the 30 Day English
Listening Challenge Pack Two, there's a link
in the description, and then I'll post a link
here at the end of this video.
Thanks so much for joining me.
I hope you have a wonderful week, and I'll
see you again the next time.
Bye.