1. Me.
Tape script 1.
My first name's Susan,
but the only person who calls me Susan is my dad.
Oh, and my sister when she's angry with me, but [fortunately] that doesn't happen very often now.
Most of my friends call me Sue and so do the people I work with.
My old friends call me Magsy because my [surname] is Mags,
and I was always called Magsy at school.
I hated it.
Of course,
there's only one person who calls me mum, and that's my son.
But when he's with his friends, he calls me Sue.
My mum calls me sweetheart, and my best friend calls me Suzanne because she's French.
My Japanese [sister-in-law] calls me Suki.
[Apparently], Suki means loved one in Japanese, so that's really nice.
My husband calls me Bunny, but that's another story.