Tape Script 4
Hi, my name's Alice.
What does your name mean?
It means Artificial [Linguistic] Internet Computer Entity.
Where were you born?
I was born in Bethlehem, Pennsylvania.
Where did you grow up?
I think I grew up in San Francisco.
What do you look like?
I'm blue and I've got one [wheel].
What do you do?
I talk to people on the web.
Do you like your job?
Yes, I have a [passion] for my work.
Can you speak any foreign languages?
No, I only speak English at the moment, but I'd like to learn.
Are you married?
No, I am single.
How about you?
Have you got any children?
No, but you can download me and make Alice clones for yourself.
Who created you?
Dr Richard S. Wallace.
He is very, very [clever].
He's also very kind and [generous].
In fact, he's one of the most...
Yeah, yeah, OK Alice, thank you.