TapeScript 6
Dave Carter's my best friend.
We met when we were five years old because our parents were friends and we went to the same school.
He works in a different city now, so I only see him at weekends and during the holidays.
He's important to me because he knows me so well.
We have a really good laugh together and we enjoy the same things.
Football, clubbing, girls, the usual stuff.
When I'm feeling down or when I need to talk to somebody I can always call him.
Recently I had girlfriend problems, and he was great. He's a really good listener.
He just lets you speak and he listens.
But he isn't perfect.
He's always late for everything and he never says sorry, never.
The last time I saw him was last weekend.
We arranged to meet at four o'clock to play football and he arrived at half past six. It was nearly dark.
Oh well, nobody's perfect are they? He's still a really good mate.