2. Place.
Tape script 7. 1.
Do you like your city?
Oh yes. I feel lucky to be living in a city that's so big and exciting.
I love looking out of my apartment window, over the high-rise buildings.
What's the city centre like?
Some people say it's too noisy and crowded, but I love that.
There's always something to see and do.
We also have the most famous beach in the world, Copacabana Beach.
Then, on the other side of the city, there are beautiful mountains.
The highest one is called Corcovado, and it has the famous statue of Christ.
If you look down at the city from there, the view is spectacular.
What's the weather like?
It's great most of the time.
The only time I don't like Rio much is in the summer. It's too hot and humid.