Four.
What do you think of your city?
It is a very special place.
There is nowhere else in the world like my city.
It's so romantic.
What's the city centre like?
The buildings are beautiful and we have San Marco,
one of the most famous churches in the world.
San Marco Square is wonderful and during Carnival in February,
Venice is the best place in the world to be.
Do you like living here?
No, I really hate living here.
It's horrible.
There are too many tourists everywhere.
Oh dear.
What are the shops like?
Well, because of the tourists, the shops are too expensive
and the canals are dirty and polluted.
My city is not big enough for all these people.
Why don't they leave us in peace?