Tape script 9. Everything's wrong here.
They do everything wrong here.
They eat far too much meat and they eat it at 11pm.
Yesterday we went out to dinner at 11.30 and we had trouble getting a table.
At 1am we were still eating and the restaurant was still half full.
They smoke too many cigarettes.
They drink lots of strong coffee and a lot of wine.
They spend too many hours in the sun and they certainly don't get enough sleep.
One Saturday night we went to a disco at 2am and were surprised to see that there were only a few people on the dance floor.
Then the DJ arrived at 3am and the party began.
There are far too many cars in the cities and there's too much noise everywhere.
They do everything wrong here but the quality of life is great and people really know how to enjoy themselves.
I don't want to go home.