Hi!
Bob the Canadian here!
Let’s learn English around the house.
Come on in!
Hi, Bob the Canadian here.
Welcome to this video.
If this is your first time here don’t forget
to click the subscribe button below, and give
me a thumbs up at some point during this video
if it’s helping you learn English.
Well today we’re going to learn some English
words and phrases that you can use to describe
a house.
I just came in through the front door.
Houses generally have a front door and a back
door.
I’ll show you that one a bit later.
And I’m standing in the front entrance or
the entranceway of the house.
It’s a little warm so I’m going to take
off my coat and you’ll notice behind me
there is a coat hanger.
So I’m going to hang my coat here and I’m
going to do what we traditionally do in Canada,
and that is that I’m going to take off my
shoes.
Before we go any further though, I want to
thank Barb the Canadian for letting me use
her house today to make this video, to help
you learn English.
The front entranceway also usually has a closet
where you can hang coats and other items.
So especially in the winter when you come
into a home you might want to hang your coat
in the closet if there’s not enough room
on the coat hangers.
So you’ll notice behind me here the kitchen.
The kitchen is one of my favourite rooms in
the house.
I really like food so I really like kitchens.
You’ll notice behind me here that a kitchen
has a certain number of items.
We have the refrigerator or the fridge, where
you can keep food cold.
This fridge has a freezer on the bottom.
We also have the stove and generally we call
this part the oven, where you would bake things,
and over here we have the stove where you
would cook things.
If you look behind me here you’ll see we
have a sink, so when you’re all done making
your food and eating your food you can do
the dishes, you can wash the dishes in the
sink.
And if you look over here on the counter you’ll
notice that we have three things that you
find quite often in a kitchen.
We have a coffee maker.
We have a kettle for boiling water, and we
have a pitcher of water if you just want to
drink some water.
Up here you’ll notice that we have cupboards,
so cupboards, notice it’s not pronounced
the way it looks.
In a cupboard you’ll find things like plates
and bowls that you can use for eating.
Those are pretty loud!
And if we look over here, we’ll have what
we in Canada call a utensil drawer.
So this is drawer where you would keep spoons,
forks, and knives.
You’ll also see this area here is what we
would call the counter or the countertop.
You can use both words interchangeably.
So you might use the countertop or the counter
to prepare food.
And you’ll notice hiding over here in the
corner we have a microwave, just a small appliance
that lets you heat up food really really quickly.
So that’s the kitchen.
One of my favourite rooms.
Let’s move on to the living room.
So we’re in the living now.
The living room is the room in the home where
you will usually find chairs and sofas or
what we also call couches.
It’s the room where, when you just want
to relax, this is the room that you would
generally sit in.
Maybe you want to read a book, maybe you want
to watch tv or if we look over here you’ll
see that this living room also has a tv, a
television, where you could sit just to have
a quiet relaxing evening where you are going
to entertain yourself by reading a book, maybe
sitting and talking with friends, or watching
some television.
So that’s the living room.
Let’s look at the dining room next.
So another, another part of the house that
I really like is the dining room.
So this is a room with a table specifically
for eating meals.
So you would have breakfast, lunch, and supper
at this table in the dining room.
You can tell that Christmas is coming soon,
I’ll do a video soon about Christmas.
I think next week I’m going to a parade
and I’ll show you whole bunch of stuff about
Christmas, but this is the dining room.
We have a dining room table and we have chairs
to sit at as we would eat our meals.
So we’re in the bathroom now, and there’s
really three main parts to a bathroom.
We have a sink where you could wash your hands
so you could turn on the water and wash your
hands.
We also have, if I turn just a little bit,
behind me here we have a shower.
So you could jump in here to have a shower
maybe at the end of a long day of work, and
then we also have, I’m not gonna describe
what this is for, but we also have a toilet.
I think everyone in the world knows what this
is for and how to use it, so I’m not gonna
spend any time describing it.
But you have a toilet.
This is the toilet seat.
You have toilet paper and this is where you
would go if you felt the call of nature.
That’s the nice way of putting it.
So we’re in the upstairs of the house now,
you’ll notice that we’re in a bedroom.
So there’s a good reason why it’s called
a bedroom.
It’s because, there’s a bed!
So in a bedroom you’re going to have a bed.
You’re also going to have things that in
English we call dressers.
So if you look over here there is a dresser
and a dresser is a place where using these
drawers, this is where you would store all
of your clothes.
So in a bedroom you generally have a bed,
which is right here, and you have a dresser
where you can store stuff.
There’s also in this bedroom what we would
call night tables.
So there’s a table on each side of the bed
with a small lamp.
This is a place where you could keep a book
if you read at night before you go to bed.
You would keep it on your night stand, or
night table.
So this is a bedroom.
I’m not sure how easy this is to see, but
I’m standing in a hallway.
So a hallway is the part of the home that
connects all of the rooms together.
This room is empty.
In English we would call this a spare room.
Sometimes a spare room has an extra bed in
it.
This room is just empty so we would call this
a spare room.
I just came down these stairs and I’m now
in the basement of this house.
A basement is the part of the house that is
below ground, and many times in a home the
basement is used to store things.
It also usually has a furnace.
This is what heats the home with gas or oil
in the winter.
And a hot water heater.
This is what makes hot water for the house
as well.
And usually those types of things are found
in a basement.
So we’re here in the basement, it’s the
part that’s below ground.
I’ll just show you a window over here for
a sec so that you get a sense of where we
are.
So here’s the basement window, it’s a
little hard to see, but if you look outside
you’ll notice the we are at ground level,
or below ground level in the basement here.
So a lot of Canadian homes will also have
a garage.
A garage is a place where you can keep your
car, and a garage has a garage door which
you just saw open behind me.
As well a garage sometimes has a garage door
opener.
This is a device that’s on the ceiling of
the garage, and I’ll just show you for a
sec, this is a device that’s on the ceiling
of a garage that opens the door automatically
when you click the button in your car.
So that’s a garage door opener.
It’s a little cold to be out here with no
coat on but I just wanted to show you earlier
I mentioned the back door.
This is the back door of the house.
When you have a back door a lot of times you’ll
have a barbecue outside and then also down
here there’s just kind of a patio area.
So there’s an area where you can come out
to cook some food in the summer months when
it’s warmer.
You can come out your backdoor.
You can go down your steps, and you can use
your barbecue to cook some food.
So this is a small patio area outside the
back door.
Well, hey, thanks for joining me today to
learn some English that you can use around
a house.
Bob the Canadian.
Learn English with Bob the Canadian.
If you haven’t yet please click the subscribe
button below and the small bell icon so that
you can be notified of new videos.
Give me a thumbs up if you liked this video
and it helped you learn English, and please
do share this video with a friend or anyone
you know that is learning English.
Don’t forget as well to scroll down, there
is some bonus material in the description
below to help you practice some of the English
that you have learned in this video.
Bob the Canadian here.
Learn English with Bob the Canadian.
I hope you enjoyed this video and have a great
day!