Hi Bob the Canadian here.
Sometimes when you’re having an English
conversation you want to be able to talk about
the weather, and you probably already know
some of the basics.
You probably know how to say, “It’s sunny.”
You probably know how to say, “It’s raining.”
But in this video I’ll help you learn some
more advanced phrases to talk about the weather
in English.
Hey welcome to this video.
If this is your first time here don’t forget
to click the subscribe button below and the
bell icon, and if you don’t mind sometime
during this video, if you like it, give me
a thumbs up!
So we’re here to talk about the weather.
There’s a lot different kinds of weather.
There’s a lot of different kinds of temperatures,
and in English it’s nice to be able to talk
about all of them.
Let’s start by talking about temperature.
If you’re talking about temperature in general,
you can say things like, from hot to cold:
It is hot out!
It is warm out - a little less hot.
It is cool out.
It is cold out.
Or: It is freezing.
Notice I went from really warm to really cool.
So those are general ways to talk about the
temperature outside.
You can of course also say the exact temperature.
Today, at my place, it is six degrees celsius
outside.
You’ll wanna be able to say celsius or fahrenheit
depending on which segment of measurement
the country you are in uses.
Most places around the world, I think use
celsius.
So today there might be a high of nine degrees
later today.
If it stays sunny it will get warmer.
But let’s also talk about a few different
kinds of weather descriptions.
In my introduction I mentioned you probably
already know how to say, “It is sunny.”
You can also say: “The sun is out.”
You can also say, “The sun is bright today.
The sun is very bright today.”
And I’d like to give you examples of how
to use the past, the present, and the future.
So you could say:
Yesterday it was sunny.
Today it is sunny.
Tomorrow it is going to be sunny.
or
Tomorrow it will be sunny.
It is sunny out today.
At my place, I don’t think you can actually
see it, but it’s quite sunny out today.
A bit of the opposite of sunny is a rainy
day.
You can describe rain in a couple of ways.
You can say, “It is raining.”
or you can say, “It is a rainy day.”
Both are totally valid ways to talk about
rain.
But there’s different degrees of rain.
We could say, “It is spitting outside.”
which means very small drops, very small raindrops
are coming down.
I could say, “It’s drizzling.” which
is a little more rain than spitting.
I could say simply, “It is raining.” which
is a pretty steady rain.
Or, I could say, “It is pouring outside.”
Pouring is when the rain just comes down in
torrents.
It’s just an amazing amount of water falling
out of the sky as raindrops.
But let’s look at the past, the present,
and the future.
You could say:
Yesterday it was raining.
Today it is raining.
Tomorrow it is going to rain.
or
Tomorrow it will rain.
Rain.
Water falling out of the sky.
I actually love being outside in a nice rainstorm.
As long as it’s warm outside.
I don’t like being outside in the rain when
it’s cold.
Sometimes you have a day where there’s no
rain, but there’s lots of clouds.
So let’s talk about cloudy days.
You can say, “It is cloudy.”
In English we also say, “It is overcast.”
Overcast meaning that the clouds have covered
up the sun.
It is a cloudy day.
It is an overcast day.
Sometimes in the weather announcement they’ll
say, “It’s going to be partly cloudy.”
That means there will be some clouds in the
sky, but they won’t be completely covering
the sky, so you’ll still see some blue sky
with clouds in the sky.
We also sometimes just say, “There’s lots
of clouds.”
“There’s lots of clouds out today.”
Just indicating that it is a cloudy day by
stating that there’s clouds in the sky.
Yesterday it was cloudy.
Today it is cloudy.
Tomorrow it is going to be cloudy.
or
Tomorrow it will be cloudy.
In Canada we have another kind of weather
which some of you may have and that’s snow.
You can describe it as,”It is snowing.”
“It is a snowy day.”
And there’s a variety of different kinds
of words and phrases that go along with snow.
We have drifting snow, when the wind blows
the snow along the ground and starts to pile
it in different places.
We have snow that comes down with really big
snowflakes.
We have what we call,”packing snow” which
is snow that comes down when the temperature
is close to zero, and you’re able to pack
the snow together and build things like snowmen.
Snow’s a fun thing, I know some of you live
in countries where you never get to say, “It
is snowing outside.”
or “It is snowy.”
but let’s talk about how to say it in the
past, the present, and the future anyways.
You can say:
Yesterday it was snowing.
Today it is snowing.
and
Tomorrow it is going to snow.
or
Tomorrow it will snow.
So you notice the background changed, it was
windy.
So let’s talk about wind.
Wind is obviously when the air blows and starts
to move stuff and you can say, “It is windy.”
or you can say, “It is a windy day.”
You can say:
Yesterday it was windy.
Today it is windy.
and
Tomorrow it is going to be windy.
And we describe wind a couple of ways.
A really slow calm wind is called a breeze.
And we also describe wind when it’s really
really fast moving as it is a hard wind.
And we also describe wind by how fast it goes.
So they might say, “Tomorrow we are going
to have 80 kilometer per hour winds.”
Those are really really hard fast winds.
So,
Yesterday it was windy.
Today it is windy.
Tomorrow it is going to be windy.
Tomorrow it will be windy.
The wind.
I know there is a lot of different kinds of
weather, but this is the last time I’m going
to talk about and that is fog.
So fog is when there’s so much moisture
in the air that you can hardly see more than
a few meters in front of you.
And we describe it as saying, “It is foggy.”
We also say things like, “The fog rolled
in.”
Sometimes the fog rolls into an area.
So there’s no fog, and then the fog comes
to the area slowly, and we say the fog is
rolling in.
When fog is really really thick we describe
it as, “It’s as thick as pea soup.”
And I don’t know if you’ve ever seen pea
soup, but it’s a really really thick kind
of soup that you eat.
And when the fog is really thick we say the
fog is like pea soup.
And we also say, “Visibility is low.”
And, and usually we’re saying that because
people are going to be driving and on the
weather report they’ll say, “Fog has rolled
in, visibility is going to be low.”
Which means you’re not going to be able
to see very well.
In the past we say:
Yesterday it was foggy.
Today it is foggy.
And in the future we would say:
Tomorrow it is going to be foggy.
Or
Tomorrow it will be foggy.
Well that’s a look at some English words
and phrases to talk about the weather.
Thank you so much for watching this video.
Again if you haven’t yet subscribed, please
click the read subscribe button and click
the bell below.
Give me a thumbs up, and why don’t you leave
a comment below or a question and I’ll be
happy to answer it.
Bob the Canadian here.
Learn English with Bob the Canadian.
Why don’t you take a minute to watch another
video?
And I hope that you have a great day!