Hi Bob the Canadian here, let’s learn English
at the grocery store!
Hi Bob the Canadian here, if this is your
first time here don’t forget to click the
subscribe button below and give me a thumbs
up at some point during this video if you
enjoy it as you continue to learn English.
Well I was thinking the other day, I really
haven’t taken any of you on a field trip.
A field trip is when a teacher takes students
somewhere outside of the classroom.
Normally you would learn in a classroom, but
sometimes the teacher will take students somewhere
and that’s called a field trip.
So today I thought we would go on a field
trip to the supermarket or what we usually
call in English the grocery store.
Let me get my keys!
So in English we generally use the term, “grocery
store”.
We don’t often use the term, “supermarket”
I know supermarket is quite common in other
languages, in French we say, “supermarché”
but in English we don’t often say supermarket.
It is an English word but we usually say grocery
store.
And you could say for instance, “I have
to stop at the grocery store.”
You could say, “I need to pick up some groceries.”
You could say, “I need to go to the grocery
store.”
And you could also say, “I need to go grocery
shopping.”
So that’s pretty common.
I need to get some food, so I’m going to
go grocery shopping.
So let’s head over there!
Well we made it, I’m at my local grocery
store and I thought I would take you guys
inside and we’ll look at each section of
the grocery store and I’ll kind of tell
you what the name of the section is, and some
of the items that you can buy there.
So let’s go on inside.
One of the first things we’re gonna need
is a shopping cart otherwise known as a grocery
cart.
Let’s grab one from right here.
Now we’re ready.
The very first section of the grocery store
that you’ll see, especially in a Canadian
grocery store is the produce section.
So the produce section is the section where
you’ll find fruits, the kinds of things
that grow on trees like apples, oranges, bananas.
By the way if you are from a country that
produces bananas just a big, “THANK YOU!”
from me I love bananas.
I eat one everyday.
But yeah you can see the sign up here we’re
in the produce section so you’re gonna find
a lot of fruit.
You’re also gonna find a lot of vegetables.
You’re gonna find things like carrots and
cucumbers and broccoli and those kinds of
things.
So first section you usually see - the produce
section.
Lots of fruits.
Lots of vegetables.
Let’s move on to the deli section.
The next section you’ll usually find in
a Canadian grocery store is the deli section.
And the deli section is where you would find
what we call luncheon meat or deli meat or
sliced meat.
And this is the kind of meat that you buy
pre-sliced so that you can put them on sandwiches
or buns or subs - sub sandwiches.
So the deli section is things like ham, things
like bologna, and things like oven roasted
chicken or oven roasted turkey.
So that’s the deli section.
The next section you’ll usually find in
the grocery store is the bakery section.
The bakery section has things like loaves
of bread.
The bakery section would have fresh baked
buns, fresh baked bread, things like french
bread.
As well as yummier things to eat like cakes,
maybe muffins, and maybe croissants.
Another section you’ll find in the grocery
store is the dairy section.
The dairy section has all things that would
come from cow milk, goat’s milk, or sheep
milk.
So here you’ll find things like milk, you’ll
find things like butter, and you’ll find
things like cheese.
Another section at the grocery store is the
frozen food section.
In the frozen food section you’ll find things
like frozen pizzas.
You’ll find ice cream.
You’ll find frozen fruits and frozen vegetables.
So all of the parts of the grocery store that
we have visited are on the outside walls of
the grocery store.
Those sections are on the perimeter, the outside
walls of the store but in the inside of the
store are aisles like this and these are aisles
of things like cookies, things like bottled
juice, things like canned goods and there
is usually these really nice signs above each
aisle you can see them here that help you
know what’s in each aisle.
Well hey that was a quick tour of the grocery
store.
I hope this video was helpful for you as you
continue to learn English.
Don’t forget to like this video and if you
haven’t yet subscribed to this channel please
click the subscribe button below, I would
really appreciate it and I’ll see you in
the next video.