Hi, Bob the Canadian here.
Let’s learn English on the road!
I have to make sure I don’t get run over!
Haha!
Hey Bob the Canadian here welcome to this
video about roads, streets, and highways.
If this is your first time here don’t forget
to click the subscribe button below and the
small bell icon so that you can be notified
when I upload videos.
Give me a thumbs up if this video is helping
you learn English, and don’t forget to scroll
down into the description to look for free
bonus material to help you practice the English
that we’re going over in this video.
Well, hey, welcome to this video we’re going
to talk a little bit about roads, streets,
and highways today, and some of the things
that you will find beside them.
This road here is a paved road, that means
the surface of the road is hard and that means
that cars can go a lot faster and it’s just
easier to drive on.
And this part right here is called the shoulder
of the road, so when you pull off the road
you can go onto the shoulder of the road.
This part over here is kind of a little hard
to see is called the ditch, and the ditch
is where when it rains all the water would
run off the road into the ditch to keep the
road nice and dry.
The road behind me is what we would call a
gravel road or a dirt road.
A paved road like we saw has a hard surface.
A gravel road has all of these little stones,
I’ll hold them up to the camera.
So there’s a couple ways that you’ll know
that you need to stop when you get to the
end of a street or road.
Behind me you’ll see a stop sign.
This is a red sign with the word stop in it,
and it has eight sides, it’s an octagon.
So a stop sign is one of the ways that you
know that you need to stop your car.
So the intersection behind me here is called
a four way stop, or an all way stop.
If you can see under the stop sign here it
says, “All Way”.
What that means is that whoever stops first
at the intersection gets to go next.
So everyone needs to take turns going through
this intersection.
So another way you’ll know when to stop
is when you see a stoplight or a traffic signal.
So behind me is an intersection where two
roads cross and up here you can see that the
light just turned red.
Red lights mean stop, and green lights mean
go.
You can also see right here these white lines
are what’s called a crosswalk.
This is where if you push the button on the
pole over there, there’s a pole, and you
wait then eventually it tells you, this little
hand here will turn to a person and you can
walk.
..we have a little sign here, how’s it going!
So I’m at a railway crossing right and if
you notice right here there’s a railway
crossing light.
When that light comes on it means there’s
a train coming.
I think I’m just in time to see this.
Let’s watch the train go by.
Here it comes!
So that’s why when that light’s going
you should not cross the railroad track.
So we looked at stop signs, which tell you
that you need to stop.
But sometimes you wanna know how fast you
can go.
On the sides of the road you will see speed
limit signs which tell you how fast you can
drive your vehicle.
This is speed limit sign from a city or town
and it says you can do 50 kilometres an hour
maximum.
This is a speed limit sign from out in the
country.
It says you can 80 kilometres an hour max,
and if you go any faster you might get a ticket.
So I’m gonna let you guess what this sign
means and you can post it in the comments
below.
I’m not gonna give you any hints but if
you think you know post it below.
So sometimes along the side of the road they
want to protect things so they put up what
is called a guardrail.
A guardrail stops vehicles from going off
the road if they lose control.
So let’s say the road was really icy and
slippery and if you lost control you would
hit the guardrail first instead of that pole
that they’re trying to protect.
So this is a guardrail.
So I’m going to walk through the ditch here,
if you remember the ditch is the part on the
side of the road that the water can go into,
but we’re going to kind of jump across the
ditch here because I want to show you this
pole.
So in Canada we call these hydro poles, let
me lean back for you and you can see the hydro
wires.
In the United States they’re called utility
poles or telephone poles and the lines at
the top are usually called power lines.
Hopefully I don't get my shoe wet when I go
through the ditch this time.
Let’s see how it goes.
I think I’m gonna make it.
So behind me here you’ll see a street, a
city street, and what makes a street a little
bit different than a road is that you will
usually find a sidewalk.
This is a place for pedestrians to walk.
Pedestrians are people who are walking along
the sidewalk.
Sometimes you’ll even find a bike lane.
If you look down here you’ll see the shape
of a bike because on this road there’s a
special lane just for people who are biking.
And one of the main differences is that in
the city you’re going to always find….
I always have trouble pointing.
You’re always gonna find street lights.
So right here we have a nice street light
and there’s a few of them all along this
road.
There’s another one right here.
So this street, is well lit at night.
You noticed I just called it a road.
I think that’s because I live in the country
and it’s easier to refer to this that way.
But this is a street, it’s definitely a
street.
It is a city street.
Sidewalk.
Bike lane.
Street lights.
So behind me you can see the highway.
This is a six lane highway.
It has three lanes going in either direction.
If you look over here it’s a little hard
to see but you can see the off ramp.
The off ramp is what allows traffic to get
off the highway, and if you look over here
you can just sort of see the on ramp.
The on ramp is where you can speed up to get
on the highway.
I’m standing on what we would call an overpass.
An overpass is the road or street that goes
overtop of a highway, and below me the cars
are going under through the underpass.
It’s a lot of traffic.
Well hey, thanks for watching this video about
roads, streets, highways, and the things that
you sometimes find along them.
Bob the Canadian here.
Learn English with Bob the Canadian.
Don’t forget to subscribe by clicking the
red subscribe button below and the bell icon.
Give me a thumbs up if you liked this video.
Please share it with anyone that you know
who is learning English and be sure to check
out the bonus material in the description.
Bob the Canadian here.
Hope you’re having a good day and hope you
have good week!
See you in the next video.