Hi Bob the Canadian here!
Let’s learn English at the library!
Well hey welcome to this video if this is
your first time here and you’re learning
English don’t forget to click the subscribe
button below and the small bell notification
so that you know when new videos come out.
And if at some point during this video you
could give me a thumbs up, that would be awesome.
And one more thing, in the description below,
if you scroll down in the description there’s
actually some bonus material to help you practice
the English that you’re learning in this
video.
But hey, let’s head into the library and
learn some English.
So welcome to the library, if you’re learning
English, books are one of the best things
that you can use to help improve your English,
and libraries are really cool because they’re
free to use.
If you have a library card, here’s mine
right here, if you have a library card which
is free, you can go to your local library
and you can borrow a book.
When you first walk into a library you will
see the front desk and there will be a librarian
sitting at the front desk.
I’m not a actually a librarian but fun fact,
an interesting thing about Bob the Canadian,
my mom is actually a librarian.
Anyways the front desk is where you will bring
your books in order to check them out, or
to sign them out.
So once you’ve gone through the library
and you’ve found one or two books to read,
this is the place where you would come to
sign them out.
The librarian will have a little scanner and
they’ll “beep” the book for you.
So in English we say, “scan” or “beep”
because it makes a beeping sound.
They’ll go, “beep” and then that book
will be registered under your name as being
borrowed.
I’m not sure if you can read this right
here but it says, “Book Return”.
So this is a place where you could put a book
in if you were returning it to the library.
Maybe the librarian is not at their desk.
You could return your book by putting it in
the slot.
Sometimes when you’re going to return your
book to the library, the library’s closed.
But most libraries have a book drop off slot
on the outside of the library.
And you can put your books in here to return
them when the library is closed and you’re
not able to go inside.
So libraries have a number of different book
sections.
The section that I’m standing in front of
here is called the, “Fiction Section”.
A fiction section has books that have been
written by authors where they have made up
the story.
So they’re not true stories, they’re fictional
stories.
So if you think of books like, “The Martian”
or books like, “The Hitchhiker's Guide to
the Galaxy” they are fiction books and you
would find those books in the fiction section.
Another section that the library will have
is the, “Non-Fiction Section”.
So the non-fiction section is a great place
to get books where you’re just looking for
information.
For instance, maybe you wanted a book about
the Prime Ministers of Canada, so you would
come to the non-fiction section to find books
about information like that.
In this area you’ll also find books that
are true stories, so biographies or auto-biographies,
which are the stories of a person’s life,
stories that are true, as opposed to fiction
where the stories are not true.
So this is the non-fiction section of the
library.
So over here in this corner is what’s called
the “Reference Section” and these are
Encyclopedias.
What’s interesting with encyclopedias is
not a lot of people use them anymore.
Most people use websites like Wikipedia or
they use the internet to do their research,
but here we have a couple of encyclopedias
where you could look up information if you
needed to, but I think they’re actually
kind of old.
So another part of the reference section is
a place where you can find dictionaries.
And I wanted to show you this book shelf because
what’s really cool is right here there’s
a Japanese-English dictionary, a Chinese-English
dictionary, and a Spanish-English dictionary,
and a French-English dictionary, so sometimes
at your local library you’ll be able to
find dictionaries that will help you learn
words in different languages, or to help you
learn the English word for the language that
you speak.
Another section of the library is the “Periodicals”
or “Magazine Section” So this is an area
where you would find monthly publications.
Magazines on different topics.
If you wanted to learn about cows, if you
wanted to learn how to build things or renovate
your house this is the place where you would
come to find a magazine that would tell you
how to do that.
“..which is a monthly magazine which shows
you how to build things you would come to
the magazine…
Bob the Canadian is not very good at putting
things on the shelf.
Most libraries also have a “Kid’s Section”
where there are only children’s books, so
kids as well as adults are always welcome
to go to the library to find a book to read.
So another nice thing about the library is
that they have computers, and there’s a
couple of things that you can use these computers
for.
You can use the computer to browse the internet,
to look things up, or to check your email.
But usually you can also use the computer
at a library to look up where in the library
you can find the book that you’re looking
for.
So let’s say you knew a specific book that
you wanted to read, you could use the computer
to look that book up and it would say it’s
in this section, under this author’s name.
It’s important when you’re at the library
to remember that you’re supposed to be quiet.
Shhhh! is something that we say in English
to tell people that they’re being too noisy.
So hopefully when you’re at the library
no one says, “Shhh!” to you.
But generally in a library it’s supposed
to be a quiet place where people can study
or people can read.
So try to keep it quiet.
So often times a library will have a reading
area where you can sit and read a book, or
a magazine, or a newspaper.
You don’t always have to borrow a book to
read it, you can go to the library, you can
find a quiet place to sit and read, and you
can read a book right at the library.
If you’re in a library at a University or
College, they’ll usually have a work area
where you can study or do homework.
It’ll usually have a power outlet so you
can plug in a laptop or charge your phone,
but going to the library while you’re at
University or College can be a nice quiet
place to get some homework done.
Well, hey, thanks for coming to the library
with me to learn English.
Don’t forget there’s some bonus practice
material down below in the description, and
if you have not yet subscribed to this channel
please hit the red subscribe button below
and the bell icon so you get notifications
when I put out a new video.
If you like this video give me a thumbs up,
and please share it with a friend.
Bob the Canadian here, learn English with
Bob the Canadian.
Have a great day!