You guys love Ben Franklin videos.
They're one of the best ways for you to improve listening comprehension and
learn tricks to sound more natural when speaking English, like using specific reductions.
This January, you're getting five all new Ben Franklin videos
where we do a full analysis of real American English conversations.
Today's topic: grocery shopping.
Let's get started with this analysis.
First, the whole conversation.
I just got my first weird look.
But you know what? At the end of the day,
- it doesn't matter.
- I know.
At the end of the day, it's the students who matter.
That's right.
- Ok green beans.
- Ooo.
- Cranberries. Fresh.
- Oh yeah.
Oh, and I was hoping that we wouldn't have to buy a huge bag.
How many do we need?
Now, The analysis.
I just got my first weird look.
The words that I hear being the most stressed there are just, weird, and look.
They're a little bit longer: So I just got my first weird look.
Let's talk about the pronunciations of T here. They're interesting.
First, we have a stop T in 'got my'.
This is how we usually pronounce an ending T when the next word begins with a consonant.
Got my-- So it's not: gah my-- gah my-- with a continuous flow of sound
but it's: got my-- got-- an abrupt stop for the word, then the word 'my'.
Got my- We stopped the air in our throat and that signifies the stop T.
Got my--
Got my-- Got my-- Got my--
The other two T's are also ending T's but
now they're part of a cluster, the ST cluster
and it's very common when a T is
between two other consonants, to drop that T.
So if you look, when we link the
two words together, which we always do
with a thought group, the T's now come
between two consonants.
So we will drop them. This is so common with ST ending clusters.
When the next word begins the consonant, we drop it.
So the word 'just' is a very common word and when it is followed by a consonant word, we drop that T sound.
So instead of 'I just got' it becomes 'I just got'
Just got- The S sound right into the G.
Does this sound familiar to you?
Do you think you've heard Americans doing this?
It's really common.
Just got-
Just got- Just got- Just got my first weird look.
And for 'first weird', we pronounce that: first weird- firsts weird-
Right from the S into the W
and this helps us link the two words more smoothly,
and we always like a smooth  line in American English.
First weird look. First weird look. First weird look.
But you know what? At the end of the day, it doesn't matter.
She's speaking really quickly here:
So even though she's speaking really quickly,
some of the  syllables are a little bit longer and that's what helps make it clear to a  native listener.
Let's just look at the first sentence: But you know what?
'Know' and  'what' both a little bit longer, we have a stop T at the end of 'what'.
But you know what?
The intonation goes up at the end,
it's a yes/no question.
But you know what? But you know what? But you know what?
What about 'but' and 'you'?
She pronounces that so quickly: but you- but you-
She actually drops the T which isn't that common in general
but  in this phrase, which is pretty common,
But you know what? Or You know what?
We say that quite a bit and in a phrase
that's more common,
we tend to do even more reductions because of the familiarity.
We know that it will still be understood.
So it's very common to pronounce this phrase: But you know what?
But you- But you- But you- But you-
These two words linked together, said very quickly, become just the B sound and the schwa,
buh- buh- buh-
then the Y sound, and the schwa, a common reduction  of the word 'you'.
But you- But you- But you- But you know what?
But you know what? But you know what? But you know what? At the end of the day, it doesn't matter.
At the end of the day, it doesn't matter.
'End' a little bit longer.
At the end--
Of the day--
It doesn't ma--tter.
So those syllables are a little bit longer
which provides a little contrast with her very fast speech, her very fast  unstressed words.
And we do need this contrast of stressed and unstressed to  sound natural in American English.
So let's look at the unstressed words 'at'  and 'the'.
At the end of the day-
It's actually 'at the' and the vowel is so fast.
This can either be the whole AH vowel or it can be the schwa:
but- but- but- or at- at- at- at-
At the end of the day--
At the end of the day---
It doesn't really matter. What matters is that it said incredibly quickly.
We have a stop T so the word 'at' is cut off a little abrupt.
You stop the air in your throat
and the E here is pronounced as the EE as in she vowel
because the next word begins with a vowel or diphthong sound.
If the next word began with a consonant sound,
then it would be: the- which is what
we get here.
Here, it's pronounced as the schwa because the next sound is a consonant sound.
So we have 'the end' and 'the day'.
But of course it's not pronounced that clearly, is it?
Because this isn't an important word, so it's: at the-- at the-- at the-- at the--
at the end of the day-- at the end of the day-- at the end of the day--
'Of' and 'the' becomes: of the-- of the--
The whole word 'of' is reduced to just the schwa, which we link on to the word 'the'.
of the-- of the--  of the--
end of the day--
at the end of the day--
end of the day-- the end of the day-- end of the day--
So making these less important words
really quickly helps provide the contrast we need.
Practice that with me.
at the- at the- at the-
of the- of the- of the-
at the end of the day-- at the end of the day--
At the end of the day, it doesn't matter.
The words 'it' and 'doesn't' also said pretty quickly.
Another stop T here.
It doesn't matter.
It doesn't matter. Now I think I hear the T here being totally  dropped as well.
This is pretty common. We either drop the T or we make it sort of a nasal stop sound to signify the NT:
doesn't-- nt-- nt-- nt-- nt--
But here, I think she's just making the N sound glide right into the M sound:
doesn't matter--
And because of that  smooth connection, there's no stop.
It doesn't matter.
The word 'it' very quick stop after 'it'
but these two words are still said pretty quickly: it doesn't-- It doesn't matter.
And then the stressed syllable ah with the AH vowel in 'matter' and then we have a
flap T: matter.
- It doesn't matter.
- I know.
I know.  I know.
So I said  this at the same time she was saying doesn't matter.
I know.
It's a two-word  phrase and stress is on the word 'know'
but the pitch of the whole phrase is smooth. It's not: I know.
But it's this smooth line connecting.
I know.
It's the smooth change in pitch. This rise and fall of intonation
that makes one of the characteristics of American English.
Smooth transitions. We want the words to be linked.
We want the change in intonation to be smooth so that nothing's choppy.
I know.
I know. I know. I know.
At the end of the day--
Now here I definitely reduce the
vowel to the schwa: but at- Stop T.
At the end of the day--
Again, the whole phrase is very smooth.
At the end of the day-
with 'end' and 'day' being a little bit longer,
also having that peak in intonation.
Again, the letter E here makes the EE as in she vowel because the next word begins with a vowel sound.
And here it makes the schwa because the next word begins with a consonant.
So we have: at the-- at the end--
and then I also drop the V sound and make just the schwa.
of the--
of the-- of the-- of the--
These two words said very quickly: of the day--
At the end of the day--
At the end of the day-- At the end of the day--
At the end of the day, it's the students who matter.
It's the students who matter.
And here 'stu-' is the most stressed syllable of that phrase. Ma-- also a little stressed.
Again, we have a flap T here: matter-
It's the students who matter.
It's the- said quickly: it's the- it's the- it's the-
it's the stu-- it's the stu-- it's the stu--
Stu-- dents who-- dents who-- dents who--
Students-- Students-- Students--
Then these two syllables more quickly.
Ma-- another little stretch.
It's the students who matter. Aaahhhh--
Smooth change in intonation with peaks on the stressed syllables.
It's the students who matter.
That's right.
That's right. That's right. That's right.
The TH sound here not terribly clear.
She's not bringing the tongue tip
through the teeth for it but she's
pressing the tongue tip on the backs of
the teeth where the top and bottom teeth meet.
that's- that's- that's- that's- that's-
That's right.
It allows us to make that sound a little bit more quickly: That's right.
That's right. That's right. That's right.
Now here, we have the TS cluster into the R.
All of these sounds are  pronounced. we get ts-- and then er--
That's right. That's right.
But this is a stop T where we cut off the air,
the pitch doesn't fall down slowly.
We have an abrupt stop. Right-- right-- That's right.
Right-- right--   right--
Okay, green beans.
'Green' most stressed word in that phrase and the pitch is all smooth.
The pitch goes up, energy builds towards the stressed word, and then it falls away: beans-- afterwards.
Green beans.
While I say that, Laura says: Oooh. Oooh. Oooh.
Just a little exclamation you make when you notice something
or something's important, you want to
call attention to it or if you get
excited about something. Oooh. Look at that.
- Green beans.
- Oooh.
Cranberries.
Cranberries. Cranberries.
Stress is on the first syllable there. That's a three syllable word,
so the first syllable is 'cran' and the last two syllables are:  berries- berries- berries-
They're a little less clear, a little bit more mumbled,
that's how unstressed syllables sound.
Cranberries.
Fresh.
What do you notice about the intonation of that word?
It moves up and down.
And that is the shape of a stressed syllable.
Fresh.
We don't want flat pitches in American English.
- Fresh.
- Oh yeah.
Oh yeah.
A little unclear because my head is turned so I'm not facing the mic.
But you can still hear that the intonation is nice and smooth. Oh yeah.
Oh yeah. The words linked together. There's no separation of the two words.
Oh yeah. Oh yeah. Oh yeah.
Oh, and I was hoping--
Oh. Oh. This is like 'ooh' it's just a filler word, an exclamation: Oh. Oh.
Do you need some lip rounding for the second half of that diphthong? Oh.
Oh. Oh. And I was hoping that we wouldn't have to buy a huge bag.
And I was hoping that we wouldn't have to buy a huge bag.
Ho--. Buy a huge bag.
These are the words that I hear being the most stressed here.
The word 'and' is reduced we dropped the D: And I was-- And I was-- And I was--
And I was-- And I was-- And I was--
And in the word 'was', we reduced the vowel from
the UH as in butter to the schwa.
That just means it's said even more quickly
with less jaw drop, a little less clarity.
I was-- was-- was--  was--
And I was--
And I was-- And I was-- And I was--
So these three words a little less clear
than the stress word: ho- hoping-
Flatter in pitch, said more quickly:
And I was hoping that we wouldn't have to buy--
That we wouldn't have to buy--
What's happening here? We have: that we wouldn't have to--
and then a little bit longer on 'buy'.
So how are we saying these words so quickly?
The word 'that', we reduce the vowel to the schwa
so that we can say it more quickly. That-- that-- that--
Stop T. That we-- That we-- That we--
That we wouldn't have to--
That we wouldn't have to buy--
wouldn't have to buy--
that we--  that we--
wouldn't have to- wouldn't have to-
So again, I think I'm hearing this as a dropped T. Just an N sound going right into the H.
Wouldn't have to-
The vowel here reduces to the schwa
and when we have an ending V linking into to,
linking into the word 'to' which begins with the T,
it's often in this two-word combination to change the V sound to an F because T is unvoiced.
So this becomes unvoiced.
The V unvoiced is the F.
have to- have to- have to- have to-
Try that with me.
have to- have to--
have to-- have to-- have to--
that we wouldn't have to-
that we wouldn't have to- that we wouldn't have to- that we wouldn't have to-
What do you have to do to be able to say those words that quickly?
We have to simplify mouth movements. We have to produce some of the sounds
and the pitch doesn't change as much, it stays lower and flatter. There is not quite as much energy in the voice.
All of these things  are part of the important contrast
between stressed and unstressed syllables.
That we wouldn't have to-- That we wouldn't have to-- That we wouldn't have to buy a huge bag.
A huge bag- Uh- The schwa said very quickly.
'Huge' a little bit longer and then 'bag' has more of that up-down shape of stress.
a huge bag--
a huge bag-- a huge bag-- a huge bag-- How many do we need?
How many do we need? How- The question word.
How many do we need--
and 'need' are the most stressed there.
Many do we--
these three words are said more quickly.
How many do we-- How many do we-- How many do we--
I don't reduce anything. All of the sounds stay the same.
Some people it could happen that I would reduce 'do' to 'de': How many do we need?
Da-da- Da-da- with the schwa. That's okay.
But I actually keep the OO vowel.
What's more important here than whether or not I make that reduction is that the word is said incredibly quickly
and then it links into the word before and the word after:
many do we-
many do we- many do we-
How many do we--  How many do we--
How many do we--
And that provides a nice contrast with 'how' and 'need'.
How many do we need?
So it's long, short, short, short, long all with a smooth change in intonation.
How many do we need? How many do we need?
How many do we need?
Let's listen to the whole conversation one more time.
I just got my first weird look.
But you know what? At the end of the day,
- it doesn't matter.
- I know.
At the end of the day, it's the students who matter.
That's right.
- Ok green beans.
- Ooo.
Cranberries.
- Fresh.
- Oh yeah.
Oh, and I was hoping that we wouldn't have to buy a huge bag.
How many do we need?
That analysis is really fun and helpful, right?
Click here to see other Ben Franklin videos on my YouTube channel.
But if you're ready to go even further, even bigger,
I challenge you this January,
to start the new year off right with a new
commitment to your English Studies.
Join my online school Rachel's English Academy.
There, you will find tons of Ben Franklin speech analysis videos
just like this one that you can't get anywhere else.
They're longer, they cover more conversation,
and I add more each month.
You have to have the interest,
you have to make the time to watch the videos, to work with the audio.
Can you do this?
To help you get in the door, to help you get started,
I'm offering a discount for the month of January.
You can get the first month of the Academy for just $5.
Use the code start2018 at check out.
The fee is normally $14 a month which is a steal for what you get:
tools and support for self-study, to make a real difference in how you sound.
If you sign up and this method doesn't help you, no problem.
Just email me within 30 days and you'll get a full refund.
This is a subscription and you will be charged every month with continuous access to everything.
But you can cancel at any time.
Just email me and I will make that happen for you.
So get this deal and in 2018, get the accent you want.
More fluency, more ease in American conversation.