In this American English pronunciation video,
we’re going to go over:
&gt;&gt; Cheers [3x]
&gt;&gt; Cheers! Great to see you, HaQuyen.
&gt;&gt; Great to see you too, Rachel.
At the table, at the bar, when you’re drinking
the first round, you might want to say “cheers.”
Do this if it’s a special occasion, if you’re
with friends you don’t see often, or just
because. David and I do it at home sometimes
when we sit down to dinner on just a
regular day.
&gt;&gt; Cheers!
&gt;&gt; Cheers.
This is a one-syllable word, and it’s a
stressed word. So it will have an up-down
shape in the voice. Uh, cheers, cheers.
Start with the CH sound, ch, ch. To make the
sound, the tongue goes to the roof of the
mouth, and your lips will flare. Hold the
air, ch, and then release, ch. In this case,
release right into the EE vowel. Chee-. The
tongue tip is normally down for this vowel,
but since it was up, and needs to be back
up for the R, you don’t need to bring it
all the way down. The tongue tip doesn’t
have to touch back here. Cheer. Now the R.
The tongue should lift in the middle so it’s
lightly touching the sides of the roof of
the mouth. And the tip pulls back, it’s
not touching anything. So don’t pull back
the whole tongue, just the front. Flare the
lips a little bit. Cheers. We end with the
Z sound. But the ending voiced consonants
are weak, so it shouldn’t sound like this:
zzz. It’s more like this: ss, ss: actually,
a really light S. Cheers, s, s, s. And don’t
forget the shape. Cheers, cheers.
You might want to toast something in particular.
For example, “to summer vacation” or “Here’s
to Tom and Julie”.
So use the phrase ‘to’ or ‘here’s
to’ – and you’ll to reduce ‘to’
in both of those cases: tuh. To summer vacation.
&gt;&gt; To summer vacation.
Here’s to. Here’s to Tom and Julie!
&gt;&gt; Here’s to Tom and Julie!
The T sound plus the schwa, really fast, to,
to, to. Because it’s not the word that matters,
what matters is summer vacation. To summer
vacation!
&gt;&gt; To the road trip!
&gt;&gt; Cheers!
Try this out at your next meal! What word
do you use for cheers in your country? Let
me know in the comments below.
Be sure to sign up for my mailing list so
you can be sure to keep up with all the latest
news and videos from Rachel’s English – it’s
absolutely free. Click here or in the description
below.
That’s it, and thanks so much for using
Rachel’s English.
&gt;&gt; To summer vacation!
&gt;&gt; To summer vacation. Cheers!
&gt;&gt; Cheers!
&gt;&gt; Wait, wait. Can we do one like that?
&gt;&gt; To summer vacation.
&gt;&gt; To summer vacation!
&gt;&gt; Cheers!