In this American English pronunciation video,
I'm not going to teach you anything about
pronunciation.
This year for Christmas, I've come to my parents
house in Florida. This is where I grew up.
Here is our beautiful tree. Let me show you
some of my favorite ornaments.
This ornament is one that I gave my mother
when I was probably about 7. Um, no one in
my family is blonde, I don't think I even
had any blond friends, and I certainly didn't
have a mint green jump suit, but something
about this ornament called to me, and so I
purchased it for her.
This is my mother's favorite ornament. Many,
many years ago.
As I grew up in Florida, not
terribly far from Disney World, it's fitting
that we have a Mickey ornament.
Now, I said I wasn't going to teach you anything
about pronunciation, but there's one thing
I can't resist. Did you notice how I said
Florida, Florida. I'm from Florida, and that's
how I say that phrase, Florida, Florida. A
lot of people will pronounce that with a third
syllable in there. That's ok, Florida, Florida.
Must make sure you don't pronounce it Florida,
ee, ee, ee, we don't want that ee vowel in
that middle, unaccented syllable. Either Florida
or Florida, Florida.
Silent Night, holy night.
All is calm, all is bright.
Round yon virgin, mother and child.
Holy infant, so tender and mild.
Sleep in heavenly peace,
Sleep in heavenly peace.
From my family to you and yours, happy holidays,
and have a great 2013.
That's it, and thanks so much
for using Rachel's English.