I often talk about the use of reductions in
everyday, casual conversation. In this American
English pronunciation video, we're going to
take a look at reductions in a more formal
setting: important speeches.
Yesterday, Barack Obama was reelected as the
President of the United States. We're going
to take a look at both his speech, and his
opponent, Mitt Romney's speech, delivered
at the end of the evening.
First, the word 'wanna'. Both men used this
reduction in their speeches. 'Wanna' is a
reduction of the words 'want to'. Wanna, wanna.
It has the UH as in BUTTER vowel in the stressed
syllable, and the schwa in the unstressed
syllable. Here are 'wanna' examples from the
speeches.
&gt;&gt; I wanna thank every American who participated
in this election.
&gt;&gt; I wanna thank Paul Ryan for all that he
has done for our campaign.
&gt;&gt; I also wanna thank Ann.
I wanna, I wanna. Listen to these clips again,
repeat in the pause.
&gt;&gt; I wanna thank every American. [3x]
&gt;&gt; I wanna thank Paul Ryan. [3x]
&gt;&gt; I also wanna thank Ann. [3x]
The reduction of the word 'to' was also frequently
used. 'To' can either be reduced to 'to',
with the True T, schwa sound, or 'to', with
the Flap T/schwa sound. Let's see some examples.
&gt;&gt; The best is yet to come.
&gt;&gt; By the way, we have to fix that.
&gt;&gt; To the best campaign team.
&gt;&gt; Just for a chance to argue.
&gt;&gt; To the furniture worker's child in North
Carolina.
&gt;&gt; And his commitment to principle will continue
to contribute to the good of our nation.
To, to, listen to these clips again.
&gt;&gt; The best is yet to come. [3x]
&gt;&gt; we have to fix that. [3x]
&gt;&gt; To the best campaign team. [3x]
&gt;&gt; to argue. [3x]
&gt;&gt; To the furniture worker's child [3x]
&gt;&gt; And his commitment to principle [3x] will
continue to contribute [3x]
Also, both men reduced the word 'have' to
simply the schwa sound, uh. Mr. Obama said
'may-uh' for 'may have', and Mr. Romney said
'would-uh' for 'would have'
&gt;&gt; We may have battled fiercely
&gt;&gt; She would have been a wonderful first lady
May have, may have, would have, would have.
&gt;&gt; We may have battled fiercely [3x]
&gt;&gt; She would have been a wonderful first lady
[3x]
There were lots of other reductions in these
speeches. For example, reducing 'for' to 'fer'
&gt;&gt; But for the United States of America
&gt;&gt; I thank my sons for their tireless work.
Reducing 'can' to 'kun'.
&gt;&gt; That's what politics can be.
&gt;&gt; That can compare with what you've done.
And use of contractions:
&gt;&gt; And you've made me a better President.
&gt;&gt; Because I'm concerned about America.
Watch the speeches in full and study them.
What reductions do you notice?
That's it, and thanks so much
for using Rachel's English.