In this American English pronunciation video, you'll
come with me to the Union Square farmer's market.
Today I spent some time at the farmer's market
where I did things like buy these beautiful
flowers. The words 'farmer' and 'market' both
have the 'ah' as in 'father' vowel followed
by the R consonant. I've noticed that this
combination can be problematic for my students.
It's important to remember to make a good
'ah' vowel before moving into the R consonant.
A lot of people want to rush this, and the
two sounds end up getting combined to something
like far-, far-, instead of fah-rr, fah-rr.
So, it is true with this combination that
your tongue will probably start moving back
into the R as soon as you start the AH vowel.
But it's important to start the AH vowel with
the tongue tip forward. Far, far. And make
sure you have enough jaw drop to get the good
AH vowel. When in doubt, always practice slowly.
Ah-rr, farmer's market. Farmer's market.
The farmer's market at Union Square has some
interesting things, like hand-dyed yarn, seafood,
beautiful flowers, and sometimes, if you're
lucky, free samples.
&gt;&gt; Spicy.
&gt;&gt; Is it?
Did you hear how the intonation went up at
the end. Is it? This is true of questions
that can be answered with yes or no. In general,
other questions will go down in pitch at the
end. For example, what does it taste like?
Taste like? like? it? like? Listen again.
&gt;&gt; Is it? [3x]
&gt;&gt; Too spicy or just right?
Here the question will be answered with either
'too spicy' or 'just right'. So, not a yes/no
question. Therefore, the sentence goes down
in pitch at the end. Just right. Right, right.
Listen again.
&gt;&gt; Too spicy, or just right [3x]
&gt;&gt; Perfect.
There's also a local vendor who brings lots
of honey, and, with that, bees. After putting
honey and bees on my finger, the beekeeper
told me the only way to get them off is with
a good shake.
The farmer's market also has lots of great
baked goods, like these cider donuts.
&gt;&gt; Apple cider donuts.
&gt;&gt; Oh, yum!
&gt;&gt; Can I have some?
Can I have some? Again, a yes/no question,
so the pitch went up at the end. Some? Some?
Also, did you notice how I reduced the word
'can' to 'kn'. We do this when it is a helping
verb in a sentence. That is, not the main
verb. Can I have some? Listen again.
&gt;&gt; Can I have some? [3x]
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; Oh wow. It's soft. That is good.
&gt;&gt; Now hold up your apple.
&gt;&gt; This is my honey crisp apple.
The word 'apple' is a great word to pick out
and study for pronunciation, because many
people have difficulty with the Dark L sound.
It's quite common to hear non-native speakers
substitute the OH diphthong for the dark L.
So we end up getting a sound like 'app-oh'
instead of 'apple'. App-oh, apple. So what's
the difference? When we substitute the OH
diphthong, you can see that the lips will
round. App-oh. This means that the sound is
being formed here at the front of the mouth.
But for the dark L, apple, ul, ul, the sound
vibrates here in the back of the mouth, and
even the throat. Ul, ul, oh, oh, ul, ul. So,
how do you make the dark L? Ul, ul. To make
this, the tongue shifts back a little bit
in the back, so the tension is in the back
of the mouth, back of the tongue. Ul, that's
what brings the vibration here. Ul, ul, apple,
ul, ul, rather than app-oh, oh, oh. Apple,
apple. There are lots of words that end with
this dark L in an unstressed syllable, like
'bottle', 'incredible'. So, it's really worth
getting the sound right. Ul, ul.
Grape. The 'ay' diphthong is another sound
that my students sometimes have problems with.
Ay, ay. We have to hear two distinctly different
vowel sounds, so for the first sound, the
jaw has to drop quite a bit, and that's the
part that my students generally miss. Ay,
ay. For the second half of the diphthong,
the tongue tip still stays down here, behind
the bottom front teeth, but the front part
of the tongue stretches up towards the roof
of the mouth. That's what brings the jaw up.
Ay, ay, grape.
So, if you ever find yourself in the New York
area, I do recommend hitting up the farmer's
market in Union Square.
That's it, and thanks so much
for using Rachel's English.