In this American English pronunciation video,
you're going to meet my parents.
Now, I've been spending a lot of time teaching
you English, and I thought it would be fun
to show you who taught me English. These are
my parents Rita and Stan.
Rita. Notice we have a flap T there, because
the T is coming between two vowel sounds.
-ta, -ta, Rita. Stan. Now here we have the
AA as in BAT vowel followed by the N consonant.
When this vowel is followed by the N or the
M consonant, we get an extra sound. Aa-uu,
uu, an uh-like sound before the nasal consonant.
Stan, Stan, Stan.
These are my parents Rita and Stan.
&gt;&gt; Hello.
&gt;&gt; So guys, do you remember what my first
word was?
&gt;&gt; I remember your brother's first word.
&gt;&gt; Ok. So, I'm the youngest of two. Clearly
I'm not a memorable child because the first
one is the more interesting one.
&gt;&gt; His first word was 'hi'.
&gt;&gt; Hi.
&gt;&gt; And, I don't remember Rachel's first word,
but once she started speaking, she never stopped.
&gt;&gt; That's true.
&gt;&gt; So you don't remember my first word either?
&gt;&gt; It was probably 'mama'.
&gt;&gt; But you don't actually know.
&gt;&gt; I don't actually know.
&gt;&gt; Ok.
The pronunciation of this word is four syllables,
and with the CH consonant sound. Actually.
But I notice both my Mom and I here pronounced
it actually. We're reducing the word by substituting
the CH with a SH sound, that has no stop; we're
making it a little bit smoother. And we're
dropping the schwa syllable altogether. Actually.
Actually.
&gt;&gt; But you don't actually know.
&gt;&gt; I don't actually know.  &gt;&gt; Ok.
&gt;&gt; They're trying to think of something cute
that I might have said to tell you guys. But
my Mom said:
&gt;&gt; I can think of something cute your brother
said.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. See? It's terrible.
&gt;&gt; Well, I remember doing lots of things with
you.
&gt;&gt; Right. No, it's fine.
&gt;&gt; I remember riding you to school on the
handlebars of my bike.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. That hurt. I always wished that he
would buy an actual seat to put on the bike.
&gt;&gt; One thing I remember is sending off a card
three days before she left for summer camp
so she would receive a card on the first day
of summer camp.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. That was nice. I used to go away
for two weeks, and Mom was very good about
sending cards and also treats.
&gt;&gt; Well, thanks Mom and Dad so much for being
willing to meet my Rachel's English audience.
One last thing I want to say about them is
tomorrow is their 45th wedding anniversary.
So, happy anniversary, guys!
&gt;&gt; Thank you!
&gt;&gt; Are you ok?
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; This is my favorite uncle John. This is
my dad's older brother. Isn't he cute? John,
this is Rachel's English.
&gt;&gt; Hi Rachel's English. How are you? Rachel
comes from a very talkative family.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. We, we all talk a lot.
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; It makes sense that I'm doing what I'm
doing.
&gt;&gt; Right. I'm the quietest one I think.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, probably. And he's not that quiet.