In this American English pronunciation video,
we'll look at English in action and take a
look at the 'aa' vowel followed by nasal consonants.
&gt;&gt; Hey Jovon, happy Easter.
&gt;&gt; Oh, hey, happy Easter.
&gt;&gt; Hi Ben.
&gt;&gt; Hello Rachel.
&gt;&gt; Happy Easter.
&gt;&gt; Ben brought a ham for us to eat.
&gt;&gt; I brought a ham.
&gt;&gt; Ben brings a ham every year because he's
a dear. And I don't mean deer the animal,
I mean dear, D-E-A-R, a kind and thoughtful
person. 'Dear' and 'deer' are homophones.
&gt;&gt; What is this, Ben?
&gt;&gt; This is a ham. And it is made with pineapple
and brown sugar.
&gt;&gt; Oh, delicious. Ham. This is a teachable moment.
&gt;&gt; Here comes the ham. Now the word ham --
&gt;&gt; (it's really hot)
&gt;&gt; -- is an interesting word because it's
the AA as in BAT vowel followed by a nasal
consonant, in this case, M. So even though
it's written in IPA just with the H consonant,
AA vowel, and M consonant, it's not actually
pronounced that way. That would be "haam",
"haam". But we say, ha-uh-m. And there's that
UH sound that's not accounted for in IPA:
aa-uh, aa-uh. Ham. So, if you add this UH
sound to your AA vowel, you'll sound much
more American. Other examples, camera. AA-UH-M.
Cam-, Camera. This is also true if the sound
after the AA is the N sound. For example,
'ant'. AA-UHnt. Ant. Now, one last thing.
If the AA vowel is followed by the NG consonant,
then it changes also, but, in a different
way. In that case it becomes a sound more
like the 'ay' diphthong, ay. For example,
in the word 'thanks': thanks. Or, bank, bank.
So pronounce your AA vowel this way when it's
followed by N, M, or NG.
&gt;&gt; Michelle, what are you working on here?
&gt;&gt; I'm making Eggs Benedict.
&gt;&gt; Ooo.
&gt;&gt; So I'm poaching eggs --
&gt;&gt; Uh-huh.
&gt;&gt; And then making them with salmon and spinach.
&gt;&gt; Oh, that looks delicious.
&gt;&gt; Jovon's always taking pictures. It's a
good thing I'm used to the camera, right?
So this is what I made for our meal. Some
green---it probably doesn't look as good under
plastic, eh? Some asparagus. I roasted it
yesterday, gonna serve it chilled with a dijon
vinaigrette. Yum.
&gt;&gt; What did you make, Kate?
&gt;&gt; I made Easter egg chocolate / peanut butter
candy.
&gt;&gt; Oo, that looks good. Now these are special,
right?
&gt;&gt; They're special: they're vegan.
&gt;&gt; They're vegan.
&gt;&gt; No dairy.
&gt;&gt; Wow. Let me zoom up on that. Jovon's been
trying to sneak one of those ever since you
made them yesterday.
&gt;&gt; I found the little ladle. That's a hard
little phrase. Say that five times quickly!
Little ladle [x5].
&gt;&gt; Ben, this ham is delicious.
&gt;&gt; Thanks.
&gt;&gt; You guys are so clear, such good actors
for my Rachel's English audience. Totally
natural.
&gt;&gt; They're hamming it up.
&gt;&gt; They are hamming it up. Thank you, Matthew,
for brining up another use of the word 'ham'.
Matthew cleverly pointed out a second definition
for the word 'ham'. An actor or performer
who overacts. As a verb: to act with exaggerated
expression of emotion, to overact. So the
idiom, to ham it up, simply means, to overact.
Example sentence: He really hammed it up for
the camera.
&gt;&gt; Happy Easter, guys.
&gt;&gt; Happy Easter, Rachel.
&gt;&gt; Hope you're learning lots of fun vocabulary.
&gt;&gt; They are.
&gt;&gt; We learned all about the word 'ham'.
&gt;&gt; Ham.
&gt;&gt; Oo, ham.
&gt;&gt; That's a good one.
&gt;&gt; It is a good one and --
&gt;&gt; It's a nasal one.
&gt;&gt; -- it's sort of an odd word because it's
got this AA-UH sound.
&gt;&gt; haa, haaa. Like that.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. If you had to explain how you pronounce
'ham', what would you say?
&gt;&gt; Um, haa, aa. There's an H in there.
&gt;&gt; Yes?
&gt;&gt; There's an A, with an aa, kind of an aa?
&gt;&gt; Very nasal aa sound.
&gt;&gt; M, and then an M, mm, mm.
&gt;&gt; So if you had to say it in slow motion,
say it in slow motion.
&gt;&gt; Haaauhm.
&gt;&gt; There you go! I heard that good UH sound.
HaQuyen?
&gt;&gt; Ham.
Let's watch this in slow motion. As you know,
AA followed by M has an 'uh' sound. AA-uh,
AA-uh. You can see HaQuyen's tongue pull back
to make that UH sound before her lips close
for the M.
&gt;&gt; Ham.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, nice
&gt;&gt; Got that in the profile.
&gt;&gt; Yep, she gave the profile so we can see
the movement of the tongue and everything.
Thanks guys!
&gt;&gt; You're welcome Rachel.
&gt;&gt; You're most welcome.
That's it, and thanks so much
for using Rachel's English.
Don't stop there. Have fun with my real-life
English videos. Or get more comfortable with
the IPA in this play list. Learn about the
online courses I offer, or check out my latest
video.