Rita and Lee are talking to each other. So Rita says,
so how's everything been? Did you end up moving forward with the house purchase?
And Lee says, yes, we did. We signed the paperwork last week and the previous owners are moving out
end of the month. Assuming we can cram everything into the moving truck in one go,
we're aiming to have moved in by the end of next month.
Rita says,
they're so exciting. We would have taken up that opportunity too. The price was almost too good
to be true. Are you still planning to put up a treehouse in the garden? And Lee says,
oh for sure, we've got all sorts of things planned out already. The garden needs some tidying up,
but we'll be okay. Rita says, nice. If you could build onto the side of the garage, you could fit
both cars inside too. And Lee says, yep, that's on the wish list as well. We're also thinking of
doing up one side of the garage as a playroom for the kids, but we'll see. Anyway, I've got a run.
It was nice bumping into you. Chapsun.