We have to shell out a lot of money for the new equipment, we have to shell out a lot
of money for the new equipment.
Let's go for number two there now.
We are working towards our sales target for the quarter.
Number three, let's zoom in on the details of this proposal to make sure we have all
our bases covered.
Then number four, the company is looking to do away with its outdated software system.
The company is looking to do away with its outdated software system.
They're looking to means thinking about or planning to.
Number five, without proper training, the team is falling behind on the project.
Without proper training, the team is falling behind on the project.
Let's go six.
The company is cutting back on expenses to reduce costs.
Number seven, staying on top of industry trends is crucial for staying competitive.
Staying on top of industry trends is crucial for staying competitive.
Number eight, we're counting on the new product launch to boost our revenue.
We're counting on the new product launch to boost our revenue.
Number nine, if the business can't turn things around, it may end up going on.
If the business can't turn things around, it may end up going under.
And ten, the management team needs to deal with the issue of employee morale.
The management team needs to deal with the issue of employee morale.