So it's Nikolai talking to Klaus.
So Nikolai says, I'm glad we could meet today
to discuss the potential cooperation.
Let's run through the contract details.
Klaus says likewise, that means he's also happy to meet.
We'll need to go over a few details
to make sure this is a viable partnership from our end.
We're not willing to risk our finances on a deal
that isn't well thought out, okay?
Nikolai says, of course, we've put together a proposal
that we think is fair and realistic.
We're willing to put up some initial seed capital
to help get the projects off the ground,
but we'll need your company to take over
the implementation side, okay?
Klaus says, looking at these figures,
I will have to confirm with the executive,
but because I'm not authorized to sign off on this.