Hey, Jude, do you have a moment to talk about setting up a meeting?
Jude says, sure, what's up?
Dominic says, we need to brainstorm the way forward regarding our latest client.
Could sometime this week work for you?
Jude says, let me pull up my calendar quickly.
Damn, I'm all blocked up this week, but I can set aside sometime next week.
How long do you reckon we'd need?
Dominic says, given the lack of resources assigned to the project, at least two hours.
And then Jude says, cool, I'm sure I can squeeze in a two hour gap next week Wednesday.
Do you think this a chance will run over?
And Dominic says, great, let me pencil in the Wednesday slot.
I think we should be able to get through everything.
If anything changes last minute, I'll give you a heads up ASAP.
See you next week.