So, what's the new business idea you've come up with?
We want to create an online platform where people can compare different local gyms.
That sounds like a great idea.
We should start drawing up a plan and mapping up the details.
Yes, but before we do that, we need to go over the competition and make sure we're not
duplicating what's already up there.
That's a good point.
We don't want to run into any legal issues down the road.
Right, we need to do our due diligence and see if there are any potential roadblocks
we need to get around before moving forward.
Absolutely.
And once we have a solid plan, we can act on it and start building our platform.
But we need to be open to feedback and make adjustments as necessary to make sure that
our business is successful.
Agreed.
It's important to be flexible and adapt to any changes in the market.