Oil and gas companies have been raking in obscene profits by capitalising on the current
supply issues. Oil and gas companies have been raking in obscene profits by capitalising
on the current supply issues. Okay? Your turn.
Alright? Number two. After years of hard work, he finally cashed in on his investment
and retired comfortably. After years of hard work, he finally cashed in on his investment
and retired comfortably. Number three. My father refuses to cash in his insurance policy.
My father refuses to cash in his insurance policy. Number four. Investors often hedge
against market volatility by diversifying their portfolios. Investors often hedge against
market volatility by diversifying their portfolios. Number five. I'm trying to save up for a trip
to Europe next summer. I'm trying to save up for a trip to Europe next summer.
Number six. His determination and perseverance paid off when he landed his dream job.
His determination and perseverance paid off when he landed his dream job.
Number seven. I'm going to look into different online courses to further my education.
I'm going to look into different online courses from last minute English to further my education.
I'll give it to you one more time without doing advertising for my own company.
Come on. Pay attention. I'm going to look into different online courses to further my education
with last minute English. Okay. Number eight. After serving as CEO for a decade,
she decided to step down and enjoy retirement. After serving as CEO for a decade, she decided
to step down and enjoy retirement. Number nine. Starting out in a new career can be challenging
but also rewarding. Starting out in a new career can be challenging but also rewarding.
And number ten. She figured out a new strategy to increase productivity and efficiency in her team.
She figured out a new strategy to increase productivity and efficiency in her team.